Throw down the rope!
(CAMERAS SNAPPING)
It's port side.
_
(AIR WHOOSHES)
(MUSIC)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BELL DINGS)
Lassen Sie die Landelinien.
(AIR HISSING)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
You supposed to be this close?
Probably not.
You believe something
this big actually flies?
Men.
Always obsessed with
how big something is.
(MUSIC)
(FILM ROLLING)
It's practically standing still now.
Uh, they've dropped ropes out
of the nose of the ship.
Over to the starboard side.
(MEN GRUNTING)
(MACHINERY RUMBLING)
(ELECTRIC SPARKS)
(ELECTRICITY SPARKING)
Aah!
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(MUSIC)
It burst into flames.
It burst into flames!
And it's falling, It's crashing!
(RUMBLING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
(PANTING)
(MUSIC)
Mama!
(EXPLOSION)
(MAN SCREAMING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
And... oh... and the
frame is crashing to the ground,
not quite to the the mooring mast, but...
Oh, the humanity.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Aah!
- (SHIP RUMBLES)
- (GASPS)
(MUSIC)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
_
A White House reported asked LBJ,
"why are we in Vietnam?"
And the president
whipped out his genitalia...
(LAUGHTER)
And said, "This is why."
(CROWD CHUCKLING)
It's true. He called it "Jumbo".
(LAUGHTER)
For better or worse,
and in this case, worse,
this is real history.
To understand it,
we've got to get
inside these people's heads,
their loves, their quirks,
their...
Jumbos.
(LAUGHTER)
(GIGGLES)
You're cancelling my tenure meeting?
It's not me.
You're department chair.
It's the committee.
Can we just... let's
talk about this over coffee.
I have busted my ass for tenure.
Why?
The department thinks that...
My mother built this department.
The real truth?
You could push this
through if you wanted.
Lucy.
(DOG BARKING)
Amy?
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
Hey.
Hi.
Hey, Mom.
(KISSES)
How's she doing?
Same as yesterday.
And the day before.
Mm.
Come on.
Let me buy you a drink.
They're not gonna give you tenure?
So what are you gonna do?
Go to the chancellor,
if I have to, raise hell.
Or quit. Just get out of there.
You don't need this crap.
So we'll all just live off your podcast?
Ouch.
Lucy, you're a great professor.
Go somewhere you're wanted.
That department is Mom's legacy.
It's what I've worked
for my entire life.
So what, I should just
throw my whole future away?
I'm just saying.
Stop worrying about disappointing Mom.
Make your own future.
(CAGE THE ELEPHANT'S
"MESS AROUND" PLAYS)
♪ Ah ♪
(SONG CONTINUES OVER HEADPHONES)
♪ No, she don't mess around ♪
Hey.
♪ She don't mess around ♪
♪ Oh St. Louie, California ♪
What's good, Jiya?
♪ Blue eyes yeah she's comin... ♪
(TENSE MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(BEEPS)
(GATE SLIDES)
(MUSIC)
You sure you can trust that book?
Hold up!
I need to see some ID.
(MUSIC)
Rufus.
Hey, Anthony.
Is it or is it not
Taco Tuesday,
and your turn to pick up said tacos?
Um, ask Jiya to go with you.
Better than staring
at her 12 hours a day.
(OVER HEADPHONES)
♪ What she's made of ♪
♪ She's coming for ya
She's gonna try to break ya ♪
♪ Yeah, she don't... ♪
(GUNSHOT)
(BROODING MUSIC)
- What wa...
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (COMMOTION)
- (GASPS)
Everybody, get
down on the ground, now!
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOTS)
- Come on!
- Move yourself or you're dead!
Sit down on the ground.
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (WOMEN YELPING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
Go! Go!
- Shut up!
- (GUN COCKS)
Go up to the top! Go!
You, move!
(SIRENS WAILING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(HATCH LOCKING)
(CAPSULE CLANKING)
(CAPSULE WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING INTENSIFIES)
(SONIC POP)
Police!
Hands up! Let me see your hands!
Where'd they go?
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: September 4, 2016
(SOMBER MUSIC)
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
(MUSIC)
(DOOR BELL RINGS)
Lucy Preston?
I'm Agent Kondo
with Homeland Security.
(SIGHS) Look,
whatever you're selling,
- I'm not buying...
- Really.
Agent Kondo, Homeland Security.
Miss Preston, you need to come with me.
What'd she do?
We need your help.
Now, please.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Get out, please.
(MUSIC)
This way, follow me.
- Wait here, please.
- Okay.
You know what? I just need to call...
Cool.
(WHISPERS) Are you asleep?
- No, ma'am.
- Oh.
(FAINTLY) Okay, good.
This is Connor Mason's company?
Do you know why we're here?
No idea, ma'am.
You know, we're
pretty much the same age,
so you can just stop calling me ma'am.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Lucy Preston?
Agent Denise Christopher,
homeland Security.
You've got a hell of a reputation.
History, anthropology.
You're world - Class.
I'm just a teacher. My
mother is world - Class.
I've read all of her books.
I'm sorry to hear she's sick.
And Master Sergeant Wyatt Logan.
Delta Force?
Yes, ma'am.
Boy. Speaking of reputations.
Well, we are on the clock so follow me,
but hold onto your asses.
Uhh. Uh... ok... okay.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
Garcia Flynn, ex - NSA
asset in Eastern Europe.
Ex since when?
Since he killed his wife
and child and went off the grid.
That was a year ago. We
thought he was holed up
in Chechnya, but apparently not.
Why's he taking the Star Tours ride?
(SONIC POP)
Wh...
What the hell was that?
Some sort of special effect?
Ever heard of a closed timelike curve?
You're Connor Mason.
My buddy has one of your cars.
I... excuse me, a closed timelike what?
Right. Say, this,
is the fabric of space - Time.
Now, If you get a powerful enough
gravitational field, you
could actually bend it back
on itself, creating a kind
of loop that would allow you
to cross over to an earlier point.
An... an earlier point
in time, you mean?
What he means is, Mr. Mason
invented a time machine.
And chose not to tell
the government about it
until it was stolen by terrorists.
Right, 'cause the federal government
never screws up anything and
can always keep a secret.
You're asking for our help now.
Uh... wait, hold on.
This is a joke, right?
I mean, some... some psych
test the government came up with?
I mean this... this
can't be possible, right?
Well, that's what they
said about the moon shot,
until someone with enough imagination
made it very possible.
(METAL CLANKS)
(ALARMS BLARING)
Our earliest prototype.
She isn't fancy, but she works, usually.
Now, we kept her operational in case
the crew of the mother
ship ever needed a rescue.
We call this one the "Lifeboat."
Their CPUs are linked.
But unfortunately she can't
tell us exactly where
the mother ship has gone.
But she can tell us when.
Naturally.
Only tells you when.
Time machine problems.
Yes, we're working on it,
but for the moment that's
the best we have.
3:30 p. M. May 6, 1937.
We found this on the dead shooter.
It's an address, a tavern
in Manchester, New Jersey.
That's the "Hindenburg."
About four hours before it crashed.
You're telling me that this
guy actually went back in time,
for real, to the "Hindenburg"?
Lucy,
if Flynn kills people in '37
who aren't supposed to die,
they don't have the kids
they're supposed to have,
do the things they're supposed to do,
history changes.
Reality changes.
So why would you be stupid enough
to invent something so dangerous?
I didn't count on this happening.
Why would Flynn do it?
We don't know.
But there's room in
there for three passengers.
Wait... to... to do what?
Go after him?
Why else would we bring you here?
You're insane!
I mean,
even if I believed you, which I don't,
i am not getting in
that thing to... what?
Go after some terrorist?
I am not a soldier.
We have a soldier. We need a historian.
A good one who knows the customs,
can travel incognito,
help us keep a low profile.
Great, I'll email you some names.
I think someone who loved history
would want to save it.
Besides,
what if I am telling the truth?
Don't tell me you're
not the least bit curious.
(TENSE MUSIC)
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
You need to go with them.
I can't.
I am a coder.
Okay, that is what I'm good at.
All right, I don't
like to leave my desk,
let alone go in there or back then.
Also, I don't know how it
works across the pond,
but I am black.
There is literally no
place in American history
that'll be awesome for me.
Rufus, enough.
We both know why it has to be you.
(MUSIC)
"Lifeboat" systems coming online.
Ground crew...
This is all wrong.
This skirt is from the
'40s. And this blouse?
They didn't have this kind
of fabric back then.
Or underwire bras.
Who is gonna see your bra?
Best we could do on short notice.
- Take this please.
- I have to call my sister.
You can do it when you get back.
- What?
- He's the address
- For the tavern.
- And some money.
- Huh?
- Let's go.
Verify control systems.
(COMPUTERS BEEPING)
Don't be noticed.
Don't change anything.
Understand?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
(GROANS)
It's okay, just start.
(MUSIC)
(SIGHS)
Lucy.
Rufus.
I'm a pilot. Kind of.
Kind of?
Wyatt.
Time displacement circuits activated.
(VARIOUS BEEPS)
(MUSIC)
Are all these seat
belts really necessary?
Oh, yeah.
You'll see.
You okay?
I'm... i'm claustrophobic.
And apparently about to
travel through time, so...
(EXHALES)
Have you been drinking?
Didn't know I was gonna
be working tonight, ma'am.
Stop calling me ma'am.
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENTS)
Might want to hold on.
(SHIP POWERING UP)
(METAL CLANKING)
(ALARMS BLARING)
(MUSIC)
Gravitational flux...
(METAL WARBLING)
(RUMBLING)
(MUSIC)
(CAPSULE WHIRRING)
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(WHIRRING INTENSIFIES)
(SONIC POP)
Launch sequence completed.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
(WIND BLOWING)
(SONIC POP)
(RUMBLING)
(METAL WHIRRING, CLANKING)
(MECHINERY WHIRRING)
(AIR LOCK HISSES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Are you okay?
Totally good.
(AMBIENT MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Oh.
(GRUNTS)
Oh. (SPITS)
Are we here?
Think so.
You sure?
Pretty sure.
(AIRCRAFT HOVERING)
(STIRRING MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Okay, just one thing that I don't get.
Apparently, this time machine works.
So why don't we just go
back five minutes before
Flynn stormed in and
then shoot him in the face?
You can't go back to any
time where you already exist,
where you might meet
a double of yourself.
It is bad for the fabric of reality.
Define "bad."
We tried it once. The pilot came back,
but not all of him.
What?
Oh!
(EXHALES)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
So the back of the bus was amazing.
Wow.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Mom, I wish you could see this.
Come on, Professor, we gotta move.
- Tell us what we're getting into.
- Okay.
(STIRRING MUSIC)
The "Hindenburg" is
just reaching the airfield,
but she won't be
able to land right away.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Because of that.
Light rain and high winds.
So she'll make a bunch of turns,
causing the air friction, building
up static electricity.
Then, at exactly 7:25 p. M.,
the "Hindenburg" will throw
down the mooring ropes,
but the ground crew will drag the ropes
through the grass... they get soaked.
Which electrically grounds the ship,
causing a spark in the metal hull.
The spark ignites a
leaking hydrogen balloon,
burning 2,000 cubic
liters and 36 people alive.
So why is Flynn here?
Here you go.
- Thank you, miss.
- Thank you.
Maybe he wants to
kill all 97 people on board
instead of just the 36?
Make a bad thing worse?
Whatever it is, we find
him first, fast as we can.
And if we do find him?
Leave that to me.
(OMINOUS TONE)
(BILLIE HOLIDAY'S "EENY
MEENY MINEY MO" PLAYS)
♪ If it hollers let it go ♪
♪ Let it fly away ♪
It might be the '30s,
but Jersey's Jersey.
You see Flynn?
Ah...
(MUSIC)
Um, everyone's staring at you.
Maybe you should just wait outside?
On a scale from Million Man
March to Mississippi Burning,
how safe do you think
I'm gonna be out there?
You should be fine, just, uh...
don't make eye contact with anyone.
So glad I came.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
Hey, man. How's it going?
How's what going where?
How do you do, sir?
Um, we were just wondering
if you've seen this man?
Why's he wearing pajamas?
Just have you seen him?
No, I don't think so.
Look again. It's important.
Hey, what are you, deaf?
I said I haven't seen him.
Yep.
Jersey's Jersey.
(MOTORIZED TRAFFIC)
(MUSIC)
That's Kate Drummond.
Oh, right, of course she'd be here.
Who's she?
She has a column in the Hearst papers.
She covered the wars in
Manchuria and Ethiopia.
(GLASSES CLINKS)
(MUSIC)
(LAUGHS)
What?
Just reminds me of someone, that's all.
(WHISPERS) Wyatt!
(COIN CLANKS)
(BALL RATTLES)
That's a pinball machine?
Nothing gets past you, pal.
Double or nothing?
Would you like a drink, Miss Drummond?
You know who I am?
Oh, yeah.
The way you covered the
wars in Manchuria and Ethiopia
really makes a guy think.
Oh, you're a soldier.
How'd you know?
The pick - Up line, for one.
I've known too many soldiers.
Not like me, you haven't.
Miss Drummond.
Um, It is so nice to meet you.
You are a hell of a writer.
This is my older sister, Lucy.
That's kind of you, Lucy.
You're in town to cover
the "Hindenburg's" arrival?
Yes, and then I'm riding
it back to Europe
for the coronation
'cause there's nothing like
a tight, enclosed space with
a bunch of stuffed shirts.
Well, maybe you won't have
to take that trip after all.
(MUSIC)
(PINBALL MACHINE DINGS)
Have you seen this man?
Who is he? And why's
he wearing pajamas?
He's a friend of ours.
Mm.
Well, yes, he was here.
About two hours ago.
What was he doing?
Well, when the officers
at the airfield need
a couple of extra hands, this
is where they pick 'em up.
Your friend is working as ground crew.
He's gonna help bring
down the "Hindenburg."
(BROODING MUSIC)
We owe Kate
another drink for that one.
She is amazing.
- Who we talking about?
- Kate Drummond.
She only has about 90 minutes to live.
She'll be right under the "Hindenburg"
when it crashes down on top of her.
Wait.
You just stood there, chatting her up,
knowing she's about to die?
Well, we can't change anything.
Today's the day she...
Today's her day.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Excuse me. Excuse me.
(CAMERA SNAPS)
Guys, follow me. Follow me.
Commander Rosendahl?
Oh... um, I'm sorry to bother you,
but it... it's urgent.
Yes?
Um...
This man is working as
one of your ground crew,
and it's very
important we find him quickly.
He's a threat to your base, sir.
How? Who are you?
Well, uh, we're actually...
This is Doctor Dre. I'm Nurse Jackie.
We're from General Hospital.
This man is a patient
of ours, which is, uh,
- Why he's...
- Both: Wearing pajamas.
He has a bad case of Spanish Flu,
which last time killed,
what, almost 700,000 people
in the US alone, so,
you can see why we're nervous.
Yes, yes, of course.
I'll help however I can.
Oh.
Officers!
- Step forward!
- Sir?
Yes, sir.
This man is somewhere
amongst this crowd.
(ENGINE HOVERING)
He's only got five more minutes.
Yeah, let's split up.
And if you see Flynn, don't engage.
You find me first.
(MUSIC)
Starboard side!
- (BELL DINGS)
- Lassen Sie die Landelinien.
(MUSIC)
(AIR HISSING)
(FILM REEL ROLLING)
It's practically standing still now.
Uh, they've dropped ropes out
of the nose of the ship.
(MUSIC)
(CAMERA SNAPS)
(WATCH TICKING)
(MUSIC)
Wyatt!
You believe something
this big actually flies?
Men.
Always obsessed with
how big something is.
- Hi, there. Remember me?
- Yes, hello.
Yeah, couple things I
want to talk to you about.
Maybe we can go someplace private.
In... in a minute, I'm working.
Well, we don't have a minute, really.
Well, maybe you haven't noticed, soldier,
but the ship is
landing, It'll have to wait.
- It can't wait.
- No!
Hey! You stay away from me!
We're out of time!
- Stop! Get off me!
- Run! Run!
It's gonna blow!
Stay away!
Get off of me!
Oh! You stay away from me!
(FILM REEL ROLLING)
(MUSIC)
The majestic airship lands gracefully
as passengers wave to
the awed spectators.
(SHIP HOVERING)
Um...
That's not supposed to happen, right?
Where's Lucy?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUFFLED SHOUTS)
Are you following us?
Flynn wants to talk to you.
- (BLOW LANDS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (STRUGGLING)
- (PUNCHES LAND)
(GRUNTS)
(GUN COCKS)
(BOTH PANTING)
Take me to Flynn.
- (SILENCER SHOOTS)
- (GRUNTING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
- (SPEAKING GERMAN)
- (LAUGHS)
(MUSIC)
You okay?
Flynn just saved the "Hindenburg."
So no, I am definitely not okay.
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
So saving the "Hindenburg," huh?
How'd Flynn even do it?
The mooring ropes.
I saw crewmen, they didn't
let the ropes touch the wet grass.
They wrapped them up.
No wet ropes means the
ship doesn't ground.
There's no spark in the hull, no boom.
Those must've been Flynn's guys.
I'm less concerned with
how Flynn did it then why.
It's a bad thing 36 people lived?
Very bad.
It could change the present
in ways we can't possibly predict.
Huh.
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
Finally.
Some civilization in
this backwater crap - Hole.
I can rewire it to track
the other walkie's signal,
use it to find Flynn.
Give me a minute.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING FAINTLY)
You shouldn't have brought that gun.
- Oh, the one
- I saved your ass with?
We are surrounded by Nazis.
What if one of them
takes your future gun
- To Berlin?
- Sometimes things get messy.
It is my job to make
sure there is no mess.
There's always a mess.
That's the deal.
So now we make it up as we go.
And I take out Flynn.
Which, by the way, might
require the use of a damn gun.
So if that's your job, why
did you run off after Kate?
(TENSE MUSIC)
Hey, guys?
Turns out I can't track Flynn
because this isn't actually a walkie.
- At least, not anymore.
- What do you mean?
Someone soldered the lead wires.
And then there's this thing.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's a blasting cap.
This is a detonator.
For a... a bomb?
Wait.
Kate's column. Listen.
"The 'Hindenburg' will welcome
many luminaries aboard
"its return trip to Europe
and the king's coronation.
John D. Rockefeller Jr., Omar
Bradley, Igor Sikorsky..."
I don't follow.
Rockefeller's gonna help
build the United Nations.
Bradley's crucial to planning D - Day.
S... sikorsky invented
the damn helicopter.
I mean, what if that's why Flynn
saved the "Hindenburg"?
What if he didn't want
to blow it up on the way in
because he wants to blow
it up on the way out?
If these people died, the...
the damage to the timeline
it's... it's catastrophic...
Hands up!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Stay right where you are!
(MUSIC)
Let me guess, someone called
in an anonymous tip?
Shut up.
(MUSIC)
(GRUNTS)
When do they invent deodorant?
Please, just call the airfield
and tell them that the
"Hindenburg" is in danger!
Please!
Piece - Of - Crap, old lock.
Can you open it?
Oh, yeah. Easy with a hairpin,
which I'm guessing you don't have.
No, I don't.
(SIGHS)
(CELL RATTLES)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(BROODING MUSIC)
How soon till the "Hindenburg" leaves?
Just before dawn, so pretty soon.
Great, we just rot in
here while all those people die.
- While...
- Kate dies?
Okay.
So, what is it about her?
Hmm?
Nothing.
Okay, so you're just one
of those soldiers who
ignores his orders to
chase a pretty face?
Kate reminds me of my wife.
Okay?
They even look alike.
Little bit.
I didn't know you were married.
Jessica died.
(SOLEMN MUSIC)
It was my fault.
If I could just change that one...
(MUSIC)
So when I saw Kate, I
just couldn't let her...
(MUSIC)
(SCOFFS)
(LIVELY PIANO MUSIC PLAYS)
KIDS: ♪ Who's afraid of
the big, bad wolf? ♪
♪ The big, bad wolf the big, bad wolf ♪
♪ Who's afraid of the big, bad wolf? ♪
♪ Tra - La - La - La - La ♪
♪ Who's afraid of the big, bad wolf... ♪
Excuse me.
(OMINOUS TONE)
What the hell kind of a gun is this?
(SCOFFS)
I know how to get out.
How?
(HISSES)
Make a distraction.
Uh... ahem. Excuse me,
can I get a glass of water, please, sir?
Swallow your spit, boy.
I'm not a boy, actually.
Excuse me?
You have eyes, right?
You can tell I'm not a child,
and I am definitely not your son,
so don't call me "boy."
I'm not sure you realize where you are,
boy.
Actually, I do.
I'm in the damn Stone Age, but, man,
i hope you live a long, long life.
Long enough to see Michael Jordan dunk,
michael Jackson dance,
mike Tyson punch,
really, just, any black
guy named Michael.
OJ? Yeah, he gets off.
He did it, but we don't care.
And Obama, he's the president.
2008. That's gonna suck for you!
I hope you see it all.
Because the future is not on your side,
boy.
Okay, so where's he going?
- Take off your bra.
- What?
Your modern bra.
With underwire, yeah.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Here.
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
Uh... gu... guys?
- Uh, Wyatt?
- Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Guy... guys... guys... wyatt?
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, guys, please
stop. Don't come in here.
Look, no, no - No - No!
Hold on, stop, stop.
No, no! Stop!
- (BLOWS LAND)
- (GRUNTS)
(BLOWS LANDING)
- (BLOW LANDS)
- (GRUNTS)
- Oh!
(GRUNTS)
Oh, my God.
Not bad, Rufus.
- Eh.
- Come on, come on.
That was amazing.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
- How we gonna find the bomb?
- Working on it.
Oh!
- No, I need a steward!
- No!
I need a steward!
You stay away from me,
you attacked me!
No, no, I was trying to save you!
I'm trying to save you right now.
This ship is in danger. There is a bomb.
And we're trying to find it.
He's telling the truth.
The picture we showed you,
that guy planted the bomb.
Help us.
Please.
I saw him.
Follow me.
He came out of here in a hurry.
- Look over there.
- Okay.
Um...
(MUSIC)
Hey!
(TENSE MUSIC)
(BOMB BEEPING)
What the hell is that?
We got to get this off the ship now.
Uh... about that.
(MUSIC)
You've defused a bomb before, right?
I've seen it done.
Had some training in Afghanistan.
Since when were we
fighting Afghanistan?
Hey, I need you to ground the
ship and get the people off.
How do we do that?
We make it up as we go.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
Come on.
(GEAR TWISTS)
(MUSIC)
Stay back!
Stay back.
We're the Anarchist Black Cross.
We have a bomb on this ship.
You're going to land now
and await further demands.
(MUSIC)
Do it or I'll cut his throat, you Nazis!
(AIR SIREN WAILS)
Hurry up! Let's go!
(SIREN WAILING)
(MUSIC)
The ship is landing.
Something's wrong.
(BOMB BEEPING)
(MUSIC)
Ask me something.
Wha... like what?
Anything. It relaxes me to talk.
Anything, well...
Where the hell did this
glowing clock come from?
Or you, for that matter?
All right, look, I know
this is hard to believe,
but I'm gonna tell you the truth.
My name is Buck Rogers and
this thing came from outer space.
(SOFT LAUGH)
- (YELPS)
- (GASPS)
(BLOWS LANDING)
(GRUNTING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
- (PUNCH LANDS)
- (GRUNTS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(STRAINING)
(BLOWS LAND)
(GRUNTS)
(KNIFE DROPS)
(BOTH GRUNTS)
(BOMB BEEPING)
(GRUNTS)
(BLOWS LAND)
(ITEMS SMASH)
- (PUNCHES LAND)
- (GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(BOMB BEEPING)
(DISHES SMASHING)
(MUSIC)
(BLOWS LANDING)
Hey!
- (PAN CLANKS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
(MUSIC)
(GUN COCKS)
Don't shoot, you idiot!
(GUNSHOT)
- (BULLET RICOCHETTING)
- (FLAMES WHOOSH)
(EXPLOSION)
Go! Go! We gotta go!
(FLAMES WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Come on!
(ELECTRICITY SPARKING)
(FLAMES WHOOSHING)
(MUSIC)
Hey!
(EXPLOSION)
(AGONIZED SCREAMING)
Go, go!
- (GRUNTS)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
Come on, I got you! Let's go!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
I need some help
over here! Someone help!
(MUSIC)
(WOMAN WAILING)
Sir, do you need help? Here, here.
Go get that little girl!
Here you go.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(MUSIC)
It's time we talked.
You need to understand who
and what you're dealing with.
I understand that
you're a psychopath trying to
burn everything to the ground.
Well, that depends on
your point of view, Lucy.
How do you know my name?
I know everything about you.
Your father's dead.
You think you're meant to
follow in your mother's footsteps,
but you don't really want to.
You wanna know how I know?
(MUSIC)
That's my handwriting, but...
I didn't write that.
Not yet.
But you will.
(CRIES)
I know what you're really
meant to be, Lucy,
and it isn't a teacher.
Why would I believe anything
from someone who killed
their own family?
(MUSIC)
Just ask them why
they really chose you
for this mission.
And ask them what Rittenhouse is.
Rittenhouse?
(MUSIC)
Get someplace safe!
Where are you going?
Have a good life.
(EXPLOSION)
Wha...
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(YELPS)
I know for a fact that
you're not gonna shoot.
(MUSIC)
Wyatt.
(GUNSHOT)
(YELPS)
- (GUNSHOT)
- (GRUNTS)
(MUSIC)
- Kate?
- Oh, Kate.
Oh, my God.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
You got her?
I got her! Go!
Oh, my God.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(GRUNTING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
- (WHIMPERS)
- Come on, stay with me.
I'm right here.
Move, move, move.
- You're okay...
- Here, let me.
- (WHIMPERING)
- Come on.
Just relax, relax.
(COUGHS)
It's okay, It's okay.
Ple... plea...
- Come on.
- (COUGHS)
Kate, come... kate, come on!
(GASPING)
Come on.
(SOMBER MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
(SONIC POP)
(RUMBLING)
(ROUSING MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(PANTING)
The "Hindenburg" exploded early morning
May the 7th, 1937.
It was bombed by the
Anarchist Black Cross.
There were only two casualties.
Journalist Kate Drummond
and the man whose body
was unable to be identified.
Okay, so... so to you,
this is what's in the books?
- This is how it went down?
- Of course.
And the anarchist group?
Three suspects who escaped from jail
- And vanished without a trace?
- Yes?
That was us.
What?
We had some issues.
Flynn wanted a lot
more than two casualties.
He wanted to murder everyone onboard,
and we stopped him,
but the "Hindenburg,"
it wasn't supposed to happen like this.
Flynn still changed history
in... in ways I... (SIGHS)
In what ways I... i don't know yet.
Did you see him?
I spoke to him.
Really? What did he say?
He said I should ask
you why you chose me
and what Rittenhouse means.
I have no idea what
he's talking about.
I don't know.
Rufus, where's Flynn now?
Uh, the "Lifeboat's" CPU says that
he's back in present
day, but who knows where.
And so we can't go back to '37?
- Give it another shot?
- No.
Remember, we can't double - Back
to any place
where we meet ourselves.
There are no do - Overs.
So what is Flynn after?
I have a theory.
Any anti - Government wack - Job
can get a few barrels of fertilizer
and blow up a federal building.
It's not going to really
change anything.
Our institutions are too established,
but in the past, things
were a lot more fragile.
I...
I think Flynn is trying
to kill America in the crib.
Rewrite history before
it's even written.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
None of you are to say
a word about any of this,
under penalty of treason.
If we need you, we'll call you.
- Wait.
- Need us?
Nothing has changed.
Flynn is still out there. He
still has the mother ship.
And you are still our best option.
When he uses it again,
we will call you.
(MUSIC)
You have something for me?
I didn't get everything.
For some of it, they
were out of earshot.
Those must have been Flynn's guys.
I'm less concerned with
how Flynn did it than why.
(BEEPS)
I'm not at all comfortable with this.
By the way.
Do you think I'm comfortable
with any of this?
(DOOR CREAKS)
Hey.
When you shot Flynn,
couple inches to the right,
you would have blown my brains out.
You just that good or was
I just that expendable?
Well, I guess I'm just that good,
ma'am.
(SCOFFS)
Wyatt.
You asked Rufus about going
back to your own timeline
because you want to change
what happened to your wife, right?
But maybe the
"Hindenburg" was meant to explode,
kate was meant to die.
Maybe we don't get
to make it up as we go.
- Maybe some things are just...
- What?
Fate?
(PIANO PLAYS PINK FLOYD'S
"WISH YOU WERE HERE" )
(MUSIC)
Hey. Um...
How was it? What was it like?
Uh, you know, to time - Travel?
(LAUGHS)
I'll take you to dinner,
tell you all about it.
Oh, uh...
Okay.
(CHUCKLES)
♪ So you think ♪
♪ So you think you can tell ♪
♪ Heaven from Hell? ♪
♪ Blues skies from pain? ♪
♪ Can you tell a green field ♪
♪ From a cold steel rail? ♪
♪ A smile from a veil? ♪
♪ Do you think you can... ♪
Amy?
How's she doing?
Amy, I'm back!
(MUSIC)
(KNIFE CHOPPING)
Hi, sweetheart.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Mom?
What was all that about Amy?
Please say that you
brought me a Snickers.
Hm?
What's wrong?
You're okay?
Yes, of course I'm okay.
(CRIES)
(LAUGHS)
Hey.
- (SNIFFS)
- Hey, hey.
What's gotten into you?
I just... how is this possible?
How could... how
could... the "Hindenburg"...
How could the
"Hindenburg" have done this?
"Hindenburg"?
Lucy, you're not making any sense.
Sorry. I'm just so happy to see you.
Sweetheart.
What's happened to your engagement ring?
My what?
Sweetheart, what is wrong?
Sorry, It's, um...
just a lot to, uh...
Where's Amy?
Lucy, you keep saying that. Amy who?
(BROODING MUSIC)
No.
- No.
- Lucy?
Amy?
- Amy!
Tell me what is going on.
(MUSIC)
No.
This isn't right.
I don't...
Lucy, what are you talking about?
You're starting to scare me.
(PHONE RINGING)
(PHONE BEEPS)
- Hello?
- The car's turning around
to pick you up, we
need you back here now.
Flynn just took out the
mother ship again.
Where?
Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: September 4, 2016
When?