NARRATOR:
Previously on "Timeless"...
Garcia Flynn. He went
straight for Anthony.
He knew he was
the project leader.
What the hell was that?
Mr. Mason invented a time machine
and chose not to tell
the government about it
until it was stolen by terrorists.
We call this one the "Lifeboat."
But there's room in
there for three passengers.
To do what? Go after him?
Might want to hold on.
Just ask them why they really
chose you for this mission,
and ask them what Rittenhouse is.
Rittenhouse?
Flynn still changed history in ways
I don't know yet.
Mom? You're okay?
Yes, of course I'm okay.
What's happened
to your engagement ring?
My what?
My... engagement party.
Hello, beautiful.
Hello.
(MELLOW FOLK MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
You didn't come to bed last night.
Oh.
What you doing?
Just, uh... feeling nostalgic.
Ah. You remember that?
That was a perfect day, wasn't it?
Yeah.
The beach was amazing.
And it was the day we got engaged.
Yeah. That too.
Speaking of, guess what
I found in the bathroom?
Oh, no. What?
Yeah.
You okay?
Just, uh... my head
is somewhere else.
Well, I think I can help with that.
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh, God, It's, um... it's work.
Okay.
Hello?
What happened
on September 21st, 1962?
Uh, I don't... i don't know.
The Cuban missile crisis
happens a month later.
Well, figure it out on your way in.
Flynn took out the Mothership,
and we're hours behind him.
_
(MUSIC)
(PHONE RINGING)
Three hours since Flynn jumped,
and you still don't know where?
Well, we know when. When's easy.
Where in '62? Much harder.
- Could be anywhere.
- Almost cracked it, though.
- Crack harder.
- Rufus.
Can you come with me a moment?
Give me a minute. We're close.
It's about Anthony.
What about Anthony?
I've been doing a lot of
thinking about him lately.
And on the night Garcia
Flynn stole the Mothership,
did Anthony do anything...
Say anything to you...
That might have seemed,
i don't know, strange?
No. Why?
We've taken a peek at
Anthony's cell phone records.
30 minutes before
Flynn stormed the place,
anthony made a phone call
to an unknown number...
since disconnected.
Okay.
Flynn outsmarting our
security so easily...
Well, It makes a lot more sense
if he had inside assistance.
From Anthony?
You can't be serious.
We've just suffered
a devastating attack.
Now, we need
to consider all possibilities.
Well, consider some others.
Anthony is the victim here.
He was kidnapped.
He doesn't need us
questioning his loyalty.
He needs us to save him.
Yes, of course.
(MUSIC)
I got it.
Guys, I know where they are.
Um, uh, okay, so it turns out
that the negative - Mass kinetic energy
given off by the Mothership
actually leaves behind
a trace of...
They're in Nevada.
Somewhere in this 50 - Mile radius.
Uh, not exactly a pinpoint.
Can we do any better than 50 miles?
- Sorry, no.
- Well, It's either the desert
or Vegas, so... vegas.
But why would Flynn go there?
I'm looking. Okay, September 21st.
Vegas, 1962.
President Kennedy was in town
for a DNC fund raiser at the Sands hotel.
Sinatra headlining.
So what are we thinking?
Flynn's gonna "JFK"
JFK one year early?
Maybe.
That room was filled with celebrities,
politicians, Mafia...
Flynn could kill any of them,
and it would be a disaster.
Well, we need to get there first.
(UPBEAT MUSIC)
SINATRA: How did all these
people get in my room?
(APPLAUSE)
♪ Come fly with me ♪
♪ We'll fly, we'll fly away ♪
♪ If you can use some exotic booze ♪
♪ There's a bar in far Bombay ♪
♪ Come on, fly with me ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
please head to the pool.
The show is about to begin!
♪ Come fly with me ♪
ALL: Whoo!
♪ In llama land, there's
a one - Man band ♪
Ten. Nine.
Eight. Seven.
Six. Five.
Four. Three.
Two. One.
- (EXPLOSION)
- (APPLAUSE)
♪ You might hear all the angels cheer ♪
♪ 'Cause we're together ♪
♪ Weather - Wise, It's such a lovely day ♪
You should come see this, Jack.
I've seen it before.
Takes more than an atomic bomb
to impress the President of
the United States, does it?
Hmm. (CHUCKLES)
Sure does.
Takes you.
♪ Honeymoon, they say ♪
♪ Come on, fly with me,
we'll fly, we'll fly ♪
(MUSIC)
♪ Pack up, let's fly away ♪
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: October 18, 2016
(INTENSE MUSIC)
Initiate "Lifeboat"
departure procedure.
(MUSIC)
Something you want to tell us?
- Huh?
- Your rock.
Is that part of the costume?
Oh. No, apparently, I'm engaged.
Congratulations?
- To who?
- Exactly.
His name is Noah.
I've never met him before,
but there's all these pictures
of us on vacation that
I have no memory of.
I mean, ever since that we
got back from the Hindenburg,
my life has completely
changed overnight.
You gonna take his name
or are you gonna keep yours?
I don't even know his last name.
- Well, look on the bright side.
- There's a bright side?
You still got the
honeymoon to look forward to.
Plus you get to go to Vegas.
(MUSIC)
(INDISTINCT P. A. ANNOUNCEMENTS)
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
(RUMBLING INTENSIFIES)
(GRUNTING AND GROANING)
You couldn't land any
more out of the way?
You rather I park on the Strip?
(EXPLOSION)
- We're too late.
- That's not Flynn.
There's a nuclear test site
about 60 miles
on the other side of town.
Who's crazy enough to
test a nuclear bomb
outside of Vegas?
The U. S. Department of Energy.
During the '50s and '60s, they tested
over 1,000 nuclear weapons
in the Nevada desert.
Set 'em off a couple times a week.
What?
I know my military history.
Before Vegas was known as Sin City,
they called it Atomic City.
Anyone got any sunscreen?
(UPBEAT MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
♪ How lucky can one guy be? ♪
(LOUD CHEERING)
There's, like, 54 years
worth of baseball games
we can bet on in here.
What? You don't like money?
♪ Ain't that a kick in the head? ♪
♪ The room was completely black ♪
♪ I hugged her and she hugged back ♪
♪ Like the sailor said, quote ♪
♪ "Ain't that a hole in the boat?" ♪
Security's pretty tight.
I don't know how we're
gonna get into the show
with no tickets, which are sold out.
Why don't we call in a bomb threat?
They'll shut it down. Clear out JFK.
For once, I know where the
son of a bitch is gonna be.
I'm taking Flynn
out at the show tonight.
Okay, so how do you plan on keeping
the President and a dozen
other celebrities safe?
Saving history is your
job. Mine is Flynn.
What, so you just
get to make this call?
- No debate?
- No, there's no debate.
Guys, I got uniforms.
We can get in.
What? How did you...
'Cause in '62,
i'm pretty much invisible.
It's my superpower.
Really? You couldn't have
found me a thong?
It's a cigarette girl's uniform.
Hey, I didn't invent Vegas.
Well, go back and invent
me a waitress uniform.
Got it.
("LUCK BE A LADY" PLAYING)
(MUSIC)
♪ Luck, be a lady tonight ♪
Ever dream you'd see the Rat Pack?
Got to admit,
despite the unrelenting fear,
this job does have its moments.
Hmm.
♪ Tonight ♪
(MUSIC)
♪ Luck, let a gentleman see ♪
Hey, sweetie.
How about a martini
and a few hours of you?
Really, Joey?
If that's how you talk to a lady,
it's no wonder you never get one.
(LAUGHTER)
Excuse my friend, doll.
He's terrible after his second martini.
Even worse after his third.
Thank you.
♪ A lady doesn't leave her escort ♪
(MUSIC)
♪ It isn't fair ♪
(FADING)
♪ And it's not nice... ♪
(FOREBODING MUSIC)
♪ A lady doesn't wander ♪
Hey. You see that guy up
there in the dark glasses?
That's Sam Giancana.
He's the biggest
mobster in the country.
He worked with both
the CIA and JFK
to try and assassinate Fidel Castro.
Let's just find Flynn.
Anthony. I can't believe I found you.
Come on. Let's go.
We can get you home.
Rufus. You can't be here.
- Go.
- Not without you. Let's go.
If that man comes back and
sees you, he'll kill you.
- He won't listen to me.
- Why would he?
You're his prisoner...
Who's completely unsupervised.
You are his prisoner,
right, Anthony?
(MUSIC)
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
One more.
You're helping Garcia Flynn?
- What does he have on you?
- Nothing.
He doesn't have anything.
Then why?
People are dying
because of Flynn.
You don't think I know that?
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
All a means to an end, right?
Here's to the amazing "Christy Pitt."
Christy who?
You'll be with us soon.
Anthony, you're not
making any sense.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Get the hell out of here, Rufus,
before it's too late.
Go! Here he comes.
He'll kill you.
SINATRA:
A very good friend of mine,
the President
of the United States,
john Kennedy. Yeah, Jack.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
Ms. Campbell, you have a
phone call from your sister.
It's urgent.
Thank you.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
You're gonna do exactly as I say.
And here is why.
(GUN FIRING)
(MUSIC)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Are you okay?
- Why was he after you?
- I don't know.
Are you Christy Pitt,
by any chance?
What?
No, my name is Judith Campbell.
You're Judith Campbell?
Who's Judith Campbell?
What do you think you're doing?
I'm saving your life.
You're welcome, by the way.
You let me out of here!
Lady, I'm trying to protect you.
By kidnapping me
from another kidnapper?
All right. (CLEARS THROAT)
We're Vegas PD.
We're, uh... we're undercover.
Let's see some badges.
Why would we bring our badges?
We're undercover.
They're back at the precinct.
If you're cops, I'm Princess Grace.
- Okay, we're not cops.
- Seriously. Really?
I really thought I had it sold.
Okay, look. The truth is we
do work for the government.
We're trying to get the
man who grabbed you.
His name is Garcia Flynn,
and he's dangerous.
And if he wants you,
he's not gonna stop coming for you.
So why does he want you?
- Lots of men want me.
- (SCOFFS)
They're usually more polite about it.
Why don't you come freshen up,
and we'll get this sorted out?
And then you're gonna let me go.
Yeah, as soon as possible...
Okay, she is hiding something.
What she is hiding is that
she is Kennedy's mistress.
- Seriously?
- For the last two years.
- And Sam Giancana's mistress.
- The mob boss?
Yes, remember the plot to
kill Castro I told you about?
She is the one that delivers
messages from JFK to the mob.
Not a lot of people know her name,
but she is at the dead
center of 1960s politics.
Okay, this is some real
Oliver Stone stuff right here.
She has some of the most
powerful men in the world
wrapped around her finger.
So she's an operator.
What does Flynn want with her?
(SQUEAKING)
- Come here!
- No! No, you... no!
You let go of me!
I am tying you up to keep you safe.
- He is not going to tie you up.
- Oh, the hell I won't.
Look, I don't know what this
Flynn guy wants, okay?
But he threatened me.
- With what?
- He knows things about me.
Personal things
that are none of your
damn business.
- What, like screwing JFK?
- Wyatt!
I'm sorry.
We cannot play coy anymore.
- Stop it!
- How did you know that?
He has pictures, okay?
How he got them, I don't know,
but if I don't do whatever
it is he wants,
he could ruin me.
And cost Jack the next election.
Trust me.
We won't say anything.
Oh, so I should trust you?
Is that before
or after he ties me up?
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
You told me they can only see
what date we're traveling to.
Not where.
That's right.
So how'd they follow us here?
Jiya and Rufus are smart.
They must've figured out a way.
Rufus. I've had enough of him.
Hold on.
Rufus is just a civilian.
He's not part of this.
Not part of this?
He's their pilot.
If I take him out,
they can't chase us at all.
He's my friend.
You're not gonna touch him.
I told you there's gonna
be casualties, Anthony.
If you can't handle that...
Don't give me that.
I've given up everything for this.
My wife.
My kids.
And I haven't given up mine?
I'm not like you.
This isn't easy for me.
Watching people... good people... die.
If that's what it takes to
wipe Rittenhouse from history,
then that's what we have to do.
You understand?
All a means to an end, huh?
We need to get that woman back.
(DOORS SHUT,
eNGINE TURNS OVER)
Let the record show
that our restraint...
Water?
If you sprinkle it on
top of a glass of gin.
So, you and brooding blue
eyes in the next room.
You sleeping with him?
What? Um, no.
He could use it. He's
wound pretty tight.
Okay, I'll just...
(CLEARS THROAT)
So how'd you know?
This Flynn guy tell you?
Doesn't matter.
Your secrets are safe with us.
As soon as we find Flynn,
you can go back to...
To Jack?
All right. Go ahead, say it.
You think I'm a tramp.
No.
I think you're fascinating.
Don't think another woman's
ever called me that before.
I mean it.
A woman...
Especially in this day and age.
Living the life that you're living.
The people that you know.
The things that you've seen.
Honestly, I... felt like a nobody.
And then one night, I met Jack.
And the next morning,
it was all different.
Like a roller coaster.
You ever wake up one day and
not recognize your own life?
Es, actually.
A lot lately.
And now I never know
what's going to happen next.
I really don't.
Isn't that terrifying?
Some of the time.
Do you ever wish that you
could go back to your old life?
Never.
It'd be easier, I guess,
but I think if I did,
i'd always wonder.
Wonder what?
If I was missing out
on something better.
You said that name before.
Who the hell is Christy Pitt?
I don't know,
but that's who Anthony said
they were here to get.
And Anthony's not a hostage?
He's working with Flynn?
Yeah, but you got to understand.
Anthony would never hurt anyone.
He lives for his wife and kids.
I don't get it.
I don't get any of this.
From the jump,
flynn's been five steps ahead of us.
I'm sick of it.
Let's get ahead of him for once.
The name Christy Pitt
mean anything to you?
- Never heard of her.
- Rufus, find out who she is.
Meantime, we're not gonna find Flynn.
Flynn's gonna find you.
I'll take you back
to your hotel room,
and when Flynn shows up,
which he will, sooner or later,
i'm gonna take him out.
- You want to use her as bait?
- He's not gonna hurt her.
He needs her for
whatever he needs her for.
Are we 100% sure
this is our best plan?
And you'll get the pictures back?
When it's all over?
Yeah, they're yours.
I need a word.
We can't risk it.
She's too important
to JFK and to history.
I cannot do my job
boxed in like this,
worried about knocking
over a salt shaker
and somehow changing history.
- This is not a game.
- I agree.
Flynn wants to wipe out everything,
so if we have a shot
at him, we take it.
I'll do it by myself if I have to.
You don't give the orders.
You got a problem,
take it up with Agent Christopher.
I am not a soldier,
i don't take orders,
and you are not taking her.
Try and stop me.
So, how long I got to stand here?
Until Flynn sees you.
And you're sure this is safe?
Absolutely.
I've been around long enough
to know when a man is lying.
I'm not lying.
- I would tell you.
- Tell me something.
You got a girl?
Someone you love?
Would you risk her life?
Is that how sure you are?
Just trust me.
If I had a nickel every
time a guy told me that...
He's coming.
(MUSIC)
Are you sure there's
no Christy Pitt here?
Got this bottle of champagne
I'm supposed to deliver to her.
I'm sorry, man.
No one by that name.
Thanks.
(MUSIC)
Come on.
I'm not just gonna stand
here and do nothing.
(MUSIC)
- (PHONE CHIMES)
- (WYATT GRUNTS)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
- What took you so long?
- Where are the others?
They're halfway across town.
But you and I have a deal,
so as long as
I get those pictures...
You wanted me?
You got me.
Now, let's get this over with.
(MUSIC)
Oh! Oh!
- It's just us!
- I told you to wait downstairs!
Yeah, no, you look like
you had it well in hand.
Just saying. What happened?
She double - Crossed us.
That's what happened.
- She went right to Flynn.
- Well, of course she did,
because Flynn still has the pictures
and she's still afraid
that he's gonna use them.
He has the upper hand.
Plus, you could've been
a little nicer to her.
(SCOFFS)
What? No. Hey,
where are you going?
What are we supposed
to do now?
(MUSIC)
ID and badge.
Hi, Paul. He's with me.
My usual driver is sick today.
Oh. Hello, Ms. Campbell.
The general's expecting you.
Thank you.
(KNOCKING)
General.
Judith.
Oh, I'm so glad you called.
- Mm.
- It made my night.
Well, If a call made your night,
then what I have planned for
you will make your whole month.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh.
But first,
a glass of the Chateau Margaux?
Of course.
I will be right back.
(MUSIC)
Mmm.
Any problems?
Besides you? No.
Keys?
Right, 'cause I was born yesterday.
Pictures, please.
And the negatives?
Now, take me home.
Just one more little
errand to run.
(MUSIC)
2012?
You want this telegram
delivered 50 years from now?
Look, you said you can do
it anytime, anywhere.
Can you do it or not?
Hey, It's your money.
What do you want
the message to say?
Jessica.
(KEYS CLACKING)
I know this might be
hard to understand.
But whatever happens on Saturday,
february 11th, 2012...
Go home with Wyatt.
Even if he's being an ass.
Just let him take you home.
And know that he loves you.
More than you'll ever know.
(MUSIC)
Yeah.
Thanks.
Worked in "Back to the Future II."
Wyatt.
I know what you're gonna say.
No, you don't.
Look. I understand.
I would do anything
to get my sister back.
Look, I'm sorry about before.
I get it's your job,
keeping history the
way it's meant to be.
I don't believe
in "meant to be," though,
or fate or anything like that,
and if you knew how Jess died...
You would know there's
no such thing.
It's all just dumb luck
and random chance.
It's just a roll of the dice.
Guys, guys, guys.
I know why Flynn is here.
It was staring
at me right in the face.
I'm so sorry, It was staring
at me the whole time.
Slow down.
It's just such an outdated phrase.
I've only heard it once used at MIT.
Leave it up to Anthony to call it that.
Rufus, what are you talking about?
Christy Pitt.
It's not a person.
It's the Christy pit.
Named after the physicist Robert Christy.
It's slang for an
A - Bomb's plutonium core.
(MUSIC)
A nuke?
Technically an atom bomb.
How in the world could Flynn
possibly steal an atom bomb
without anybody noticing?
He doesn't have
to steal the whole nuke.
Just the plutonium core.
Once the pit's removed,
it's actually quite small.
Wait, so Flynn
is suddenly an expert
at dismantling an atomic bomb?
Well, Flynn doesn't have to be.
He's got Anthony.
Could they take the
core in the Mothership?
I don't know.
It's not exactly something
we ever tried before,
but if it explodes during
a time jump,
who knows what it'll do?
To the past or the present?
And Flynn's just crazy
enough to try it.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Good to go?
We got to get to the
test site, fast.
Welcome to the Sands, sir.
See? Invisible.
(MUSIC)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TYRES SCREECHES)
I think that's them. Hold on.
(MUSIC)
Wyatt, what are you doing?
He's gonna hit us!
- No, he won't.
- How do you know?
'Cause then we all blow up.
Wyatt.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
- Stay in the car!
- No!
No, you cannot do this alone.
- I'll get the nuke.
- I'll get Judith.
Be careful.
(GUNSHOTS FIRING)
(FIRING CONTINUES)
Go! I'll cover you!
Anthony!
Give me the suitcase.
I can't.
You can't give Flynn an atomic bomb.
There is no means to an
end that justifies this.
I know you, Anthony.
This isn't you.
Judith!
Are you okay?
I didn't know.
I wouldn't have helped him
if I knew about the bomb.
I believe you. Okay?
I got to get you out
of here. Come on!
Please.
Get down! Get down!
(EMPTY GUN CLICKING)
(INTENSE MUSIC)
I got it!
(MUSIC)
- Rufus!
- No!
- Get out of the way, Rufus!
- Anthony gave us the nuke!
- It's not good enough!
- He's my friend!
And he needs our help!
(SLOW DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
So, was it worth it?
Protecting Jack?
I didn't do it for Jack.
I did it for me.
I mean, at the end of the day,
that's all I have, right?
Hey.
Are you gonna be okay?
Always am.
Oh, hey. Sorry about the
crack on the head, gorgeous.
Don't take it personal.
What happens to her?
Eventually, her secrets
come out anyway.
She's vilified by the public,
and she dies of cancer.
Damn. She seems like
she had it all together.
No one's got it all together.
Better get the suitcase
back where it belongs.
Hopefully before anyone
knows that it's gone.
(UNCERTAIN PIANO MUSIC)
No, no, no, no.
He switched it.
Rufus...
Does Flynn have the nuke?
(MUSIC)
(CLANGING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Did you find Flynn?
Yeah. We found him.
And?
What did he want in Las Vegas?
You're gonna want
to sit down for this.
You can't be serious.
We saved Judith Campbell.
Kept history the same.
But Garcia Flynn is still alive,
and he got away with an atomic bomb.
The situation was chaotic.
On the upside, we're finally
starting to gel as a team.
Just saying.
And you believe that
Anthony is working with Flynn?
I think it's complicated.
There's got to be
an explanation as to why.
Anthony's not the type of guy
that would do something like that.
They never are on the surface.
Well, makes one part of our job easier.
We don't have to rescue
Anthony Bruhl anymore.
We just need to eliminate him.
Leave Flynn without anyone
to pilot the Mothership.
That crossed my mind.
And in this gun battle, did you
ever get a shot at Anthony?
Never a clean shot.
Next time, make sure you do.
(MUSIC)
- Jiya.
- Yeah?
You found the Mothership
in Vegas in the past.
Do you think you might
be able to track her down
in the present?
Probably, but it'll take some time.
Then get started.
(SIGHS) I forgot my...
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
Did it work?
I... i'm so sorry, Wyatt.
- It was a long shot.
- Do you...
I'm gonna change out
of these clothes.
Hey!
You going somewhere?
We need to talk.
Okay, those are four
terrifying words.
I met this woman today,
and she seemed like
she had it all together,
but the truth is that she didn't.
No one has it all together.
Least of all me.
I know.
And it's okay.
A lot has changed recently at work,
and I need to get my head straight,
and I don't know if I'm
gonna be able to do that
while I'm living here.
With you.
(MUSIC)
Is this about the wedding?
We can elope, for God's sake.
It's not that.
I'm gonna go stay with my
mom for a few days or weeks.
I'm not really sure how long.
I'm sorry.
(MUSIC)
Okay.
Really?
Lucy, I love you.
I want to spend the rest
of my life with you,
so if you need to spend some time,
figure things out first...
Do it.
Hey, I'll be here when you're ready.
Hey.
Thanks for not throwing me
under the bus with
Agent Christopher.
Anthony's a good guy.
I know you don't know him,
but trust me, I do.
There is something going on,
and I am not gonna let my friend
die without knowing the truth.
For the record,
i'd do the same for you and Lucy.
Thanks.
Aren't you at all curious as
to why this is all happening?
I don't get trained in why.
Just the who,
what, where, and when.
Yeah, but without the why,
how can we be sure we're on
the right side of things?
(MUSIC)
I found it.
The Mothership.
Where?
I've got it to a 50 - Mile radius.
We need to do better than that.
We find the Mothership,
we find Flynn.
(INTENSE MUSIC)
(MUSIC)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: October 18, 2016