Previously on "Timeless"...
I know a lot about you, Emma.
You faked your own death,
and hid in the past.
You have no idea what you're up against.
I have a pretty good idea.
No, you don't.
I know things that Anthony doesn't know.
Things that they have
planned for that machine.
You're helping Garcia Flynn?
What does he have on you?
I've given up everything for this.
This isn't easy for me.
Jessica died. It was my fault.
That's all I can think about.
- I'm so sorry.
- You help me.
I'll give you the name
of your wife's killer.
The guy you're looking for...
is currently serving for two
other murders in San Quentin,
and his name is Wes Gillian.
What're you gonna do about it?
I want you to help me steal
the time machine to save Jess.
Will you help me save my wife?
[loud knocking]
[tense music]
Hi.
Is everything okay?
Nice place.
Look, I'm sorry, I know it's so late,
but I need to tell you something,
and I'm only telling
you because I trust you.
- Okay.
- I'm going to get Jessica back.
- What?
- Me and Rufus. Tonight.
- We're stealing the Lifeboat.
- [laughs]
Do you have any idea how much trouble
you are going to get into?
I mean, this... that's insane!
That's an understatement.
Okay, let me get dressed.
Lucy, no, no, no... lucy. I'm
not dragging you into this.
If you think for one second that
I'm letting you go without me...
You have a deal with Agent
Christopher to get your sister back,
if you come, that's out
the window. You know that.
But... does it have to be tonight?
I don't have a deal.
The minute we actually stop Flynn,
they're never letting me
near that machine again.
What if Flynn takes out the
Mothership again while you're gone?
Then the Lifeboat's CPU will
tell us, we'll come right back.
What if you get into a
sticky history situation
and can't history yourself out of it,
- What are you gonna do without me?
- I've done my research.
What if someone gets hurt?
I'm gonna go back and make sure
the killer's parent's never meet.
That way, he's never born.
Nobody's getting hurt.
Lucy, Jessica's killer
murdered two other women.
My hope is to save all three.
[sentimental music]
- What about Rufus?
- I got him covered.
What about you?
Best case scenario,
you get kicked off the team.
Yeah, well, whatever happens,
it'll be worth it to have Jessica back.
♪ ♪
[cries]
Are you okay?
What do you need me to do?
I need you to call Agent Christopher.
Tell her everything.
Just give me a 20 minute head start,
that way, you'll be covered,
you won't get in trouble.
Why does this feel like
we're saying goodbye?
♪ ♪
Good luck, Wyatt.
Thank you, ma'am.
♪ ♪
Pretty sure, but there's
no way they're gonna believe
I'm your hostage.
Plausible deniability is
all we need, my friend.
March 1983's cutting it kind of close.
I was born December of that year.
What kind of clothes
did you pick out for me?
I don't know, something shiny.
If there are parachute pants
in that bag, so help me God...
Rufus, minute tops,
before this place is swarming
with Homeland Security.
You promise you're
not gonna hurt anyone?
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
All right, look good for the cameras.
[exciting music]
♪ ♪
And that's Rittenhouse's
dirty little secret.
Least as far as I know.
Hey, you wanted to hear it.
Feel better?
Oh, God, that's good.
I missed beer.
So you actually think
Rittenhouse can do all that
with the Mothership?
That's why they bankrolled
it in the first place.
Soon as I found out, sent
me running to the 1800s.
And you didn't know about it?
I had notions. But not this.
This is an existential
threat to reality.
[tense music]
We should destroy the machine.
Not the worst idea.
Oh, come on.
Even if we destroy the Mothership,
someone still needs
to smash the Lifeboat.
Rufus will do it.
If we told him, you know, the
fate of the world is at stake.
I think he might.
And what's to stop Mason or Rittenhouse
from just building another one?
Takes three or four years to build one.
- Buys us a little time.
- No.
We stick to the plan.
We wipe Rittenhouse from history.
Look,
you want to save your family, I get it.
But if the Mothership falls
into Rittenhouse's hands,
it's too dangerous.
Like I said, we stick to the plan.
Are we clear?
Anthony.
[airplane engines whooshing]
[indistinct chatter]
- Do you see her?
- No. I don't know.
♪ My only sunshine ♪
♪ You make me happy ♪
What're you doing?
"The A - Team."
Season one, episode 13,
"the Beast from a Belly
of a Boeing" airing live.
You know, we're kind of like the A - Team.
Through time. Time Team.
Okay, we're looking for
Claire Gilliam and Joel Bender.
The killer's parents.
Claire's a flight
attendant from Cleveland,
big Indians fan.
She has a layover tonight here in Toledo
where she has a one night
stand with a bartender, Joel.
- Classy.
- The 9:00 A. M. Tomorrow,
she's got a flight to
Milwaukee, never sees him again.
- And you know all this, how?
- Her son was a serial killer.
There's tons of interviews,
articles with him.
I've done my homework.
Look, all we gotta do...
is make sure these two
don't hook up tonight.
So it's like a reverse
"Back to the Future"?
- Got it.
- Okay.
She should be deplaning... now.
♪ ♪
It landed early.
It says the plane
arrived 20 minutes ago.
- We missed her.
- Wait, you didn't know that?
No, Rufus, I didn't know that.
Come on.
[clears throat] Excuse me.
Hi, uh, do any of you happen
to know Claire Gilliam?
- She's a flight attendant.
- Uh, stewardess.
They're called stewardesses.
I'm an old friend from high school.
- We're supposed to be meeting up.
- You just missed her.
Oh, no, where'd she go?
Hopped in a cab to the hotel, I think.
Yeah, I'm supposed to
be meeting her there.
It's the, uh, the Red Roof Inn...
- The Toledo Express Inn.
- Toledo Express Inn.
That's right. Great.
Thank you.
Welcome.
He's cute.
What the hell was Wyatt thinking?
- I get you're upset...
- Upset doesn't touch how pissed I am.
I'm fielding calls from the
President, for God's sake.
And Rufus was a hostage? My ass.
He was in on it, and
so were you, by the way.
The minute that Wyatt told me
what he was doing, I called you.
24 minutes after he left, actually.
So you're spying on me now?
I put a car on your house for
your protection, you're welcome.
This is about Wyatt's wife, Isn't it?
I knew he was fixated on her murder,
but this is just so reckless.
Can you blame him?
I mean how is he
supposed to let Jessica go
when, thanks to you, everyday,
he has to come to work
and stare at a damn machine
that can go back in time
and bring his wife back to life?
I thought we were a team...
he should've just come to me.
Oh, the way that I
came to you about Amy?
You and I had a deal.
While I chased Flynn through time,
you would be working on
getting me my sister back,
and how is that going so far?
- It is not that simple.
- You have done nothing!
I am not surprised that Wyatt stole
the Lifeboat behind your back...
I am shocked that he
didn't do it sooner.
I would steal it myself if I
thought it would bring Amy back.
And you would do the
same for your family.
[thunder rumbling]
[Tommy Tutone's
"867 - 5309/Jenny" playing]
♪ Jenny, Jenny, who can I turn to ♪
♪ ♪
♪ You give me somethin'
I can hold on to ♪
[arcade game beeping]
♪ I know you think ♪
♪ I'm like the others before ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Who saw your name ♪
Wow.
Yeah. Wow.
♪ Jenny, I got your number ♪
♪ I need to make you mine ♪
♪ Jenny, don't change your number ♪
That's her.
Can we we get two rum and Cokes,
- One with lemon?
- Yeah.
- You got it.
- Thank you.
♪ 867 - 5309 ♪
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
[scoffs] That's him!
So the people we're supposed
to keep from meeting just met.
[telephone rings]
- Yeah?
- I need to speak to Rufus.
[tense music]
Anthony?
Get Rufus now.
Um...
Hey, you all right? Who is it?
He's not available.
Well, make him available.
I'm not sure how to respond to that.
Jiya, who's on the phone?
Anthony Bruhl's on the line.
He says he'll only talk to Lucy.
That's ridiculous,
i'm gonna speak to him.
- No, you won't.
- What... why? Why me?
I don't know, but he asked
for you, just keep him talking.
No, no, no, no... that's... i...
Hello? This is Lucy Preston.
Where is he?
Rufus took out the Lifeboat, didn't he?
That's got to be the only
reason he's not picking up
his half dozen devices.
Why would Rufus want to talk to you
after everything that
you've done to help Flynn?
Yeah. Right.
So you and me...
we'll have to speak, Instead.
Face to face.
There's a park, 16th and Mariposa.
Downtown, one hour.
What? So you're here?
You're... you're in San Francisco?
Come alone. Leave your phone.
No technology. I'll
know if you're wired.
I don't understand. Why me?
Besides Rufus, you're the
only one that'll understand.
Understand what?
Give me one good reason
why I should trust you.
Because I have a plan
to end all of this.
For good.
[dramatic music]
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www. Addic7ed. Com
[The Human League's "(Keep
Feeling) Fascination" playing]
Two rum and Cokes, one with a lemon.
Thank you.
♪ ♪
- Uh! Hey.
- Sorry.
- Ma'am.
- Thank you.
- Did you just call me "ma'am"?
- Hey, bartender!
I'm sorry, ma'am, that's
just a force of habit.
From what?
Well, look, In the Special Forces,
- They teach you to be polite.
- Uh - Huh.
- Yeah, right.
- No, no, no.
It's a true story... delta Force.
♪ ♪
Look me in my eyes and
tell me if I'm lying.
♪ Turned ♪
♪ Until the sun went down ♪
♪ ♪
Oh, my God, when Len Barker
pitched that perfect game?
Stop, that's crazy...
I was at that game.
- What?
- Yeah, I am a huge Indians fan.
- No way.
- Yeah.
So you like baseball?
No, not really.
♪ ♪
- "Manimal"!
- What?
The... the show.
It's, uh, hard to find, where I'm from.
Oh, my God, I love "Manimal."
I mean, I love "A - Team," but still.
Yeah, that's because "The
A - Team" is the best show
- In the history of ever, yeah.
- Best show ever!
[both chuckling]
What?
For most girls, oh, I
don't know, "Flashdance"
or "Staying Alive" is their thing,
but most guys think that I'm a weirdo.
You are.
♪ ♪
I am, too.
Hey, do you guys want to get out of here
and go to a club or something?
Oh, actually, I'm waiting for
a friend to arrive, so... i can't
- Special bulletin here, folks,
- _
tornado watch currently in effect
for Lucas, Fulton, and Wood counties.
We've got storm clouds moving
east all along this area
with gale - Force winds as high as 65...
That does not sound good.
Ah, they always make it
seem worse than it is.
[groaning]
Oh, my God.
What happened, are you okay?
There's a tree down in the road.
I couldn't see anything...
I slammed right into it.
Here, sit, sit.
Were you wearing your seat belt?
No, I'm not nine years old.
Here, I'm a stewardess,
i know first aid.
- Is there a first aid kit?
- Right here.
- Ugh.
- Hey, I can help with that.
- I got it.
- They were closing the highway.
Pretty much every road in the area,
so I am sorry to say, folks,
but you're all stuck here.
Well, It can't be that bad.
- Let's go.
- I'm not going anywhere.
Okay, It's cool.
[tense music]
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Well, I think I should
accompany Lucy to meet Bruhl.
He and I have worked
together for over a decade.
We're mates. He trusts me.
Yet he didn't ask for you.
Which is precisely why
I think it's a trap.
Thank you, I'll take
that under advisement.
Okay, can we just be
serious for a minute?
What if Flynn grabs her again,
jumps into the Mothership?
We can't very well chase
her with a Lifeboat gone,
- Now can we?
- It's a risk.
There's a chance that
Bruhl means what he said.
If he has a way to end all
of this, we can't ignore it.
We have to try.
I... i have to try.
I'll take the risk.
We need to get going if we're
going to make it in time.
Jiya.
If there really is
a tornado out there...
- What if it hits the Lifeboat?
- It's safe in the barn.
Right, because barns
never blow away in storms?
Would you look at these two?
I mean, seriously, what are the odds?
- Just try and take it easy.
- "Take it easy"?
My wife's life hangs in the balance
of these two idiots over there flirting.
All right, Logan, If
we can escape the Alamo,
then we damn sure can ball block
Rick Springfield over there.
[thunder rumbling]
[chuckles]
It's 12 hours until Claire
leaves for Milwaukee, all right?
I'll stay on Joel, I'll
never leave his side.
Let's split up. I'll take Claire.
Rufus, he cannot go to her room.
Right, 'cause if he does, they'll bang
and conceive a serial killer, got it.
That is not a sentence
you say every day.
[The Human League's "Don't
You Want Me Baby" playing]
Uh, bartender?
Can I have a...
banana daiquiri?
Uh, I got to get the blender.
It's a whole thing.
Kind of had my heart set on it.
All right.
Let me get the Curacao.
♪ Now five years later on ♪
♪ You've got the world at your feet ♪
♪ Success has been so easy for you ♪
- Hey.
I just wanted to tell you, you
were great back there with that cop.
Oh, thank you.
- That was nothing.
- Yeah.
Hey, do you want to
play a game or something?
Uh, sure, but fair warning,
i'm really bad at these.
[scoffs] I haven't played
Ms. Pac - Man in years.
Didn't it, like, just come out?
♪ Don't ♪
♪ Don't you want to ♪
No, I'm very concerned about drug abuse.
- Especially among the young.
- Did you put anything on the windows?
The duct tape's in the drawer.
All right, well, be careful. Love ya.
Everything okay?
Yeah, my sister is getting worried.
It's getting pretty bad out there.
- Sorry to hear.
- Thanks.
- Hey.
- Becky.
- So, crazy being stuck here.
Makes you wonder what we're gonna do...
to pass time.
You could play Galaga.
That's one idea.
Um, I'm gonna go put on some music.
Dude.
Go talk to her.
Oh, um...
she kind of scares me.
I mean, It's the whole
Olivia Newton - John of it all.
Anyways, I'd rather just
stay and hang with you.
[Joan Jett and the Blackhearts'
"Crimson & Clover" playing]
'Cause you're super cool.
♪ ♪
♪ Crimson and clover ♪
[blender whirring]
Sorry. Tricky little bugger.
- You okay?
- Yeah, what... yeah I'm fine.
Well, except that my boyfriend
took off on an unauthorized,
illegal trip to 1983 and
didn't bother to tell me.
I'm sure that he was just
trying to protect you.
Oh, that is such crap.
[emotional music]
If you care about someone,
if you trust someone, If you...
might even love someone...
you tell them something like this.
♪ ♪
Yeah.
Sorry, um...
so how'd you find out
the guys were gone?
Wyatt told me.
Before.
You know, I had to buy
him some time and...
he had to tell me.
You know?
- Right.
- Tracker all set?
- Yeah, she's ready.
Um, our people will be seconds away
if you're in any trouble at all.
Okay.
Are you okay?
Could be worse.
Could be the French and Indian War.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
We're tracking her now.
- Anthony, I... i...
- Go!
- What is that?
- She stopped.
Move in now.
Inside! Inside!
- Where are you taking me?
- Where is it?
- Where's what?
- Your tracker.
- Where is it?
- What are you talking about?
I don't know... i don't
know what you're talk...
♪ ♪
Where's the signal? Get it back.
- I'm trying.
- Jiya, try it.
♪ ♪
- I just want to talk.
- Want to talk about what, okay?
I came to you 'cause you said that
you had a way to end all of this.
And I do. I just need your help first.
[indistinct chatter]
She's back.
♪ ♪
She's headed west,
west on 16th.
♪ ♪
Stop there. Against the wall.
Okay... ow! Easy, easy, easy, easy.
Jeez.
Stop!
Rufus is gone.
[tense music]
So I guess I got to trust you.
I wish I could say the same.
I know what my family must think of me.
I'm sure Homeland
Security's questioned them.
They probably think I'm a monster.
Anthony...
either you trust me or you don't.
I... i get that you and Flynn are
trying to wipe out Rittenhouse...
We're no better than Rittenhouse.
I know.
I'm just a cog in
Flynn's machine, I get it.
I do.
But I can't do it anymore.
[sighs]
Not with what Rittenhouse plans to do.
Thank you.
Okay, look...
Rittenhouse tries to control everything.
But truth is, It's a struggle.
They've always fought
against outliers, rebels.
JFK, MLK.
And these days, they lose
more control every year.
But what if they could change it?
Change what?
- Change history?
- Go back.
In the Mothership.
Attack key moments in time,
til they get what they want,
a reality in their image.
Shiny, happy, brave New World.
Sterile, clean...
and totally under their thumb.
Are you telling me that...
Rittenhouse wants to
take the Mothership back
so they can nuke history
even more than Flynn?
Sister...
you ain't seen nothing yet.
Flynn's the only thing
standing in their way.
But it's not enough.
I can't risk them
getting the Mothership.
So I'm gonna destroy it.
And I hope to God you and Rufus...
will blow up yours, too.
There'll be people
who don't want you to.
Don't trust them.
And don't trust Connor Mason.
So I'm just supposed to believe
everything that you're
telling me right now?
Tell your government agent
to turn on her satellites.
When you see an explosion in Oakland...
you'll know I've
destroyed the Mothership.
And I got to believe you'll
do the right thing, too.
♪ ♪
Grab the power pellet to your right.
- No, the other right.
- Okay, okay.
[laughs] Grab it.
You're actually really good at this.
Oh, It's all about the reflexes, ma'am.
Hey!
Claire.
Right?
Hi, yeah, you were on the flight.
You remember. 7D.
Almost did recognize you out of uniform.
You took real good care of me.
Mm. Gave me that extra tiny vodka.
Let me return the favor, come on.
Oh, actually, I'm in
the middle of something.
Come on, just one drink.
- Don't tell me you're stuck up.
- Read a signal, buddy.
The lady says no thanks.
[chuckles]
No one asked you...
buddy.
♪ ♪
Come here.
See, now you're not reading my signal,
and that's a problem.
Are you reading my signal now?
♪ ♪
Sorry.
It's an occupational hazard.
How do you like your job?
Besides the predatory schmucks?
Oh. [laughs]
- I used to love it.
- Yeah?
Yeah, I mean, I joined 'cause
I wanted to see the world.
Me, too.
Well, so far, I've seen
Columbus, Milwaukee,
rockford, Chicago a couple of times.
- Wow.
- I know. Really glamorous, right?
[both chuckle]
Pays the bills.
So if you could do
anything, what would you do?
- I'd go home.
- To Cleveland?
Yeah, how did... how did you know that?
Uh, It's just a guess.
- Well, you're an Indians fan.
- Right, yeah, of course.
Wow, you're really paying attention.
[chuckles]
You should go home.
I wish I could.
There was this thing with my mom.
It's just, uh...
it's a whole thing, so...
I can't go home until I can either...
prove her wrong or...
have some good news.
[emotional music]
Look...
do you want some advice?
If you have the chance to
go home and see your family,
you should do it.
You don't want to live with any regrets.
Tomorrow, I get to see my
family for the first time in...
years.
♪ ♪
[door opens]
- There you are!
- Claire.
You made it!
- Ugh, yeah.
- Finally.
Oh, my gosh, you're soaking.
Yeah, yeah, the roads were flooded.
It's a nightmare, you
got out just in time.
- Here, come sit down.
- Oh, thank you.
Hey, you found your friend.
- Hi.
- What?
Well, he came to the
airport looking for you.
I told him you were here.
- Oh, no, no, no, we just met.
- Yeah.
- He's not your friend from high school?
- No.
But he knew your name.
I think you're confused about something.
Um, can I talk to you for a second?
Okay, wait, wait, wait, wait.
No, I think you should
just stay away from her.
Well, If you let me
explain, then I could...
You know what, I think
you heard the lady.
Hang out in the lobby if you
want, grab yourself a coffee.
But you can't stay here.
♪ ♪
Yeah, of course.
You okay?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah. Thank you.
Yeah.
- You okay?
- Damn it. No matter what I do,
they end up together.
Okay, that's just it.
- Maybe it's just...
- No,
don't you dare say
"fate" to me right now.
No, that is just two people
who make a stupid decision
to bang in a hotel room,
and my wife dies because of it.
[sighs]
Okay.
Okay, here's the deal.
We're gonna lure Joel
into the back hallway.
"Lure him"?
In the what... what are you going to do?
I'm just gonna take
him on a little ride.
So we're just entering
kidnapping territory here?
With an armed state
trooper in the building,
and a life - Threatening storm...
I don't know... yes, pretty much.
[thunder crashes]
Wyatt...
you promised you wouldn't hurt anyone.
Rufus, I'm not gonna hurt anyone.
This is just something I got to do.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
You think Bruhl was telling the truth?
I - I don't know,
but if he is and he's going
to blow up the Mothership,
i think we should destroy the Lifeboat.
What about your sister?
We get her back first, of course.
But Bruhl's right.
These machines are too dangerous...
nobody should have
them in the first place.
You think Mason or my
bosses are just gonna smile
and say, "Sure, let's torch it"?
No, we do it ourselves.
- They'll build another one.
- Not for a couple years.
You think Wyatt's in trouble now?
Can you imagine the ocean
of crap you'd be swimming in?
I can, but if we have a chance
to end all of this now...
[chuckles]
How many opportunities does
a girl get to save the world?
♪ ♪
Okay. Let's do it.
But for now, this has to be our secret.
You can't mention it to
anyone else, especially Mason.
Mason... how can he work with
Rittenhouse, knowing this?
I know, he's a son of a
bitch, but I have proof,
photos of him meeting with
someone from Rittenhouse.
What proof?
♪ ♪
Lucy?
I've seen this man before.
I drove to his house, and
I knocked on his front door.
That's my father.
♪ ♪
Tornadoes have been sighted
in northeast Fulton County
and as far north as Lucas County.
The public is ordered to stay
off the roads and take cover.
Hey, there's, uh... there's flooding.
- Sorry?
- In the kitchen.
Uh, there's water
everywhere. It's spreading.
Let me just go and check on this.
Your sister okay?
I don't know. Phone lines are down.
She, uh, lives in a
double wide with her kid.
No basement. I'm worried.
Hey, man, I'm sorry.
For everything.
♪ ♪
Hey.
- Tough guy.
- You need to go.
The girl's mine. I saw her first.
You're not listening to
me, man... get out of here.
Oh, I'm hearing your signal now.
Loud and clear.
[blows landing]
Hey! Knock it off, right now!
- Whoa.
- Hold on.
Now you, stand over there.
You okay?
Now whatever problem
you're having, It ends now.
- Yes, sir.
All right.
- Whoa... hey, hey!
- Okay, easy, easy.
I got a permit for this,
i'm in the military.
He does.
I want to see some ID.
- Right now.
- I... i don't have it on me.
What do you think I
am, some kind of idiot?
Hands up now, where I can see them!
All right. Easy.
Turn around.
Turn around!
Everything all right?
When can we be ready?
Five more minutes.
Then we can take Emma out for a spin.
- The three hour tour.
- [chuckles]
Can't believe you're
able to do all of that
without the Mason
computers and diagnostics.
Eh, It's what I get paid for.
Oh, that's right, I don't get paid.
You remember how to pilot it?
It's like riding a bike, right?
- Can I help?
- No.
I have learned from experience
there's no point rushing Anthony.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
Yeah, the roads are all blocked.
When it opens up, I'll bring him in.
[door opens]
Uh, there's a kid...
ran out into the storm.
- You got to help!
- What kid?
His name is Haley Joel.
He's short, kind of creepy - Looking.
Okay.
[blows landing]
Get me his keys.
You didn't have to do that.
I was getting him out of here!
Is Claire still at the bar?
It's, um... it's closed.
Well, where is she?
Rufus?
They went to her room.
No, what're you gonna do?
I saw the keychain.
I know her room number.
Wyatt, you promised.
What about Jessica?
What'd she think?
♪ ♪
[groans]
Wyatt!
[grunts]
Really sorry about this.
Sorry.
♪ ♪
- Oh, my God!
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Hold on!
- No, he's got a gun!
- Joel!
- He's got a gun!
- Stop! Shh, shh, shh.
Stop it, stop it, stop
it. It's okay. Don't worry.
It's just... it's important to
me that you guys aren't together.
Okay, listen, listen, I'm sorry.
You seemed like a
really nice guy, you did.
- It's not you, I just...
- What?
- I just...
- No, no, It's not about that!
I'm trying to stop you guys
from doing something bad.
What?
I'm trying to save someone's life.
I won't touch her, man.
- I'll leave.
- No, no, no, please don't go!
- I'm sorry.
- Please don't go!
I can't take that chance. Go.
Please! Please don't kill me.
I'm not gonna hurt you,
we're just going for a drive.
Hey!
Stop fighting me. Please.
[thunder crashes]
♪ ♪
Hey!
Easy, easy.
You all right?
Uh... i'm okay.
It's all right, look, I'm
not gonna hurt you, okay?
Here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait.
♪ ♪
Come on, man.
- We got to go!
- Come on, man!
Hey, come on!
Wyatt, now!
Come on, come on!
♪ ♪
- I didn't mean to.
- I know.
[emotional music]
- I just...
- I know you didn't mean
for that guy to get hurt.
But at least the
killer will not be born.
And we saved three women.
Including Jessica.
♪ ♪
Yeah.
But he didn't deserve to die.
♪ ♪
To answer your question, she'd hate it.
What?
You asked me what Jessica
would think about all of this.
She'd be horrified.
Honestly, I don't know how
I'm gonna look her in the eye.
But she's gonna be there.
She's gonna be alive.
♪ ♪
Yeah.
I just saw Lucy downstairs.
She's as skittish as a cat.
How did it go with Bruhl?
- Did they have a nice chat?
- Sorry, Mr. Mason.
- National security and all that.
- Yes, well, obviously.
That's why I'm asking you.
What did Bruhl have to say to her?
I'm not playing games with
you today, I'm not in the mood.
Oh, what's the matter?
Your boss is miffed you
lost the time machine?
You should talk.
You've lost two of them.
You know what?
I am sick of you whispering in corners
and keeping secrets from me like
we're in bloody primary school.
And you know what, last time I looked,
this was still my building,
so you have no right...
The U. S. Government gives me the right.
Now please, respectfully,
get the hell out.
[alarm blaring]
They're back.
Right.
- Okay.
- [whispering] Okay.
Hands where I can see 'em.
Oh, okay. Hey, cool, cool, cool.
Everything's cool, all right?
He brought it back, okay? No harm right?
- Is that really necessary?
- Give them a minute.
What happened?
Tell me about Jessica.
I'm so sorry, uh...
Jessica's still dead.
They never found her killer.
What?
I'm so sorry.
No, that's not possible.
No, something doesn't seem right.
That... that doesn't make any sense.
The other two women Gilliam
killed, they're alive.
We saved them, just...
not Jessica.
No, that...
No, but he said he did
it, so that doesn't...
No, he's...
- He said he killed my wife.
- I know, I know.
Wyatt, you need to go.
That doesn't make any sense. No, no, no.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. No, no.
No, no, no... no, she's
alive, guys, please!
Just hold a second! No, she is alive!
No, she has to be!
Wait, wait! No, please!
She has to be alive! Jessica's alive.
♪ ♪
There was just an explosion in Oakland.
Pretty big.
♪ ♪
I don't get it.
There's no debris from the Mothership.
Maybe Anthony didn't
blow it up after all.
We found something else.
Jim.
♪ ♪
Oh, my God.
Two rounds to the chest.
Close range.
- Flynn?
- Most likely discovered
- He was trying to...
-... do the right thing.
What'd you tell his family?
That he died in an accident
serving his country.
It's good.
That's good.
♪ ♪
[knocking]
Come in.
Look, I know exactly who you are,
and I know you know exactly who I am,
and it's probably a huge
mistake coming over here,
but I thought that maybe even you
wouldn't hurt your own daughter.
And I just wanted to
tell you face to face...
that I know.
You've got this all wrong, Lucy.
I'm... i'm glad you
know about Rittenhouse,
i'm glad you're here.
It's a relief, honestly.
A relief?
Having to watch you from afar,
never being able to speak to...
to my own daughter. It's been...
[chuckles]
hasn't been easy.
And you...
you're smart, you're
beautiful, you're incredib...
I could care less what
you think about me.
What you are a part of is inhuman.
- Rittenhouse?
- Rittenhouse.
Well, I've got news for you, my dear,
you're a part of it, too.
Whether you know it or
not, It's in your blood.
It's your legacy.
And it's nothing to be ashamed of.
It's a gift.
[chuckles] Oh, Lucy.
We have so much to talk about.
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www. Addic7ed. Com