Previously on "Timeless"...
Jake Neville, NSA.
This project's command was taken over
by the National Security Agency.
The agents in control
of Mason Industries...
they're Rittenhouse.
She is there right now.
This is Rittenhouse we're talking about.
- They could kill her.
- Monsieur Charvet?
- Oui.
- I have so many questions.
Scary Rittenhouse dude is your father?
The guy who's been terrorizing
me, that's your dad?
I will never be a part
of this. Do you hear me?
Rittenhouse isn't a
choice. It's your legacy.
I'm just a secretary.
Ah, don't sell yourself short.
I saw that drawing on your
desk. You are very gifted.
I bet one day you'll do some
remarkable things at Lockman.
Maria Thompkins was Flynn's mother.
Hey.
What are we gonna do about Rittenhouse?
We fight.
How?
[melancholy orchestral music]
♪ ♪
You've been warming this
bench for the past two hours.
Look. I was about to step out
for my fantasy football draft,
but I can't leave you
here looking like this.
House rules.
So, a penny for your thoughts?
Might make you a millionaire, Father.
The rectory could use an upgrade.
My wife was the practicing Catholic.
She'd drag me to mass once
a month like clockwork.
I never really took it seriously myself.
Neither did I, for the longest time.
I have a job.
In the beginning, I
thought it was important,
that it could help a lot of people,
hopefully even bring my wife back to me.
But not matter what I
do, nothing gets better.
If anything, It only gets worse.
I get it. But when times are tough,
you just got to trust
that God has a plan.
What if you could change that plan?
I don't follow.
What if you could...
make a person go left instead of right,
backward instead of forward?
What if you had the power to
change the course of history?
Does that mean...
nothing's meant to be?
Does that mean God's not there?
Would he stop me?
What are you asking?
[sighs]
I'm asking for absolution.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
Guess this is what North Korea's like.
Listen. Whatever happens,
just do what they say.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Flynn made another jump?
So glad you could finally
join us, Ms. Preston.
Mr. Carlin.
I, for one, am sick of waiting
for Garcia Flynn to dictate our actions.
No more playing defense.
We're gonna take the son of a bitch out
once and for all.
How?
1962. Houston, Texas.
1962. That's the year
before the JFK assassination.
But why Houston?
Do you remember Maria Thompkins?
Wyatt Logan met her
during your NASA mission.
Yeah. Garcia Flynn's mother. Yes.
But what does she have to do with it?
In 1962, Thompkins was
a 17 - Year - Old junior
at Sam Houston High School.
The mission is to eliminate her.
- Whoa.
- You can't be serious.
No, no, no. There is no
way that we are doing that.
She's... she's innocent.
We don't expect either of you
to pull the trigger.
Meet your new tactical commander,
sergeant Major Caleb Sullivan.
You just lead him to the front door,
and he'll take care of the rest.
- Ma'am.
- Don't "ma'am" me.
Okay, so, you just
want us to play wingman
to the Terminator over there?
And you? You're fine with this?
You're just gonna stand
there and let this happen?
Flynn's mother may be innocent,
but she still raised a monster.
And given your performances,
this may be the only
way to get this done.
Forget it. We refuse.
You cannot make us do
this. This is not right.
Maybe I haven't been clear.
This operation has been
green - Lit at the highest levels.
It's a go.
You refuse, we will charge you
with aiding and abetting
a wanted terrorist.
So, you can either spend the
next few hours working for me,
or the next 10 to 15
years wishing you had.
That clear enough for you?
♪ ♪
[takes deep breath]
I'm sorry. Agent
Neville's bedside manner
leaves something to be desired.
I guess I shouldn't be
surprised that you're here.
You have to understand
Flynn is out of control.
If this one death can save hundreds...
Save Rittenhouse, you mean.
This is the murder of
an innocent girl, period.
He cares nothing about
history or collateral damage.
And what's his mother? What is she?
We need you on this trip.
You're our chosen historian.
You always have been.
- Go to hell.
- Lucy!
I know we're asking the unthinkable.
This isn't who you are.
You have such a good
heart, and I admire that.
I'm... i'm proud of you.
I only ask that you do this one mission.
The next one...
will be saving your sister.
I fully intend to honor the deal
you've made with Agent Christopher,
and I'm in a much better
position to do that
than she could ever be.
That's what you want, Isn't it?
More than anything?
[machinery whirring]
- Hey, could you...
- Hey, what?
Never mind.
Just so you know, you could
get a little queasy on reentry.
Don't worry about me. I'm
not your dance partner.
[rumbling]
[rumbling and whirring]
[groaning]
Are we here?
[breathing heavily]
[dart fires]
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
- Ohh.
- Holy sh...
You did it! Okay.
Um...
I just have to reconfigure
the coordinates.
Do you think Mason is
gonna be able to track us?
Not after what I did to his computers.
[rumbling]
[alarm beeping]
Wait a minute. I've lost them.
What do you mean, you've lost them?
They've jumped. They're no longer in...
_
- Nothing's responding.
- Get them up.
Where in the hell are they?
The system's crashing. Damn!
- [chittering]
- _
Rufus.
- I can try to run a diagnostic.
- Step away from the controls, Jiya.
Now!
Did you know he was
going to do this? Did you?
- No! I swear.
- Will somebody tell me
what the hell is going on?
This is Rufus's doing.
It's a computer worm.
We're dead in the water.
We can't track the Lifeboat.
And Jiya's not to be trusted.
She's sleeping with him.
- Mason!
- Rufus thinks he's smarter than me.
All right, well, I'll
handle this myself.
You get the hell out!
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www. Addic7ed. Com
[rumbling and whirring]
It's us! We're okay!
[laughing] We made it!
You did it! You held
the gun like I said, huh?
Yeah, pulled the
trigger between breaths.
Rufus, you're a badass.
If by "badass," you mean
scared out of my mind.
Okay. So, we just stole
a giant piece of top - Secret machinery
and made ourselves fugitives
from the US government.
- All good.
- You did the right thing.
If Rittenhouse is running the shop,
they can't have the time machine.
Your sense of calm is super annoying.
Rufus, they can't track
us? You shut them down?
Yeah, but it's only a matter of hours
before Mason is able
to counteract the worm
and get the network back online.
How much time does that give us?
The Lifeboat's battery is
drained after two jumps.
It'll need four hours to
recharge, If it even can, and...
Okay. Okay. It's all right.
One step at a time.
First step:
let's go get your sister back.
What?
I think that's reckless.
Flynn is still out there...
With all due respect, ma'am,
we don't work for the
government anymore.
I think Lucy deserves a shot.
I'll start the charge.
[laughing, crying]
Thank you.
[grunts] Okay.
[laughs]
So, what's the plan?
Okay, so, um,
we go to 1979, UC Berkeley,
and we make sure that my
mom and Henry Wallace meet.
[laughing]
They always said that it
was love at first sight.
They knew the minute that they
laid their eyes on each other.
Well, let's go play cupid.
- [laughs]
- [alarm sounding]
It's Flynn.
He's jumped.
Where?
[dark music]
♪ ♪
[whispering inaudibly]
Frankie says you have something
of vital interest to me.
These tax ledgers were seized
during the raid on one
of your establishments
a few years ago.
Key evidence for the tax evasion case
they're building against you.
Where'd you get these?
Post office, believe it or not.
Treasury Department keeps a...
poorly guarded file
room there, Mr. Capone.
That's your big gift?
As if they're gonna
get me for tax evasion.
Get him out of here.
I also have this letter
from your accountant, Mr. Mattingly.
He makes some fairly
scandalous accusations.
With this evidence, believe me,
you'd be going to prison.
Pay Mr. Mattingly a visit.
Make sure he can't
write any more letters.
I guess I owe you a debt of gratitude.
♪ ♪
What the hell are we supposed to do?
It's one problem at a time.
And right now that is Flynn
taking the Mothership to 1931.
Except now Rittenhouse has
taken over Mason Industries,
and they might be ten
times worse than Flynn.
Maybe we're fighting the wrong battle.
You're the one who
said we can't let Flynn
take a wrecking ball to
everyone and everything.
That was before we stole a
time machine, became fugitives,
and Jiya was forced to work next
to a bunch of homicidal dicks!
Rufus, like it or not,
we're the only ones
who can stop Flynn from hurting people.
And what about my sister, huh?
I mean, this was my last
shot. If we don't do this now,
i may never see my sister again.
They track us down after we get
back from Chicago, It is over.
My sister will be gone forever.
Okay, look, I get it.
None of us should have
to give up our families.
I know. I'm the last person
that should be saying that,
because I'm the selfish
ass that went after my wife,
but still...
letting Flynn murder through time...
that's madness.
And I think somewhere deep
down, we all can admit that.
Rittenhouse or not, Flynn's not
gonna stop until we stop him.
So, why us?
There's nobody else but us.
[phone buzzing]
- Hello?
- Jiya, It's me. Are you okay?
Rufus, what... did you slip me a burner?
Yeah. I got it from watching
"The Wire." Listen...
- Okay, where are you?
- I don't have a lot of time,
right now... you are
in a lot of trouble.
Whatever you did shut down the network.
Mason's pissed. He's gonna
get it up and running again,
and then he's going to find you.
That's why I'm going to
need you to run interference.
How the hell am I supposed to do that?
Delay. Distract. Do whatever you can
to keep them off of our
backs as long as you can.
Rufus, these guys are everywhere.
Jiya, we can't let them have
the time machine, all right?
I'm so sorry for
putting you on the spot.
The last thing I ever wanted was
for you to become a
double agent... believe me.
I know how hard it is.
What do you mean?
What the hell are you talking about?
I'll explain everything to you, I swear.
But you have to do this. We need you.
I need you.
Okay.
Okay, just come back to me safe.
- Promise?
- You too.
I wouldn't be able to live with myself.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Hi. What's up?
- Who were you talking to?
Myself.
I come here to think, clear my mind.
There's a lot going on.
Empty your pockets.
[scoffs]
Okay, a little handsy there.
I don't remember swiping right.
♪ ♪
You think I was born yesterday?
Hey, Singer!
Put her on ice. She
doesn't leave the building.
[whirring]
Be careful.
Oh, my God, you guys, this is terrible.
We stand out like sore thumbs.
Well, there's no time to go shopping.
Flynn's already way ahead of us.
I saw we own it,
embrace our fashion - Forwardness,
stop Flynn, and get
the hell out of here.
What if Flynn has already done
whatever it is he came here to do?
So, March 13, 1931, Chicago.
Where's Flynn headed?
There's only one place I can think of.
What can I say?
The crooked lawyers for the prosecution
somehow lost all the
evidence they had on me.
But you ask me?
They never had it in the first place.
That's Al Capone? He looks so young.
He was only 26 when
he became a crime boss.
And lost them in bank failures.
They should be the ones going on trial.
Is he not afraid to be
out in the open like this?
The people of Chicago loved him.
They would chant his name at Cubs games.
So, It's true, then?
All charges against
you have been dropped?
With no evidence, the
honorable Judge Wilkerson
had no choice but to drop the case.
Justice has been served.
[applause]
Wait, wait, wait. This isn't right.
Guys, look.
♪ ♪
Go, go, go.
[camera flashes firing]
Capone is supposed to be going
to prison for tax evasion today.
Flynn must have gotten him off somehow.
Well, that's not troubling at all.
For some reason, none of them good,
flynn has already wormed
his way in with Capone.
Well, with all that mob muscle,
it's gonna be hard to get
close to Flynn or Capone.
Which makes this a
first - Class, grade - A cluster...
- Maybe he can help.
- Mr. Ness,
it appears if Al Capone
is the Untouchable One.
Got a comment?
Any more questions?
[indistinct chatter]
♪ ♪
Come on.
Mr. Ness?
Mr. Eliot Ness?
I said no comment.
Oh, we're not the press. We're, um...
- We're private investigators.
- Yeah.
Uh, I'm Connery.
This is Costner.
And this here is our
driver, Robert... de Niro.
We're trying to get
information on the tall man
with the dark features with Capone.
Did you... did you see him?
He's not from Chicago. I
haven't seen him before.
No. He's definitely
not from around here.
Neither are we.
I can tell. Are you
wearing a woman's sweater?
His name's Garcia Flynn.
And we think he's
teaming up with Al Capone.
He is the most dangerous
gangster in San Francisco.
William Randolph Hearst...
he hired us himself
to dig up some dirt on him
and try and get him off the streets.
Yeah. And whatever he's
up to with Capone...
it's way worse than tax evasion.
You know, I told them... going
after Capone for his taxes
would never work.
Well, It could've worked.
[pounds on door] Hey!
Hey! Bathroom break?
The burner... we couldn't track it.
Your boyfriend covered every base.
Where are they, Jiya?
- Where the hell is my machine?
- I don't know.
And you expect us to believe you?
Look, he didn't say. He just...
he just said he was worried about me.
Do you have any idea how
much trouble you're in?
This is the National Security
Agency. Need I remind you?
Be smart.
Play ball.
[scoffs]
Oh, what's so funny?
You know, my first day on
the job, I was so scared,
intimidated.
I... i was in awe of you.
I mean, I was coming to work
for the Connor Mason.
I mean, my... my hero.
All I wanted to do
was to make you proud.
Right now, It's like
that moment where...
where Dorothy pulls back the curtain,
and she sees the Wizard
for who he truly is:
a coward.
Do you really think that this, um,
childish, plucky snark
is going to help you?
This is the real world.
You take your time,
you think, and decide:
help us or be arrested and incarcerated.
♪ ♪
[lock thuds]
Nice place. Very cozy.
It's a rat trap.
Capone was tipped off
as to where I lived,
so started getting death threats,
occasional brick through the window.
Sent my wife to Cincinnati
to stay with her sister,
and I moved in here.
How do you cope with all that?
Loved ones and family
in that much danger...
How do you still go after Capone?
Well, how could I not?
Couldn't look my wife in the eye
and tell her that I'd given up.
Couldn't look myself in the mirror.
Where could we find Capone right now?
We are in a little bit of a time - Crunch.
Garcia Flynn is very dangerous.
And Capone isn't?
Not by comparison.
Capone? The man responsible
for the Saint Valentine's Day Massacre?
I think we can all agree that both men
are incredibly dangerous.
Why don't we just focus on finding them
and stopping them from
doing whatever it is
- They're planning on doing?
- [pounding at door]
[pounding continues]
It's okay. That's Billy.
He's one of my guys.
Come in.
[rapid gunfire]
No. No. No, no, no, no, no.
What? No.
Eliot Ness... he can't be dead.
He's not supposed to
die for another 26 years.
How'd they even know he was here?
How do you think? Flynn.
This can't be happening. I mean,
capone is out there on the loose,
and the only guy that
can stop him is gone!
We got to get out of here right now.
We're just supposed to
leave him here like this?
What do you want to
do? Wait for the cops?
We don't have IDs.
I'm wearing button - Fly
jeans from The Gap.
There's nothing we can do.
♪ ♪
[sirens wailing]
- Where are we going?
- To find Capone.
- What about Flynn?
- One problem at a time.
Stop saying that. Why
do you keep saying that?
Do you know what the very
first Delta mission was?
1979, Iran.
That's right.
Go get the hostages out of Tehran.
One of my Delta instructors...
name is Diamond Dave...
he was on that mission.
The plane carrying the operatives
lands in the desert somewhere to refuel.
While it's on the ground,
a Navy helicopter crashes into it
due to the heavy winds.
So, Dave... he wakes up from a nap.
He sees the plane is on fire.
Now, he still thinks
they're 20,000 feet up.
He can't find a parachute,
so he just flings himself
right out the door,
right through the smoke.
Okay, this is all really nice, but
what is the point of this story?
So the guys afterwards asked Dave,
"if you thought we were
20,000 feet in the air,
"why the hell would you
fling yourself out the door
"without a parachute?"
Dave just looks at him and he says,
"all I knew was the plane was on fire,
"and I figured one problem at a time."
[sparks crackle, engine turns over]
First, we stop Capone,
and then we worry about
what Flynn wants with him
and everything else.
So, If Al Capone is
supposed to be behind bars,
how do we put him there?
I don't know. I mean,
without Ness, this is just...
Lucy?
I know who we can ask.
Hello. I'm so sorry
to bother you so late,
but are you by any chance Richard Hart?
What can I do for you?
Well, uh, we need your help.
It's about your brother,
al Capone.
Look. I don't know who
you people think I am.
You're Jimmy Capone,
born James Vincenzo Capone.
My name's Richard Hart.
You left Brooklyn when you were 16
and changed your name for a fresh start,
and wound up becoming
a Prohibition Agent.
And you haven't seen your family
or your brother ever since you left.
But you know what Al's been up to.
You can't read the morning
paper without seeing his name.
Keep it down, will you?
My wife and kids don't
know my real name.
Nobody does.
Did Al send you?
We look like mobsters to you?
You're from the bureau,
then? Is that what this is?
I work hard.
I don't take bribes.
Just because I was born a Capone,
that doesn't mean I act like one.
We know. You're a good
man and an honorable cop,
and that's why we came
to you in the first place.
- We really need your help.
- Who is it, dear?
Honey, It's...
- These people are lost.
- Sorry.
Just gonna give them directions
out of here. Won't be a minute.
Now, listen to me...
Your little brother Al
just sent Eliot Ness to the morgue.
[sighs]
I'm sorry to hear that.
Truly, I am.
But what do you want with me?
We need you to bring
us to see your brother.
- What?
- In person.
You crazy?
And then we need you to arrest him.
[laughs]
You are crazy.
[door opening]
Al!
Where's the fire?
I was having dinner with
Wrigley and some broads
when this Neanderthal drags me
out like I'm some kind of Joe.
Who's this guy?
This is the guy
who touched the Untouchable Eliot Ness.
Garcia Flynn.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Mayor.
How'd you know where Ness was holed up?
- I couldn't even find out.
- Exactly.
He's done more for me in one day
than you've done since I
put your sorry ass in office.
And the only thing he asked in return...
was to talk to you.
Is that so?
What the hell about?
[grunts]
Are you crazy?
I'm the mayor of Chicago.
And also a member of Rittenhouse.
♪ ♪
- Who sent you?
- I sent myself.
I have some questions,
and I need some honest answers.
Mr. Hart, Al should be in prison.
We need you to bring him in
before he kills any more people.
I don't have anything
to do with my brother.
- Leave me out of it.
- You're a federal agent.
I ticket rummies on the street.
I'm no Ness. I'm no Untouchable.
And like you said, I haven't
seen Al in over 20 years.
What makes you think I
could just waltz in there
- And see him now?
- You can try.
What makes you think I'd want to?
He's my little brother.
I love the stupid son of a bitch.
I wiped his damn nose, took
him to buy candy on the corner.
What makes you think
that I want to be the one
- To put him behind bars?
- Mr. Hart...
We're done here.
And if you tell anyone who I am,
you're gonna have more than
one Capone to worry about.
Did you know that he takes
ads out in newspapers,
looking for you?
All over the country, for years.
He misses you.
I understand how hard it
must be for you to face him.
I've had to give up family, too,
and nobody should have to do that,
but maybe he will listen to you.
- Maybe you could save him.
- Al's beyond being saved.
Mr. Hart, out of all the
jobs that you could've chosen,
you pick cop.
I mean, why is that?
I mean, don't you think
it's because you want
to set right what Al has done wrong,
because you know that
somebody has to stop him?
No matter how hard it is to do,
you have to do what's right.
You have to help us.
There's nobody else but you.
Aah!
Hey, watch where you're bleeding.
That's an antique.
Tell me about the meeting.
I don't know what you're
talking about. What meeting?
The one Julian Charvet told me
about in Paris four years ago.
Julian Charvet was killed
in Paris four years ago.
Felt like it was yesterday.
In his last few breaths,
he told me about this
Rittenhouse meeting
where all members get together,
but he didn't have the details,
so here I am, asking you the details.
Try the bat.
Wait. Hold on. Hold on.
The meeting was two years ago, okay?
- Two years ago.
- Where?
D. C.
All the Rittenhouse
big shots get together
to make sure everyone's
on the same page.
But it only happens every 25 years.
- The next summit is not until...
- 1954.
Yeah. 1954. Long time to wait.
Not as long as you'd think.
No, no. Stop. Stop.
- Al, you can't do this!
- I'm not gonna do anything.
He's the one who wants you dead.
But I don't want the mess.
Take him down to the docks.
No! Ugh! [muffled yelling]
Thank you for the introduction.
Hey, thank you.
Between those tax ledgers and Ness,
you killed two very big
headaches for me today.
But the way I see it,
i still owe you one.
And I hate owing favors.
I think I know a way to make it even.
♪ ♪
[elevator dings]
Swanky digs.
Lexington Hotel was the
height of luxury at the time.
At the time of what?
Hey, are you ready for this?
Hell no, I'm not ready.
Leaving home was the
smartest thing I ever done.
This was the dumbest.
[elevator dings]
Hey!
Frank Galluccio.
Looks like you finally hit puberty, huh?
Who the hell are you?
Who the hell am I?
I'm the one that broke
your nose over Shelly Russo.
[grunts]
Jimmy, Is that you?
We figured you were dead.
Not yet.
Who are they?
They're friends of mine.
Al's gonna be over the
moon when he sees you.
Come on.
- You know what I just realized?
- What?
We're totally the
Untouchables right now.
Oh, boy.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
Come on...
- We're up.
- That's great.
Where are they?
1931.
March the 13th, Chicago, Illinois.
When they jump back,
we can track their general area.
Well, that's a start.
Get teams ready to roll.
♪ ♪
[electricity crackles, winds down]
[alarm sounding]
What the hell happened?
You said you had them.
[all speaking at once]
What did you do?
I still have to pee.
Hey, boss. Sorry to interrupt,
but your brother's here to see you.
I'm busy.
Tell Ralphie to come
back in the morning.
It ain't Ralphie.
♪ ♪
Jimmy?
I was in the neighborhood.
You got a lot of damn nerve showing
up here after all these years.
You gained weight.
Yeah. You got old.
[laughs]
[sighs]
Who are they?
These are my friends.
Even that guy?
I'm likeable.
You people ain't from Chicago.
We're from California, actually.
Ah, land of the fruits and nuts.
That explains it.
Boy, first time I'm seeing
these famous scars on your
face... that's something.
Don't say the nickname they gave me.
I freakin' hate it.
The papers say you got them
in the war, but come on.
What's the real story?
Between us?
When we were teenagers,
i insulted Frank's sister.
This was his way of getting back at me.
Frankie, you did this?
He deserved it.
Bosses had us sit down, make peace.
Frankie's one of my best guys now.
I'm a Prohibition Agent.
Get out of here.
You're a G - Man?
Not a very good one.
[glasses clink]
So, what are you doing here?
You in some kind of
trouble or something?
- Maybe I'm here to see you.
- After all these years?
Come on. Let's not lie
to each other, Jimmy.
Actually, we were the ones
that asked him to come here.
We're looking for someone.
Tall guy. Name is Garcia Flynn.
Yeah. He was here.
Man of his word.
Did a couple favors for me.
I did one for him.
Did he happen to mention Rittenhouse?
Yeah, something about a
summit in D. C. In 1954.
All of them all together,
whatever that means.
Jimmy, tell me you didn't
come here just to ask me
about this guy Flynn.
I'm here to bring you in, Al.
[laughing]
You're serious?
It's one thing raising
hell as kids in Brooklyn,
but you're out of control.
I'm sorry, Al. I love you.
But someone has to stop you
before you hurt more folks.
You got some balls walking in
here out of the blue like this.
Dad died 11 years ago.
Our brother... remember
him? Back in '24.
Did you know that?
- Do you even care?
- Of course I care.
But not enough to come to the funerals.
Ma was heartbroken, you know.
I started wondering if
you were even still alive.
And now you show up here saying
you're some damn federal agent?
And that you and these
clowns are gonna bring me in?
That guy Flynn said these three
might come looking for him.
And when he left, he asked
me to do him one more favor.
And being a man of my word...
- Oh!
- No, no, no. Please!
Please. Please.
I made a deal to take
out the colored fella.
Flynn says they can't
follow him if I do.
- Can't let you do that.
- Jimmy.
You'd pull a gun on me?
Your own brother?
[gun clicks]
Lower your weapon, Al.
What are you gonna do? You
gonna... you gonna shoot me?
- I don't want to.
- But you want to take me to prison,
is that right?
Oh, Dad must be turning over
in his damn grave right now.
Dad wasn't around to
see what you became.
Neither were you!
You want to know why I disappeared?
Because I saw what you were becoming,
and I didn't want to end
up like that, like all this.
I may be a Capone, but you
and I are nothing alike.
You're right. We're not.
But we're family.
And family's more
important than anything,
which is why I know...
you won't shoot.
[shots fire]
Aah!
♪ ♪
Oh, my God. Rufus?
He shot me.
You got to stop the bleeding.
[dark music]
♪ ♪
[melancholy music]
[alarm sounding]
What's the status on this outage?
Oh, everything's on track.
We'll be up and running in a few hours.
And you'll be able to locate
them when they jump back?
Within a 50 - Square - Mile radius, yes.
All we'll need is time.
Good.
But if you want speedier
results going forward...
Yes?
I assume you know about
the NSA Data Farm in Utah.
I need access to their
12 exabytes of raw data,
which I have a sneaking
suspicion you can provide.
And what will you do with it?
My team has developed
advanced mining software,
more advanced than anything
the NSA will produce
in the next ten years.
It gives us the ability
to tap into cell phones,
email accounts, satellites,
traffic cams, that sort of thing.
Now, not only will we
be able to find Lucy,
rufus, Wyatt Logan,
garcia Flynn,
and the Lifeboat,
but if our test works,
we'll have the capability
to pinpoint anyone,
anywhere,
at any time you want.
Or we could, of course, just
wait and hope for the best.
[panting]
- How bad is it?
- Bullet's still in there.
We got to get him to a hospital.
In the '30s? No way.
They were segregated, and not good.
Yeah, well, we can't exactly
march him into an ER back home.
Our faces are on every single
government watch list out there.
I'm sorry, Rufus. I'm so sorry.
I should've... i
should've reacted faster.
One problem at a time, right?
Yeah.
Get me to the Lifeboat.
I'll take us home.
Police are on the way. Ambulance too.
I don't know if we can wait that long.
He's lost a lot of blood.
- Can you stand?
- Yeah. [grunts]
[groans]
We're just gonna take
him there ourselves.
Thank you for your help. I
know this was hard for you.
I'm sorry.
♪ ♪
- Okay, Wyatt...
- [Rufus wheezing]
Come on, Rufus. Stay with us.
- [wheezing]
- Okay, Rufus.
- Got to buckle him in.
- Rufus, look at me.
You have to get us back,
okay? We don't know how.
Come on, buddy.
- I just...
- Good.
I just...
Come here, buddy.
You want me to push a button? This one?
This one right here?
- In the seat. In the seat.
- Right here. Okay.
You got this, Rufus. Come on.
[whirring]
Stick with us, Rufus!
Tell Jiya...
We're buckled in. Get us out of here.
- What?
- Rufus.
Rufus!
- Rufus!
- Hey!
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www. Addic7ed. Com