Hello, I’m Niamh and welcome to Oxford Online
English.
In this lesson, we’re going to look at when
to use make and when to use do.
Does your language only have one verb for
make and do?
There isn’t one easy way to tell the difference
between make and do in English, but there
are some rules to help you.
Generally, you use make when you create something
and do for an activity or task.
You’ll learn more about these rules, see
when the rules don’t work, and get a chance
to test yourself at the end!
Part one: use make to mean ‘create something
physical’.
As we said, you use make to talk about creating
something.
However, this is a general point, which includes
many smaller rules.
Let’s see one.
What connects this group of sentences?
This statue is made of marble.
The toy is made of plastic.
The house is made of gingerbread.
They all use make.
But what connects them?
Can you guess?
We use make to talk about the materials which
you use to create something.
Here’s a question: you’re watching this
video on a phone, a tablet or a computer.
What’s it made of?
Probably, it’s made of plastic, metal and
glass.
So that’s rule number one: use make to describe
the materials used to create something.
Remember our gingerbread house?
Let’s look at our second rule.
Here’s another sentence:
I mmm some gingerbread for Christmas.
Which verb goes here?
Make or do?
I made some gingerbread for Christmas.
You use make with food and drink, because
you’re creating something.
Here are some more examples:
Can you make me a cup of coffee?
It's your turn to make dinner tomorrow.
My Dad makes the best sandwiches.
Now you know two rules about using make.
Let’s think about something new:
If you make a statue or make dinner, you’re
obviously creating something.
You have a physical result at the end.
But, there are some exceptions.
For example, you say do a painting or do a
drawing, even though you are creating something.
Monet did a lot of paintings of flowers.
There are also other things we make which
don’t produce a physical result.
Part two: use make to mean ‘creating something
non-physical’.
Look at a sentence:
He made a joke but nobody laughed.
Why do you think we use make here?
Let’s see some more examples, and you try
to work out the rule:
The politician made an important speech about
the economy.
They made so much noise I couldn’t hear.
She made an interesting comment in class.
Can you see what connects the words noise,
comment, speech, and joke?
They’re all nouns connected to speaking
and certain sounds.
Can you think of any other words like this?
You can also make a suggestion, make a call,
or make a slip of the tongue.
Make a slip of the tongue means you say the
wrong thing by accident, maybe because you
aren’t paying attention to what you’re
saying.
Be careful with comment.
These are nouns connected to speaking.
So, if you are speaking then you make a comment,
but if you are writing a comment you would
use the verb leave or add.
For example, please leave us a comment down
below!
There are other ways to use make meaning that
you create something, but not something physical.
For example:
She made lots of friends in the class.
We made great progress on the project.
He made a lot of mistakes on his exam.
I need to make an appointment at the clinic.
With phrases like this, it’s better to learn
and remember the phrase as one unit.
Finally, we often use make with money and
ideas connected to money.
So we say,
He makes €17,000 a year.
Their company made record profits last year.
I made a great investment and now I’m a
millionaire.
Or if you’re unlucky:
They made a loss after making too many bad
bets.
So, you can use make to mean ‘create something
physical’ or ‘create something non-physical’.
There’s one more common way to use make.
Part three: use make to mean ‘produce a
reaction in someone’.
You’ve seen how to use make for things,
but does it ever apply to people?
Look at an example:
Money makes me happy.
Can you understand why we use make here?
We use make when something causes an emotional
or physical reaction.
You can talk about physical reactions:
Thinking about what he said made me smile.
There’s too much dust and it is making me
sneeze.
…or emotional reactions:
The news made him angry.
It makes me sad to see you like this.
Okay, so now you’ve seen the most important
ways to use make.
Let’s review quickly.
You can use make: to talk about materials;
with food and drink; with nouns connected
to speaking and certain sounds; in some phrases
related to creating non-physical things (make
progress, make a mistake, etc.); with nouns
connected to money; and, when something causes
an emotional or physical reaction.
Alright, what about do?
Part four: use do to talk about activities
and work.
At the beginning, we said that we use do for
activities and tasks.
A common example is housework:
She usually does the laundry in the morning.
I’ll do the cooking if you do the washing
up.
We do our food shopping on Saturday mornings.
Most people don’t like doing this type of
work.
Do you like doing laundry, housework and homework?
Ah, remember: homework isn’t housework.
Good thing I mentioned it, though, because
we also use do in this way to talk about school
and studies:
I have to do a lot of homework every day.
What subjects are you going to do next year?
She’s going to do a film-making course.
Finally, we also use do with many tasks related
to business and work.
For example:
Please do your TPS reports by Monday morning.
Our firm does a lot of business in China.
How much more work do you have to do?
What connects of all these examples?
We use do for activities which are considered
work.
Of course, there are some exceptions.
For example, you can do a puzzle or do a crossword.
Crosswords are a great way to practise your
vocabulary and they’re great fun!
But you know sometimes, after doing lots of
work I feel like doing nothing and relaxing.
Hmm, what was that?
Part five: use do as a general verb.
Let’s look at another rule.
Do you remember what I just said at the end
of part four?
I said:
After doing lots of work, I feel like doing
nothing and relaxing.
You can use do to talk about activity in general.
Look at some more examples:
Look!
There’s a fire!
Do something!
Are you doing anything tomorrow?
She just wants to lie in bed and do nothing.
I’m tired of doing everything while you
sit around and watch TV!
This is common when you use do with the words
something, anything, nothing or everything.
Do here has a very general, basic meaning.
There’s one more way to use do with a general
meaning, but it’s slightly different.
Look at two examples and see if you can work
out what’s happening:
Can you put away your clothes?
I’ll do it later.
I’ll do the kitchen if you do the floors.
Can you see?
You can use do when the meaning of a verb
is obvious in the context.
So in the first example do replaces put away.
Can you put away your clothes?
I’ll do it later.
I’ll put away my clothes later.
In the second example, do replaces clean and
another verb, maybe sweep, vacuum or mop.
The exact meaning would be clear from the
context.
I’ll do the kitchen if you do the floors.
= I’ll clean the kitchen if you mop the
floors.
This is an informal way to use do.
So, let’s review.
We use do for: activities that are considered
work; activities in general, especially with
the words, something, anything, nothing and
everything; when the meaning of the verb is
obvious in the context.
Part six: test your skills!
Okay, so now you have some general rules to
help you to decide whether to use make or
do.
Are you ready to test yourself?
This will help you see how much you understand.
Remember you can always go back and look at
the rules again.
Complete the sentences.
How did you do?
If you didn’t get 100%, do the test again
the next time you’re studying and see if
your score improves.
You can find a longer quiz on the full version
of this free lesson, on our website: Oxford
Online English dot com.
You can find a link in the video description.
Thanks for watching!