Hello. I'm Oli. Welcome to Oxford Online English.
In this lesson, you can learn about dealing
with shyness or nervousness when you speak
English. Do you sometimes feel shy when you
speak English? Is it worse when you speak
to native speakers? Do these feelings of shyness
or nervousness stop you from practicing and
using your English? Yes? Yes? And yes? This
video could hopefully help you.
Shyness and nervousness are natural, but they
also make it more difficult to speak. If you
feel shy, you might not be able to think of
things to say, or you might not be able to
use grammar and vocabulary correctly. Some
English learners get stuck in a pattern where
they feel shy, and so they avoid using English
or speaking English. Now I can't promise to
solve all of your problems with shyness and
nervousness. But in this video, I'll share
some advice on how to deal with these feelings,
which I hope will be helpful.
Point one, remember that speaking is just
speaking. What do I mean? Well, when we first
hear foreign languages or meet foreigners,
they often sound very strange or interesting
or exotic to us. Oh, he's speaking French.
Wow! He must be saying something romantic,
or he must be talking about literature or
philosophy. I wish I could understand him.
Oh, wow! She's writing in Chinese. Those characters,
they're so beautiful. She must be writing
a poem. I wish I could understand what she's
writing.
Yeah, you know what? Maybe the French guy
is talking about philosophy. Maybe he's just
talking about how he got stuck in a traffic
jam. Maybe the Chinese girl is writing a poem
about misty mountains, or maybe it's just
a shopping list. If you think that foreign
languages and foreign people are something
strange or exotic, of course, you'll feel
more nervous when you're speaking. I think
many English learners have this idea. They
think, "Oh, I'm not talking to a person. I'm
talking to a native speaker."
But actually, speaking English isn't something
special. It's just speaking, like you do all
day, every day. All over the world, most of
what people talk about is quite simple, and
it's quite similar all over the world. Native
English speakers aren't different animals.
They're just normal people. They talk about
their work. They complain about their bosses.
They talk about movies they've seen. They
decide what they're going to have for lunch
and so on, just like anybody else. So don't
think that native speakers are some kind of
magical animal. They're not. If you want to
talk to them, talk to them. If you don't,
don't. It's not such a big deal either way.
What? Not a big deal? Really? Yeah, really.
You need to ask yourself, part two, "What's
the worst that could happen?" So you feel
really nervous about speaking English. One
day, you find the courage, you go and talk
to a teacher at your school, maybe a British
person or an American person. It goes horribly
badly. You feel really uncomfortable. You
can't think of anything to say. So you walk
away, and you think thoughts like, "I've embarrassed
myself. I feel like an idiot. Why is my English
so bad?" Here's a question though. What have
you actually lost? Nothing.
It's not a big deal. It's just a conversation.
The big deal is only in your head. You think
these thoughts. Nobody else. 10 years in the
future, are you still going to be thinking
and worrying about that time when, "Oh, I
tried to start a conversation, and it didn't
go very well."? No, of course not. Why not?
Because it's not that important. Maybe it
feels like a big deal. It feels important
at that moment, but it's not really important.
You haven't lost anything. You may feel embarrassed,
or you may feel stupid, but you're doing that
to yourself. There's no reason why. No one
else is telling you you're stupid. You aren't
risking anything, just by starting a conversation.
I guarantee the person you talk to is not
thinking these thoughts.
So what can you do about these feelings? How
can you control them? Well, let's look at
point three: wear a mask. These feelings of
nervousness or shyness are all inside. Here's
the best piece of advice I can give you. Just
because you feel nervous, you don't have to
act nervous. Let me tell you a story. Before
I started teaching, I was terrified of public
speaking. Even speaking in front of very small
groups made me feel very nervous and very,
very stressed.
The first lesson I ever taught was to a group
of maybe eight Russian teenagers, just a small
class. It was the most scared I've ever been
in my life. That's not an exaggeration. I
have quite seriously never felt so much fear.
I was shaking. I was sweating. I couldn't
remember anything about my lesson. I tried
to teach something about modal verbs. I don't
think anybody learned anything.
Afterwards, I thought, "How am I going to
do this?" My trainer gave me the same advice
I'm giving you. Act confident, even if you
don't feel confident. So I did. The first
few months, I still felt really nervous, but
I tried to hide it. After maybe a year, I
didn't feel so nervous. After a few years,
I could stand in front of 100 people and expect
their attention, even if I still felt a little
bit nervous inside. If it worked for me, it
can work for you. Sure, it takes time, and
it's not easy, but it's possible. So act confident.
Hold your head up. Chin up. Make eye contact,
even if it makes you uncomfortable. Control
the speed and the rhythm of your voice. Doing
these things is not so difficult, and it will
make you feel good because you're taking control
of your feelings, instead of letting your
feelings control you.
OK, you think, "Easy for you, Oli. You're
talking about speaking your own language.
We're talking about speaking a foreign language."
OK, let's talk about that. Point four: worrying
about your language makes your language worse.
Here's a question: when you hear a foreigner
speak your language, how do you decide if
this person is speaking well or badly? In
most cases, people notice your fluency and
your pronunciation. In speech, people don't
pay much attention to grammar and vocabulary
if your speech is easy to understand.
What does this mean? It means that if you
are embarrassed of your grammar or your vocabulary
when you're speaking English, you really shouldn't
be. First of all, worrying doesn't solve anything
anyway. If your grammar is bad, worrying about
your grammar will not make it better. The
only result is that you will feel bad. That's
it. Secondly, other people will really not
notice your grammar or vocabulary very much.
Most people don't care about these things,
most people who aren't English teachers. Even
English teachers care about these things at
work, and then they stop caring after work.
Trust me. If I've been teaching all day, and
you come and talk to me, I do not want to
think about your grammar or your vocabulary
problems. That's the last thing I want to
do at the end of the day. Most teachers I
know feel the same way. Most importantly,
worrying about your grammar and vocabulary
will affect your fluency. You'll speak slowly,
and you'll hesitate more if you're always
worrying about which verb form should I use
or what's the right word here.
So if you're just having a chat with someone,
don't think about your English too much. It
doesn't help. It doesn't make your English
better, and it doesn't make it easier to communicate.
Just talk. Try to communicate your ideas.
You'll sound more confident because you're
not hesitating and worrying about your language.
If you sound more confident, hopefully you'll
feel more confident too.
OK, let's review and put the things we've
talked about together. Part five, break the
habit sooner, not later. You can't help feeling
shy or nervous, but you can help how you respond
to these feelings. Very often, our responses
to our feelings are habits. They're habits
which are difficult to break, but not impossible.
Every time you want to talk to someone in
English, but you choose not to, you're feeding
your bad habits. Every time you think to yourself,
"My grammar sucks. I don't have anything interesting
to say," you're feeding these bad habits.
So go and talk to someone, even if it makes
you feel uncomfortable. The first time, it
might not go so well. That's okay. The 10th
time, it will be easier. The 100th time, it
will be much easier. You won't even remember
how difficult it was at the beginning. You
don't have anything interesting to say? Fine.
Say something boring. No one expects you to
be interesting all the time. No one's interesting
all the time. Just say something boring. End
the conversation. Most conversations are simple.
It doesn't matter that much what you say.
Worried about your grammar or your vocabulary?
Remember, no one else really cares that much.
Just focus on trying to communicate. Talk.
Express your ideas. When you're having a conversation
with someone, these things are much more important.
Most importantly, stop feeding bad habits.
Go talk to people, even if you're uncomfortable.
You'll learn quite quickly that feeling shy
or feeling nervous will only stop you speaking
English if you let it. OK, that's the end
of the lesson. I hope you found it useful.
You can see more of our free lessons on our
website, www.oxfordonlineenglish.com. That's
all. Thank you very much. See you next time.
Bye bye!