Hi I'm Martin. Welcome to Oxford Online English.
In today's lesson we're going to talk about
my favourite sport - football.
Even if you don't like football it's a great
idea to know a little bit of football vocabulary!
Why?
When I go to different countries, if I'm wearing
my football top, like this one, then more
people just start speaking to me. Talking
about football will make it easier for you
to start using your English and make new friends.
In this lesson, we’re going to go to a football
match. It’s an important game for me, and
I’m very excited. I hope you are, too! Ready?
Let’s go.
Let me take you to a game. We're going to
see my favourite team, Bournemouth. Their
nickname is the Cherries.
Bournemouth are great to watch because they
score a lot of goals! Unfortunately they let
in a lot of goals too.
It’s a bit of a rollercoaster ride for their
fans, but great for the neutral.
We're playing Swansea in the Premier League.
I'm really hopeful about this game because
the last time we played Swansea was the last
time we kept a clean sheet.
Also, we won our last game against West Ham,
so it's a chance for back to back victories.
Let’s take a look at some of the words I
just used.
This is a real rollercoaster ride. Rollercoasters
go up and down a lot.
When we are talking about sport, we use rollercoaster
ride to mean something that can make you very
happy one minute and then very sad the next
minute and then happy again.
Think of your emotions going up and down,
like they were on a rollercoaster ride.
Fan is another word for supporter. I support
Bournemouth. They are my team. I am a Bournemouth
fan.
A neutral is someone who does not support
either of the teams who are playing in a match.
If I watch Bournemouth play, of course I’ll
support my own team. If I watch two Italian
teams, I’ll be neutral. I don’t generally
mind who wins, and I just want to see a good
match.
When a team does not let in any goals in a
game, they have kept a clean sheet. Goalkeepers
like to keep a clean sheet, because it means
they’ve done their job very well.
If a team wins two games in a row, they have
won back to back victories.
If they win three or more in a row there are
several ways to say this.
You could say:
They’ve won three games in a row .
They’ve won three games on the bounce.
Okay, fingers crossed for back to back wins.
Let’s head to the match.
Here's the stadium; let's take a look inside.
As you can see there are four stands. You
used to be able to stand and watch the game
but nowadays everybody is supposed to sit.
Traditionally the home fans go behind this
goal…
…and the away fans go behind the other goal.
The two stands alongside the pitch are also
for the home fans. At Bournemouth they are
called the East Stand and the West Stand.
We’ll sit in the West Stand today as I have
season tickets. This means I have the same
two seats for every game. One for me and one
for you.
We can see the dugouts where the staff of
the two clubs will sit - the manager, his
assistant and the subs.
The manager chooses the team and the tactics
they will use, and is also responsible for
how they train and prepare.
11 players start a game and there are 7 more
who can be used later in the game.
These are the substitutes, or subs. The manager
can use a maximum of 3 of them.
When he takes a player off, he can send a
sub on.
Let’s talk about the tactics for this game!
I’ve lost count of how many times we’ve
hit the post and crossbar this season! If
we can just fire one in on target today, we’ll
score – they’ve got a dodgy keeper.
Bournemouth have to be careful in this game
because Swansea are very good from dead ball
situations such as corners and free kicks.
I think Eddie – that’s our manager - will
opt for a 4-4-2 formation today.
4-4-2 means four defenders, four midfielders,
and two forwards or strikers.
So there’ll be four defenders: two central
defenders and two wing-backs.
Then, four midfielders: two holding players
and two supporting the attack, plus two strikers
up front.
We’ll be looking to keep possession using
quick one-twos and triangles.
He likes the team to press up – we just
have to guard against getting caught on the
break.
Look, look there’s the ref and the players
coming out of the tunnel. Eddie Howe’s Barmy
Army. Cherries! Cherries!
Let’s take a look at some of the words I
just used.
The goalkeeper – or keeper – is supposed
to stop the opposition from scoring goals.
A dodgy keeper is one who is not very good.
We also use dodgy for other things, such as
cars that keep breaking down, or areas of
a city that are not very safe. Dodgy is a
conversational way to say bad.
A dead ball situation means that play has
stopped. For example, one player fouls another,
the referee will stop play and give the fouled
player’s team a free kick.
Some players are specialists at free kicks,
like Cristiano Ronaldo.
Corners are taken from the corner of the pitch.
The corner taker will usually put in a cross—a
pass which goes across the face of the goal.
The strikers will try to get to the cross
and score a goal.
Wing-backs play on the left or right side
of the defense.
Holding players are defensive midfielders.
They stay further back and protect the defenders.
Strikers play at the front. Their job is to
score goals.
When your team is in control of the ball,
they have possession. The other team must
try to win it back. We’ll be trying to keep
possession, which means we’ll try to keep
the ball as much as possible.A one-two means
that two players quickly pass the ball back
and forth. Player A passes to player B, who
returns it quickly to player A.
A triangle means three players form a triangle
shape and pass the ball around quickly.
Pressing up is an aggressive style of play.
It means we’re going to get into the other
team’s half. We won’t let their players
have time on the ball, even in their own half.
Sounds good, right? But there’s a problem:
if all of your players are attacking, you
might get caught on the break. The other team
counterattacks quickly, which is dangerous
because you don’t have many players at the
back.
Ref is a short form of referee. He is in charge
of the game.
The ref tosses the coin (demo it), our captain
calls heads – and it is heads. We’ll take
the kick off.
Well that’s the end of the first half. It
was a bit of a cagey affair to be honest,
but I’d say we just shaded it.
Let’s hope there’s more action in the
second half. 15 minutes to get a cuppa and
a pie – or do you fancy a quick one?
Right, the second half is underway.
The keeper rolls it out to our left back and
he sets off up the wing.
He plays a perfect 1-2 with a midfielder and
then some wonderful dribbling to beat two
players.
He lays it off to our centre forward, who
hears a shout of “man on” from one of
his team mates.
He puts in a slide rule pass to the other
striker, who fires it into the back of the
net. One-nil! The crowd go crazy!
Let’s take a look at some of the words I
just used:
Cagey means that both teams were playing very
carefully. Cagey games can be boring, because
both teams are trying not to lose, rather
than trying to win.
We just shaded it means that we were slightly
better than the other team. Maybe we created
more chances, or had more possession.
A cuppa means a cup of tea or coffee. A quick
one means a beer.
Dribbling means running past players whilst
keeping the ball at your feet. Lionel Messi
is probably the best dribbler currently playing.
He’s very good at running with the ball
and getting past opposition players.
If you’re dribbling and you get past an
opposition player, you beat them. If you say
he beat two players, that means he got past
two players who were trying to stop him.
If you lay the ball off you play a short pass,
usually with the ball going backwards or sideways.
If you’re playing football and you hear
someone shout man on, you need to pass the
ball or move quickly, because an opposing
player is coming to take the ball from you.
A slide rule pass is a very accurate pass
that goes between opposition players. Mesut
Ozil and Andreas Iniesta are well known for
their slide rule passes.
He fires it into the back of the net means
he scores a goal. If he fires it, it means
he hits the ball hard, so it was probably
a good goal. What am I saying? It was definitely
a good goal!
Bournemouth are controlling the game now.
That Swansea player has already been shown
the yellow card by the ref and he’s just
committed a very bad foul. What’s the ref
going to do?
It’s a 2nd yellow card – two yellows equals
one red and so he is sent off.
He has to leave the pitch. Swansea are down
to ten men.
Bournemouth score again, with a header!
[TEXT ONLY-DON’T READ [PART FIVE – VICTORY!]
There’s the final whistle. 2-0 and three
points to Bournemouth!
That pushes Swansea nearer relegation but
we’re mid table now. We should be safe—I’m
confident we’ll stay up and be in the Premiership
again next season.
Hopefully Brighton will get promoted; it would
be great to have a local derby next season.
At the end of the season, the bottom three
clubs are relegated from the Premiership down
to the Championship—one league lower than
the Premiership.
The bottom three teams go down. The other
teams stay up.
The top two clubs are promoted from the Championship
up to the Premiership.
The four teams in positions 3-6 play off for
the last promotion spot. Whichever team wins
the playoffs is the third team to be promoted
to the Premiership.
We say the promoted teams “go up”.
If Brighton are promoted, we’ll have a local
derby next season. A local derby is a match
against a team from the same city or a nearby
city. These teams are often fierce rivals—they
are very competitive with each other.
For example, if Real Madrid play Atletico
Madrid, that’s a local derby, because both
teams are from the same city.
Well, I hope you enjoyed the game.
Don’t forget to practice some of the words
you have learned – use them to make new
friends – or even when you are playing a
game yourself!
I’ve told you who my favourite team are
– so please tell me in the comments which
team you support!
And who do you think is the best player in
the world at dribbling? Who’s the best keeper
and the best striker?
That’s the end of the lesson. I hope you
enjoyed it! Don’t forget to check out more
of our free English lessons on our website:
Oxford Online English dot com.
See you next time!