Hi, I’m Johan.
Welcome to Oxford Online English!
In this lesson, you can learn something that
will help you to sound more like a native
speaker when you're talking.
What is this thing?
It’s vague language.
What does vague mean?
Vague means that something is not clear or
detailed.
For example, if you ask me what I did yesterday,
and I reply, “Just some stuff at home,”
that is a vague answer.
I’m not giving you any details.
Why does this matter?
Vague language is both common and important
in natural English.
It has many different uses, which you can
learn about in this video.
Using vague language will make your English
sound more natural and closer to native English.
First, let's look at the most important use
of vague language.
Part one: avoiding unnecessary detail.
In some situations, vagueness is bad.
For example, if you have a contract or a legal
document, it shouldn’t be vague!
In general, we prefer to avoid vagueness in
writing.
However, speaking is often the opposite.
Imagine that you ask your friend, “What
are you doing tomorrow?”
Look at two possible answers.
One: "First, I’m going into the city centre.
I need to buy a shirt and some toothpaste,
then at 10.30 I’m meeting William Bukowski
for coffee at the café on Gloucester Square."
"I’m going into town to buy some stuff,
then I’m meeting someone for a coffee."
Which answer sounds more natural?
The second one, right?
Can you explain why it sounds better?
In speaking, being too detailed can sound
very formal and unnatural.
It also wastes time: if I ask you a simple
question like, “What are you doing tomorrow,”
of course I don’t want to know every detail
of where you’re going, what time, who with,
and so on.
So what language can you use here?
The words 'thing' and 'stuff' are very useful.
The word 'thing' is very useful.
You can use 'thing' or 'things' to refer to
an object or objects.
For example:
"Give me that thing to clean the window."
"Don’t forget to take your things with you."
You can also use 'stuff' in a similar way.
Remember that 'stuff' is uncountable.
For example:
"We’re only going for two days, so we don’t
need much stuff."
Or: "Every time I move apartments, I throw
loads of stuff away."
Both words 'thing' and 'stuff' can also be
used to talk about things you have to do.
For example:
"I have to go to that thing tonight."
Or: "I have a lot of stuff to do next week."
We also often use vague language when talking
about numbers.
When talking about numbers or quantities,
you can avoid unnecessary detail by using
expressions like 'loads of', 'lots of', 'a
few', 'a couple', etc.
For example:
"They sent me 34 emails yesterday."
Or: "They sent me loads of emails yesterday."
"I saw six of my old school friends last night."
Or: "I saw a few of my old school friends
last night."
"I have to finish three more things, and then
we can go."
Or: "I have to finish a couple more things,
and then we can go."
In all of these cases, it’s more natural
to avoid giving the exact number unless the
number is somehow important.
Another way to use vague language is when
shortening a list.
Imagine that your friend just came back from
vacation, and you ask your friend, “What
did you do?”
Your friend says:
"We went swimming in the sea, sunbathed on
the beach, read books, ate in restaurants,
took a surfing lesson, visited different villages,
slept a lot, went for a bike ride and spent
one day relaxing."
This doesn’t sound good, right?
It sounds quite robotic, no?
In informal speech, we usually shorten long
lists by using a phrase on the end like: '…and
that kind of thing', '…and things like that',
'…and so on', '…or something like that'.
So, your friend might say:
"We went to the beach, did some sightseeing
and things like that."
Sounds more natural.
It’s also more polite in a way.
When you say something like this, you’re
giving some details but not every detail.
This shows that you are engaged in the conversation,
but it also shows that you understand that
the person you’re talking to probably doesn’t
want to hear every single detail.
Finally, it also allows the other person to
ask for more details if they’re actually
interested.
Instead of throwing information at someone,
you’re letting the other person choose where
to take the conversation.
Let’s look at some more examples of this:
"They serve curries, kebabs, grilled chicken
and that kind of thing."
"He told me about his new job, how his kids
are doing, and so on."
"We could go see a film, go for a walk or
something like that."
In all of these cases, we could continue the
list, but we don’t need to.
Using vague language to avoid unnecessary
details is a very common and important use,
but vague language also has other uses.
Let’s look:
Part two: using vague language to be indirect.
Imagine your friend comes to your home.
You notice your friend looks cold, so you
ask, “Shall I turn on the heater?”
Compare two answers:
"Yes, please.
It’s cold in here."
Or: "Yes, please.
It’s kind of cold in here."
What’s the difference?
The first answer sounds very direct, which
could be quite impolite.
It sounds a bit like a criticism.
By using the phrase 'kind of', the second
answer is vaguer and therefore more indirect.
This makes it softer and more polite.
You can use the phrases 'kind of' or 'sort
of' in this way.
For example:
"Can I have some milk?
The food’s kind of spicy."
Saying “The food is spicy” again sounds
very direct, and could sound rude.
"He sort of annoys me sometimes."
Of course this is a criticism of someone,
but using 'sort of' makes it softer.
"I kind of just want to stay in tonight."
Saying “I want to stay in tonight” sounds
very direct.
Adding 'kind of' and 'just' as well makes
it sound softer.
You might want to use this with times.
For example, you can use the words 'about'
or 'around' when arranging to meet someone,
especially if it’s just a casual meeting.
For example:
"Let’s meet at four."
More direct, could sound more like an order.
"Let’s meet at about four."
More indirect, sounds more like a suggestion.
"Can you get here at ten?"
More direct.
"Can you get here around ten?"
More indirect.
Of course, you don’t always want to use
vague language.
If your friend needs to be here by ten o’clock
at the latest, then you shouldn’t say "Can
you get here around ten?"
But in other cases, using vague language will
make you sound more indirect, friendlier and
generally more polite.
Part three:using vague language when you’ve
forgotten a word or a name.
Many English learners complain that they can’t
remember vocabulary.
Well, I have good news: you don’t always
need to!
No native speaker knows every word in English,
and native speakers also forget words all
the time.
So what can you do if you can’t remember
the word for something?
Vague language can be your friend!
Take a look:
"What does this thingy do?"
"You can use this little whatsit to take out
your SIM card."
Or: "I found a little metal thingamajig in
my desk drawer.
No idea where it came from."
Words like 'thingy' or 'whatsit' or 'thingamajig',
these are not normally used in written English.
You can use them whenever you’re speaking
if you don’t know what something is called.
You can also do this with people if you’ve
forgotten someone’s name.
For example:
"I’ve got a meeting with whatsisface from
the ad company tomorrow."
"He’s moving in with whatsername—you know,
that girl he met at his friend’s wedding."
'Whatsisface' is a word made from the question
“What is his face,” which makes no sense,
and it’s not really very clear where it
comes from.
'Whatsername' is easier to understand: it’s
made from the question “What is her name.”
You can change the words to talk about men
or women:
'Whatsisface'/'whatserface'
'Whatsisname'/'whatsername'
Again, these words cannot be used in written
English!
They are also very informal, so you really
shouldn’t use them unless you really know
the person you’re talking to well.
You should also never use these words directly
to someone’s face.
You can’t say:
"Hey, whatsisface!
Good to see you, but I’ve forgotten your
name."
That doesn't sound good at all!
Part four: using vague language to be rude.
Before, we saw how you can use vague language
to sound more indirect or polite.
But sometimes, you can also use vague language
to show that you don’t want to talk to someone.
For example, if you ask someone, “What did
you do at the weekend,” and the person answers
by saying, “Stuff,” this sounds rude.
This is like saying, “I don’t want to
tell you.”
Another example, if you ask your friend, “What
do you want to do tomorrow,” and your friend
says, “Whatever,” this also could sound
quite rude.
It’s like saying, “I don’t care what
we do.”
Generally, using vague language in a very
short answer—one or two words—can sound
rude.
It can sound like you don’t want to talk
to someone.
So, use vague language when you speak—but
remember that how you use it is important.
OK, that’s the end of the lesson.
I hope you learned some new stuff about…
whatchamacallit… vague language.
You can see more of our free English lessons
and other stuff like that on our website:
oxford online English dot com.
Thanks for watching, and see you next time!