Hello, I'm Oli. Welcome to Oxford Online English!
In this lesson, you can learn about how to
talk about your home in English. Where do
you live? What's your home like? What about
your neighbourhood? Talking about where you
live is a common conversation topic in English.
So it's good to have some things to say. Part
one: introducing where you live and talking
about types of home. Let's start with a simple
sentence. "I live in a..." what could you
put there? You could say, "I live in a house,"
"I live in an apartment." In Britain, people
sometimes say, "Flat." 'Flat' and 'apartment'
have the same meaning.
Next, let's add a bit more detail. What kind
of house or apartment is it? For example,
"I live in a small, two-stoery house in the
suburbs." When we say how many floors a building
has, we usually use the word storey, so you
can say a two-storey house, a four-storey
apartment building and so on. "I live in an
apartment on the third floor of a four-storey
building." There are many different kinds
of house and apartment. For example, do you
live in a terraced house, a semi-detached
house, or a detached house? Terraced houses
have other houses on both sides, a semi-detached
house has another house just on one side,
and a detached house stands by itself. Detached
houses are usually larger and more expensive.
Terraced houses are usually smaller and cheaper.
What kinds of houses are more common in your
country? What about apartments? Many apartments
are in apartment buildings. Easy enough, right?
If you live in a very tall apartment building
with many floors, you can say you live in
a high-rise in American English or a tower
block in British English. Sometimes a house
is divided into apartments, these are called
converted apartments. Apartments come in many
different sizes, if an apartment just has
one room which is a bedroom and living room
together, it's called a studio. Of course,
you can also have bigger apartments, a two-bedroom
apartment, a three-bedroom apartment and so
on. Large apartments might be duplex apartments,
this means the apartment has more than one
floor.
What about you? Where do you live? Do you
live in a house or an apartment? Could you
make a sentence using the vocabulary from
this section? For example, "I live in a two-story
terraced house." "I live in an apartment on
the 28th floor of a high-rise building." "I
live in a converted studio apartment." Next,
let's see how you can describe the inside
of your home in more detail. If you want to
describe your home, what can you talk about?
Well, you could start by saying what rooms
it has. For example, "My house has two bedrooms,
a kitchen, a living room, and a garden." It's
always better to add adjectives or details
to make your speaking more interesting. Let's
try: "My house has two small bedrooms, a kitchen
with a dining table, a living room with big
windows, and a small garden."
What other rooms might you have in your home?
You could have a dining room for people to
eat together. Maybe you have an office or
a study where you can work, if you live in
a warmer country, you might have a balcony
or a terrace where you can sit outside in
warmer weather. What about your home? What
does it have? Does your home have a garden,
a balcony, or another outdoor area? Try to
make a sentence describing your home. For
example, "I live in a two-bedroom apartment.
The bedrooms are quite small, but there's
a big living room with a dining area, a modern
kitchen, and also a small balcony where we
can sit outside in the summer." What can you
say about your home?
Okay, next, saying what you like or dislike.
So now you can hopefully describe your home
a little bit, but what about your opinion?
What do you like about your home, and what
would you change if you could? Positive words
you could use to describe your home include
'spacious', meaning large with lots of room;
'cosy' which means comfortable in a warm welcoming
way; 'light' describes a home which gets lot
of natural light. You can say your home is
'warm' or 'cool', meaning that it's comfortable
in winter or in summer. Finally, you can describe
your home as 'convenient', meaning it's close
to your job, it's close to the shops, it's
close to your children's school and so on.
You can use 'convenient' plus 'for.' For example,
"it's convenient for the subway," or "it's
convenient for my office." Could you use any
of these words to describe your home?
Okay, but what if you don't like your home?
Well, here are some words you could use: 'cramped'
means your home is too small, so you don't
have enough space. 'Dark' means your home
doesn't get enough light, so that even when
it's sunny outside, it's still dark inside.
'Drafty' means cold air comes inside through
the windows or through the doors in the winter.
'Stuffy' means there's not enough air so it's
very uncomfortable in hot weather. You could
say your home is 'noisy', for example if you
live near a main road, your home might be
noisy even at night.
Can you make a sentence about your home using
some of these words? For example, "My home
is light and spacious, but it can get very
drafty in the winter." "I like my apartment
because it's cosy, although it can be noisy
because there's a restaurant just downstairs."
Okay, so now you can talk about your home
and what you think of it. What else can you
say on this topic? Let's look, part four:
saying who you live with. Who do you live
with? Do live with your parents, your husband
or wife, with your family? Do you live by
yourself or do you live with flatmates (people
who you share a rented flat with)? Maybe you
live with friends.
Let's look at examples of what you could say
here. "I live with my parents." "I live in
a shared house; I have four flatmates." "I
live by myself." What about you? Okay, that
was easy. Let's look at one more topic you
can talk about. Part five: talking about your
neighbourhood. First, be careful with the
word 'neighbourhood'. A neighbourhood is not
a person; it's the area near your home. So
where is your home? Is it in the city centre,
the suburbs, or outside the city? If you live
outside the city, do you live on the outskirts
of the city, in a village, or in the middle
of nowhere?
How could you describe your neighbourhood?
Is it quiet or lively? Trendy or boring? Are
there many shops, cafes, bars, restaurants?
Are there parks or sports facilities? For
example, you could say, "I live in a very
lively area just south of the city center.
There are many cafes, shops, and places to
go." Or, "I live in a quiet area in the suburbs,
in the north of the city. It's a nice area
and it's quiet, but it's a bit boring. There
isn't really anything to do." What about you?
Can you say something about your neighborhood?
Okay, finally let's put everything together.
If you can use everything we've looked at
in this lesson, you should be able to speak
very clearly and with lots of details about
your home and where you live.
For example, "I live in a two-story terraced
house. It has two bedrooms, a living room,
a small kitchen, and a garden. It's cosy and
convenient for getting to work, but it's a
bit cramped, especially when we have guests.
I live with my wife and daughter. Our house
is near the city centre in a quiet neighborhood.
There isn't much to do, but there are some
small shops and a park where we go if the
weather's nice."
Here's one more sample answer: "I live by
myself in a studio apartment. It just has
one main room with a tiny kitchen. It's very
warm in winter, but it can get a bit stuffy
in summer. I live in the city center, very
close to everything. It's very lively, with
lots of bars and restaurants. It's a good
place for young people to live, but not many
families choose to live here."
What about you? Can you make an answer like
this talking about where you live? Try to
use as much language from the lesson as you
can. Okay, that's the end of the lesson. Thanks
very much for watching. You can see more of
our free English lessons on our website, oxfordonlineenglish.com,
but that's all. Thanks again. I'll see you
next time. Bye-bye!