Hello, I’m Mia.
Welcome to Oxford Online English!
In this lesson, you can learn how to talk
about relationships in English.
How can a wingman help you talk to people
you like?
If someone leads you on, should you be happy
or annoyed?
And what does it mean if someone tells you,
“I’m out of your league?”
In this lesson, you can learn what all of
these words and expressions mean and more.
Let’s get started.
Part 1: having a crush.
Imagine you’re single but you don’t want
to be.
You wish you were in a relationship, perhaps
you’ve got a crush on someone.
Having a crush means that you like someone
romantically.
So if there is someone you find attractive
or you like their personality, you could say
you have a crush on them.
You might also use the word 'like'.
From the context, or your tone of voice, people
would understand that you mean ‘like romantically’
and not ‘like as a friend’.
Perhaps you want to speak to this person,
but you’re too shy to do it alone.
You need a wingman.
A wingman is a person that helps you meet
attractive people and start talking to them.
Your wingman is usually a friend you can trust
to make you look good in front of someone
you like.
Your wingman can be a man or a woman!
For example, they will tell your crush interesting
things about you or encourage them to chat
to you.
They might talk to the other person’s friends
so that you can have time talking to the person
you like one-to-one.
Now, imagine you’re in a bar with your crush.
You’re chatting to them and giving them
compliments, maybe making them laugh.
We would say you’re flirting with them.
This means that you’re talking in a playful
way, which shows that you’re interested
in them.
For example, if you offer to buy your crush
a drink or dance with them or tell them they
look nice, you could say you’re flirting
with them.
But what if they don’t seem to return your
feelings?
Maybe they think you’re leading them on.
If you lead someone on, you’re not really
interested in them, you’re only interested
in the attention you receive from them.
For example, if someone dances with you and
enjoys flirting with you, but they don’t
like you romantically; they’re leading you
on because they only enjoy the attention they’re
receiving.
They’re not really interested in you.
Or, maybe they’re already taken!
If you’re taken, it means that you’re
already in a relationship with somebody else.
However, perhaps they’re just playing hard
to get.
This means that they’re acting like they
don’t like you because they want to make
you more interested.
They don’t want your job to be easy!
Let’s review:
If you have a crush on someone, you like them
romantically.
Maybe you’d want a wingman to make you look
good in front of them.
When you make your intentions clear, you’re
flirting with your crush.
If they’re playing hard to get, they may
seem like they’re not interested even if
they like you.
If they’re leading you on, they’re only
interested in attention from you and if they’re
taken, they’re already in a relationship
and it’s best to find a new crush!
Part 2: dating.
Okay, let’s imagine that your wingman was
great and you got the courage to talk to your
crush.
Things were going well so you decided to ask
them out.
If you ask someone out, it means that you’re
inviting them to go on a date with you.
Usually this will be some romantic activity
like seeing a film together, or having a meal
at a nice restaurant.
Now imagine your crush said yes, and now you’re
dating, or going out with them.
If you’re dating or going out with someone,
it means that you’re meeting regularly to
do activities together as a couple, for example,
going dancing or out to a bar or restaurant.
You can use the phrase 'seeing someone' to
mean the same thing.
Going out with someone, dating and seeing
someone all have the same purpose: you want
to see if you like each other and if you’re
well suited to be in a relationship together.
Now imagine you’re on a date in an Italian
restaurant.
There’s nice music playing and candles on
the table, it’s all very romantic!
You and your crush have been flirting and
you find out that you have good chemistry
together.
Chemistry is the feeling you get between yourself
and another person.
It can be negative, but when we’re talking
about having chemistry in a romantic relationship,
it’s positive and means you feel a connection
with the other person, and you’re excited
to spend time with them.
If you want to say that you get on well with
your crush, you can say that you click with
them.
We use the expression 'click with someone'
to say that we are compatible with someone
and that you understand each other well.
For example, if you and your date have similar
interests and lots to talk about together,
you can say you click with them.
Let’s review:
If you ask someone out, you are inviting them
to go on a date with you.
Seeing someone or going out with someone are
other ways to say you’re dating someone—you’re
romantically spending time with them.
If you have good chemistry with your date,
you have a good emotional connection with
them.
And when you click with someone, you get on
with them well and have a good relationship
with them.
Part 3: Head over heels in love.
Imagine that you’ve been on a few dates
and spent a lot of time together.
Now, you’re in a more serious relationship.
It wasn’t love at first sight but now you’re
head over heels in love with your new boyfriend
or girlfriend and you couldn’t be happier!
You feel like you’re made for each other
and you want to spend every minute together.
Love at first sight is an instant attraction
to someone.
For example, if you watch romantic movies
or read romantic books, you often see examples
of love of first sight.
Two people have an instant attraction to each
other and immediately like each other romantically.
Head over heels in love is an expression that
means you’re deeply in love with someone.
If you’re head over heels in love with your
boyfriend or girlfriend, you love them very
much!
If you use the expression made for each other
to talk about your boyfriend or girlfriend,
it means that you are perfectly suited for
each other.
For example, you could say you’re made for
each other because you’re very compatible
and love spending time together.
Now imagine that your friends and family are
so used to seeing you and your boyfriend or
girlfriend together that they start calling
him or her your partner.
In this instance, a partner is someone you’re
in a serious relationship with, usually either
living with or married to.
For example, you can call your wife or husband
your partner, or, if you’re in a serious
relationship with your girlfriend or boyfriend,
you can call them your partner, too.
You can also call your boyfriend or girlfriend
your other half.
This uses the idea that you and your boyfriend
or girlfriend are one complete unit together.
You make one whole together, so separately
you are only half.
You can call your boyfriend or girlfriend
your other half to say that they are the other
half of you.
If you want to be complimentary to your partner,
you can also call them your better half.
Let’s review:
Head over heels in love means that you love
your boyfriend or girlfriend very much.
Love at first sight is when you have an instant
attraction to someone, and when you’re made
for each other, it means you are very well
suited.
If you’re in a serious relationship—living
together or married, you can call your husband
or wife your partner.
You can also call your boyfriend or girlfriend
your other half, meaning you make one complete
unit together.
If you want to be extra nice, you can call
them your better half.
Part 4: Problems in paradise.
You think things are going really well with
your other half—you have good chemistry
and you’re head over heels in love with
them.
Then one day, you go to meet them at the cinema,
but they’re not there!
What’s happened?
Things were going so well…
You ring them but they tell you that they’re
not coming.
You have been stood up.
If you’ve been stood up, it means that you
have gone somewhere for a date, but your date
didn’t come.
For example, if you go to a restaurant but
you eat by yourself because your date never
appeared, you’ve been stood up.
You are confused about what this means, but
you ask your boyfriend or girlfriend out for
another date.
Then they turn you down.
If you turn someone down, it means that you
don’t want to go on a date with them.
For example, if you ask someone to have a
coffee with you and they say no, you have
been turned down.
Being turned down might make you feel rejected—you
feel that the other person doesn’t want
to be with you or spend time with you.
You’re getting a bit frustrated now—you
thought everything was going well with you
and your other half!
But they tell you that they didn’t feel
the same way.
They accuse you of seeing your relationship
through rose-tinted glasses and tell you that
they’re out of your league.
If you see something or someone through rose-tinted
glasses, it means that you only see the good
side of something.
You don’t notice anything that might be
wrong.
For example, if you see your boyfriend or
girlfriend through rose-tinted glasses, you
think they’re completely perfect and can’t
see anything bad about them.
You don’t notice their annoying habits or
the negative side of their personality.
If someone is out of your league, it means
they are too good for you.
For example, if your crush says that he or
she is out of your league, they think that
you aren’t good enough for them.
It’s not a nice thing to say to someone!
Imagine you’re still on the phone, you’re
getting a bit angry now, but before you can
say anything, your girlfriend or boyfriend
dumps you!
They have broken your heart and left you single
again.
If someone has decided that they don’t want
to be in a romantic relationship with you
anymore, they have dumped you.
This means that they have ended their relationship
with you.
You could also say that they have broken up
with you or ended things with you.
These phrases all mean the same thing.
If things were more serious and you loved
the other person, we would say they have broken
your heart.
This means that you were in love when they
ended their relationship with you and it has
left you very upset and hurt.
Let’s review:
If you’ve been stood up, it means that your
date isn’t coming and hasn’t told you.
If you don’t want to go on a date with somebody,
you would turn them down.
Being turned down might make you feel rejected
and unwanted.
If you’re seeing your relationship through
rose-tinted glasses, you’re seeing it as
perfect but not realistically.
If you’re out of someone’s league, it
means that you’re too good for them, and
if you don’t want to be in a relationship
anymore, you can dump your boyfriend or girlfriend.
You could also say that you broke up, or that
you decided to end things.
But be careful!
If they’re in love with you, you might break
their heart.
Now we’ve reached the end of our lesson.
I hope you’re not too heartbroken!
Now you should be able to talk about and understand
all the stages of a relationship using different
words and expressions.
Thanks very much for watching!
I hope that you have found it useful.
You can see more of our free lessons on our
website: oxfordonlineenglish.com.
See you next time!