Hi there!
I’m Johan from Oxford Online English.
Do you love cinema?
Or do you just want to find some topics to
talk about in English?
Either way this will be a fantastic lesson
for you, because we’re going to look at
how to have interesting conversations about
film and cinema in English.
We’ll look at how to talk about films in
general, and you can also learn vocabulary
to talk about different kinds of films in
English.
But first…
Part one: how to talk about your favourite
film.
The easiest way to start talking about films
is to ask:
"What is your favourite film?"
I can tell you about myself.
My favourite film is Apocalypse Now.
If you were talking to me, you could follow
this question by asking: "Why do you like
it?"
For me, I like this film because it has an
interesting plot.
It also has great cinematography and some
amazing performances.
Plot is another word for story.
Cinematography refers to the imagery of the
film—how it looks and how it was shot.
Apocalypse Now has great cinematography because
it has many beautiful, shocking and memorable
scenes, which I’ll always remember.
Performance means how an actor acts.
You can say things like:
"Edward Norton’s performance in Fight Club
was surely one of the best of his career."
"Steven Spielberg always gets good performances
out of his actors."
What else can I say about this film?
If you haven’t seen it, or you don’t know
what it is, I could give you some more basic
information, such as:
It’s a war film.
It’s set in Vietnam during the war.
It was directed by Francis Ford Coppola.
It’s based on a book by Joseph Conrad.
What about your favourite film?
You could use these sentences to talk about
it:
It’s a something film.
It’s set in...
It was directed by...
It’s based on...
What else can you say about your favourite
film?
Can you make one or two sentences to explain
why you like it?
Pause the video and practice if you want.
Next, do you know what the word for a style
of film is?
We use the word genre.
It’s pronounced with a /ʒ/ sound which
sounds like the ‘s’ in television.
You can also talk about types of films or
kinds of films.
The meaning is the same.
What genres of film do you like or dislike?
Next, you’re going to learn how to talk
about different types of films in more detail.
Shall we begin with some feel-good films?
Part two: feel-good films: comedies, musicals
and animations.
Who’s this?
This is Charlie Chaplain, one of the first
producers of comedy films.
His style is called slapstick and this means
that silly things happen to him, like slipping
on a banana.
Slapstick is usually simple, physical comedy.
Some other famous comedies are Ace Ventura:
Pet Detective, The Hangover or Monty Python
and the Holy Grail.
These are different types of comedy.
The Hangover is more of a gross-out comedy.
Its jokes are based on disgusting ideas or
images.
Monty Python is a famous surreal comedy.
It’s surreal because its humour is based
on strange situations and weird jokes.
If you laughed or enjoyed the film you would
say the film is funny or amusing.
If you laughed a lot you could say something
like:
"The Hangover was hilarious."
You could also describe how much you laughed.
For example, you could say:
"I’ve never laughed so much!"
"I was on the floor laughing."
Or,
"I laughed till I cried."
Another feel-good genre is musicals.
What do you think this means?
As you can imagine, these films have a lot
of singing.
Some famous examples are Singing in the Rain,
High School Musical and The Sound of Music.
If a musical had memorable songs you could
use the word catchy to describe them:
"The songs in The Sound of Music were very
catchy."
This means that the songs get into your head,
so you might find yourself singing the songs
to yourself days or weeks later.
Musicals should also have good dance scenes,
where all the cast dance together.
Dance scenes need good choreography—this
is how the dance scenes are planned.
"I love Moulin Rouge for many reasons, but
I particularly like the choreography."
Many films have soundtracks—songs which
are used within the film.
For a musical, the soundtrack is obviously
important.
Often, you can buy the soundtracks to famous
films.
"She’s been listening to the Frozen soundtrack
non-stop for weeks now."
Have you seen Frozen?
It’s a musical, but it’s also an animation.
These films are made by animators – people
who draw or use graphics to create the film.
Think of films like The Lion King, Shrek or
Ice Age.
These films are often made just for children,
but they often have stories that both adults
and children will enjoy.
Modern animations like Ice Age are made largely
using computer imagery, but traditional animations
were hand-drawn.
"I prefer older animated films.
I think the hand-drawn style creates a nicer
feel."
Many of these feel-good films are sentimental.
They make you feel emotional, or maybe they
even make you cry.
I never cry during films, though, honest!
If a film makes you feel strong emotions,
you can describe it as moving.
This brings us to our next topic.
Part three: moving films: romance, dramas
and epics.
When was the last time you saw a moving film.
Was it a romance or perhaps a drama?
Often, romance films follow a simple structure:
boy meets girl, boy loses girl, boy gets girl.
What language can we use to describe these
types of films?
If it made you cry you can say that it brought
you to tears or that you cried all the way
through:
"Titanic was a moving film; it brought me
to tears."
Or, you could say:
"I cried all the way through Titanic; romantic
films always make me emotional."
We can also talk about the chemistry between
the two characters.
This means that you can feel the passion between
the two main actors.
"There was so much chemistry between Leonardo
Dicaprio and Kate Winslet."
Titanic is also an example of a drama.
A drama is a film where the characters are
realistic.
The story focuses on their relationships and
problems.
Some other famous examples of dramas are The
Godfather or The Shawshank Redemption.
Drama is a very broad genre.
Dramas can be positive and uplifting like
The Shawshank Redemption, which has a happy,
optimistic message, but some dramas can be
dark and bleak, like Twelve Years a Slave,
which deals with more unpleasant and negative
themes.
Maybe the film really made you think about
life.
Sometimes the film has an open ending.
In these cases you would say that the film
was thought-provoking or you could say that
it left you thinking.
"The Shawshank Redemption left me thinking."
Or:
"Citizen Kane was thought-provoking."
Some dramas are based on true stories or real
historical events.
For example, Lawrence of Arabia is a historical
drama about real people and events.
Have you seen it?
It’s nearly four hours long!
This makes it an epic.
Epics are films which have very big, broad
stories.
Epics often have different characters and
sub-plots.
Do you remember what plot means?
Then you should be able to guess the meaning
of a sub-plot.
A sub-plot is a mini-story, maybe involving
minor characters.
For example, the main plot of a film might
be about the hero’s battle against evil,
while there is also a sub-plot about his or
her love interest.
Epic films often have many sub-plots, which
can make them very long.
Most epics are over two hours long.
Some other famous epics are Ben Hur, Braveheart
or Gangs of New York.
Epics are usually big-budget films: they cost
a lot to make.
"The budget for Ben Hur must have been huge."
Some epics, like Braveheart, contain a lot
of exciting action scenes.
This brings us to…
Part four: exciting films: horror, sci-fi
and action.
Some films try to scare you: these are horror
films.
Who is this?
For most people it’s Frankenstein but technically
it is Frankenstein’s monster.
There are many other scary films such as Nightmare
on Elm Street, The Exorcist or Jaws.
Some people don’t watch horrors because
it gives them nightmares.
Do you watch them?
Good horror films should be terrifying or
even petrifying.
Petrifying means that something is so scary
that you can’t even move.
"The Ring was petrifying.
I was too scared even to go upstairs by myself
after I saw it."
You can also say that the film will give you
nightmares.
"Jaws is a terrifying film; it really gave
me nightmares."
Some horror films use a lot of violence and
blood to scare you, but others depend on atmosphere.
These horror films are spooky or creepy.
They scare you by creating a sense of the
unknown.
"The Blair Witch Project was so spooky.
I couldn’t sleep for a week!"
What about this famous horror film?
This is an alien from the film Alien.
This film is a horror film, but it’s also
sci-fi.
Do you know what sci-fi stands for?
It stands for science fiction.
Sci-fi films show us futuristic scenarios,
often with advanced technologies like teleporters
or faster-than-light travel.
Many sci-fi films are set on other planets,
or even in outer space.
For example, Alien was set on a spaceship.
This means that sci-fi films often use a lot
of special effects.
"The special effects in the original Star
Wars were very advanced for when it was made."
Special effects can be created using models
or computer graphics.
Special effects which are made using computers
are often called CGI—computer-generated
imagery.
"When a film uses too much CGI, it stops being
believable."
Have you seen The Matrix?
This film was famous for its CGI.
It used a lot of techniques that hadn’t
really been used before.
The Matrix is another film which fits into
two genres: it’s sci-fi, but it’s also
an action film.
Action films are typically full of fights,
guns, car chases and explosions.
This looks like a scene from an action film.
James Bond, Indiana Jones and the Matrix films
are examples of action films.
Quite often these films have stunts in them.
For example, the hero might have to jump out
of a moving car, or fight someone on the roof
of a moving train.
Which do you prefer: films with real stunts,
or CGI?
Probably real stunts, right?
However, action films aren’t the only exciting
film genre…
Part five: mystery films: thrillers and crime.
Some films really hold your attention all
the way through.
You don’t know what’s going to happen,
and this can make you feel excited or nervous.
These films are thrillers.
The Usual Suspects is an example of a thriller.
Director Alfred Hitchcock is famous for his
thrillers, including the classic film Psycho.
Thrillers are suspenseful—they make you
feel excited or nervous because you aren’t
sure what's going to happen next.
In a good thriller, the suspense will keep
you on the edge of your seat.
"The Silence of the Lambs kept me on the edge
of my seat all the way through."
A good thriller is also gripping.
You can’t stop watching because you want
to see what’s going to happen.
"The Usual Suspects is a gripping film with
a brilliant twist."
What’s a twist?
Many thrillers have a twist—a very surprising
change of direction.
A good twist is unpredictable.
For example, you could say:
"I really didn’t see the twist coming in
Memento."
For a bad thriller, you might say,
"I saw the twist coming a mile away.
Boring!"
Many thrillers and exciting films are also
crime films.
Crime films can be detective stories, where
detectives try to solve a mystery, or they
can be stories about criminals.
Like thrillers, crime films should be gripping
and suspenseful.
Many crime films are also quite violent.
If a film has a lot of violence, you can describe
it as brutal.
"Scarface has some pretty brutal scenes."
If a film is so violent that it’s difficult
to watch, you might describe it as gruesome.
"I couldn’t get to the end of Reservoir
Dogs.
It was just too gruesome."
The best crime films need a good villain.
The villain is the opposite of the hero.
The villain in a crime film is often the number
one criminal, the bad guy.
"No Country for Old Men surely has one of
the best villains of any film."
However, sometimes the bad guy is the hero
of the film.
In this case, you can describe the main character
as an antihero.
In a good crime film, you’ll sympathize
with the antihero, even though they’re a
criminal.
"Leon is a great film.
Even though he’s a professional killer,
you see his human side."
So now you should be able to talk about films
you like and discuss many different kinds
of film in English.
There’s a lot of vocabulary in this lesson.
Can you remember some of the new words you’ve
heard?
For example, what does bleak mean?
What kind of film can be described as hilarious?
What does a suspenseful film do to you?
Don’t worry if you can’t remember everything!
You can always watch the video again to review
the vocabulary.
You can also read the full script on our website.
There’s also a quiz, so you can test your
film vocabulary!
That’s all from me.
What’s your favourite film?
What film genres do you like/dislike, and
why?
You can let us know in the comments below.
For more of our free English lessons please
visit: Oxford Online English dot com.
See you next time.