Hello, I’m Mia.
Welcome to Oxford Online English!
In this lesson, you can learn how to use auxiliary
verbs for emphasis.
"I like chocolate;" "I do like chocolate."
Do you know the difference between these two
sentences?
In the second sentence--"I do like chocolate"--we
use the auxiliary verb 'do' to add emphasis.
Emphasis means making your idea stronger or
clearer.
Would you like to learn how to do this?
In this lesson, you will learn how to use
auxiliary verbs (like 'do' or 'will') to add
emphasis to the things you say in English.
Part one: using auxiliaries for emphasis.
Look at the following examples:
"I like going swimming."
"I do like going swimming."
The first example tells us that you like swimming.
In the second example, it stresses that you
really like going swimming, it is emphasised.
If we want to emphasise something in English,
we can use auxiliary verbs to do this.
Here’s another example:
"Did you phone Jack?"
"Yes, I phoned Jack."
"Yes, I did phone Jack."
Can you tell the difference now?
When I say, “I did phone Jack,” the use
of 'did' makes the point stronger.
In this lesson, we’ll learn how and when
to use auxiliaries; don’t worry, this grammar
is very easy to learn and use—you’ll be
using it like a native in no time!
Part two: when to emphasise something.
Okay, now let’s look at when you might use
an auxiliary verb to add emphasis.
We use auxiliaries for emphasis when we feel
strongly about something and want to show
this.
Look at the following examples:
"I am sorry."
"I do not like your cake."
"I would like to dance."
All of these examples tell us that you feel
very strongly about what you’re saying.
We often use auxiliaries like this to correct
what somebody else says.
Have a look at this example:
"Why don’t you like pizza?"
"But I do like pizza!"
The first person wrongly thinks that the second
person doesn’t like pizza.
The second person uses the auxiliary verb
with emphasis to correct their mistake.
Here’s another example:
"You haven’t cleaned the kitchen."
"I have cleaned the kitchen."
Again, the second person adds emphasis to
the auxiliary 'have' to correct the first
person’s mistake.
Another way to use auxiliary verbs is to contrast
two different ideas or things.
Have a look:
"I can’t play football, but I can play basketball."
"I didn’t have a good time at the cinema,
but I did enjoy the restaurant."
"I don’t like cakes, but I do like chocolate."
All of these examples look at two different
things and use the auxiliary (with emphasis)
to contrast them.
Part three: how to use auxiliaries.
Now that you’ve seen when you should use
auxiliaries for emphasis, let’s look at
how to use them in more detail.
If you want to emphasise something in the
present simple or past simple tenses, add
the auxiliary verbs 'do', 'does' or 'did',
without changing the main verb.
Look at these examples:
"I work;" "I do work."
"I worked;" "I did work."
It works the same way when we’re talking
about other people; for example:
"She cleans;" "She does clean."
"She tidied up;" "She did tidy up."
In the negative form, we would stress the
negative part of the auxiliary:
"She did not tidy up."
"I do not want to visit her."
Remember: it’s important not to contract
the words, as this does not have the same
effect!
You can’t emphasise a negative like this:
"I don’t want to talk to him."
You need to use the full form, and emphasise
the word 'not', like this:
"I do not want to talk to him."
Now, let’s see how to use the auxiliary
for emphasis in other verb tenses.
In other tenses, there is already an auxiliary
verb, so you don’t need to add anything.
You just need to pronounce the auxiliary verb
with stress, to show emphasis.
In continuous tenses, we would stress the
verb 'to be'.
Don’t use contractions if you want to emphasise
the auxiliary verb; use the full form.
Here are some examples:
"I am going to phone her!"
"He is coming tomorrow."
"We are running in the race!"
What about perfect tenses?
The idea is similar.
Stress the verbs 'have', 'has' or 'had' to
make your point.
For example:
"I have emptied the dishwasher."
"I had bought her a present."
"She has visited me."
You can do the same with any modal verb ('will',
'would', 'must', 'should', etc.)—I did tell
you it would be easy grammar, didn’t I?
Take a look at these examples:
"I can sing, listen!"
"Must you be so loud?"
"You cannot believe that!"
Part four: review.
Okay, let’s review:
You can use auxiliary verbs for emphasis to:
show that you feel strongly about something;
correct something wrong that someone else
said; contrast two different ideas.
In the present simple and past simple tenses,
you need to add an auxiliary verb ('do'/'does'/'did')
if you want to emphasise the idea.
With other verb tenses or modal verbs, there’s
already an auxiliary, so you just pronounce
the auxiliary with stress to add emphasis
to the idea.
Remember not to use contractions!
To add emphasis, you need to use the full
form.
That’s the end of the lesson.
I do appreciate your time; thanks for watching!
I hope that you learned something new in this
class.
You can see more of our free lessons on our
website: Oxford Online English dot com.
See you next time!