[Music]
tales with GG presents the gingerbread
man a long long time ago an old woman
and an old man lived a quiet life in a
small cottage by the river one day the
woman decided to make a gingerbread man
for them to eat she mixed flour butter
and eggs in a bowl and then she rolled
out the dough carefully she then cut out
a lovely gingerbread man and gave him
blueberries for his eyes and buttons and
icing for his mouth and clothes the
woman put him in the oven to bake soon
enough he was ready and the woman opened
the oven door but to her surprise the
gingerbread man jumped out of it don't
eat me he shouted in terror and ran out
of the window the woman and the man
started chasing after him stop stop they
shouted but he was faster than they were
run run as fast as you can you can't
catch me I'm the gingerbread man he
laughed and kept running as he was
running he came across a pig the pig
tried to take a bite out of him but once
again the gingerbread men was faster run
run as fast as you can you can't catch
me I'm the gingerbread man he said and
carried on running the pig joined the
chase and now the old woman the old man
and the pig were running after him but
the gingerbread man was faster further
along the path he came to a cow
stop called the cow I want to eat you
but the gingerbread man started running
again and the cow couldn't catch him run
run as fast as you can you can't catch
me I'm the gingerbread man he said it
was not long before the gingerbread man
came across a horse stall up little man
I want to eat you the horse said but the
gingerbread man outran him to run run as
fast as you can you can't catch me I'm
the gingerbread man the horse joined the
old woman the old man and the pig but
the gingerbread man only laughed at them
he kept laughing until he reached the
river banks oh no now they will get me
and eat me if only I could cross the
river he thought suddenly a fox snuck up
to him please don't eat me cried the
gingerbread man I won't eat you
the Fox promised I just want to help you
jump on my back and I will swim across
the river and you will be saved the
gingerbread man had no other choice
he jumped on the fox's back and they
crossed the river easily and safely as
soon as they stepped onto dry ground the
gingerbread man thanked the Fox but a
second later the Fox opened his mouth
and gobbled up the gingerbread man did
you like this story download our story
telling up tales with Gigi where you can
find more than thirty other fairy tales
and fables which can come in handy
during feeding time bedtime or on road
trips and don't forget to subscribe to
our Channel we've got new tales coming
out every Wednesday