Previously, on Continuum.
We need to work together
because I'm the guy holding
your golden ticket.
What happens with you?
You made your choice.
You chose you.
I'm reprogramming it.
Will it work?
That's the question
I'm afraid to ask myself.
Somewhere in time the traveller
changed something.
His future ceased to exist.
A moment is coming.
A chance to repair everything.
Brad's here, I think he's here for the key.
Nothing personal, but I've got a deadline.
Give me Kellogg!
I'll come for you.
The plan moves ahead.
I promise.
Time's up.
Nora gave us approval to hit them hard.
We've got eyes on the building
but they haven't made a move.
They won't.
They can't.
When's your team going in?
Well, we're gearing up now.
I know I can't stop you.
I don't want to.
But I need to ask one last favour.
Please, give me a head-start
before you launch your assault.
What are you doing?
Making a tsunami.
Don't worry about it.
Ok. I won't.
Time to go.
That has multiple meanings at this point.
Those officers,
Travis, they died trying to prevent
what Kellogg's army is about to do.
The least we can do is finish the job.
You know, even if I figured
out a way to send you
forward in time, I'm still
not entirely sure
which future I'll be sending you to.
Odds are it'll be
linked to Kellogg's dark future
which, if we don't stop him now,
it'll be a very nasty place in 60 years.
But if there's even the slightest chance
that I can be with Sam again,
I'm willing to risk everything.
Ok.
Let's go risk everything.
I just hope it's not too late.
This cost us two good marines.
It cost a lot more than that.
Once we send the pulse
signal to our future and tether,
we will be locked.
When that happens you only
have 90 minutes to get
everyone through before the
tether degrades completely.
Is that gonna be enough?
There's only one way to find out.
Do it.
Tether is locked, the clock's running.
Open the portal.
Turn it off!
What the hell happened, Zorin?
I don't know,
I... what happened?
The key's been shorted.
Fix it, now.
The tether is holding,
the clock is still running.
Grimes, I'm sorry.
Sorry?
I just lost good men.
Men you'll miss unless we
get this portal back online.
Where's Marcellus?
He didn't make it.
Are you kidding me?
We need to get this portal
open again quickly
or the only thing coming
through will be the enemy.
It's for the best.
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
I guess we're eating in tonight.
You know, when I
first came to this timeline,
I thought that having
it all was within my grasp.
But when I really thought about it,
not having something to fight for...
someone to fight for...
well, it all seems just
a little... unsatisfying.
I'm guessing the other me, the future me,
he found something or someone
worth fighting for.
Well, based on the shaking
floors and walls,
I'm guessing you fired up your machine.
Yes, we did.
So uh... that's it, I guess
we're all done here.
Not yet.
We're having a small problem
with one of our key components.
You wouldn't happen to know if uh...
Cameron or Sadler sabotaged it?
I wouldn't put it past them.
Hmm.
Are you doing alright, sir?
Well, you know, while I
certainly appreciate the degree
to which you made efforts to get
me out of the police station,
I just can't help but feel I
moved from one cell to another.
This is for your safety.
You mean me, or other me?
At this point, what happens
to you happens to him.
Our times are tethered now,
which means any changes in this moment
would ripple into our future.
Your safety is paramount.
Hey, well I feel better already.
So when geriatric me arrives,
what happens to me, me?
What with the whole
kidney failure situation
and everything.
You were very specific.
Before we left you issued strict protocols
regarding how to deal with you.
You were to be treated in a manner
befitting your importance.
But that's a sliding scale, isn't it?
Important now, liability later.
It's not like that.
Let's say he decides to come here.
Our times are linked by
that machine out there.
That means no new timeline.
That means a paradox.
I have a little experience with paradoxes,
I lost my grandmother to one in 2012.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Has anyone ever told you
that you're a terrible liar?
You got your head start.
I'll be 30 minutes behind you.
Thank you.
You know, as much as you've
screwed up my life and my job
and, well, my understanding of everything,
I hate to admit it but I
wouldn't change a damn thing.
You reminded me of what's important.
What being a protector really means.
There's a lot to fix
in this time, you know.
You could stay and we could work together.
Guarantee your future never happened.
That's what I'm counting on.
With or without me,
that's exactly what you
and Alec are going to do.
I want to help you,
but I also don't want to lose you.
You've always been there for me.
I always will.
I know.
Ok.
Don't make me regret getting all emotional.
Get out of here.
You're a good man.
You ready?
Yeah.
What the hell happened in there?
I know you and Carlos
are covering for Travis.
I need to know why.
I've wanted to tell you.
Before now.
But I think it's better if I show you.
I don't understand.
Me, Travis, Liber8, Kellogg and his army...
we're from the future.
I'm trying to get back to the year 2077.
We came here to change history.
To make a better world,
and today it's all on the line.
You're not kidding?
We could use a good man like you.
Can I get you a glass?
No, thank you.
Save it.
Sounds ominous.
I know what you're trying to do.
What am I trying to do?
You're trying to talk me
into letting you out of here
or giving you information you want.
No.
Yeah.
Whatever.
But it's bigger than that.
And it involves a certain you.
You're wasting your time.
In this case, I think I'm
using what's left of it wisely.
Consider this:
why have an old, sick Kellogg leading you
when you can have a young
and vital Kellogg?
Sure, he needs to get up to speed,
but together they can accomplish this.
She will always be by his side as his queen
and rule their new empire together.
I see love in there.
You have feelings for me.
But we can never be together.
Never.
If you had just
listened to me, believed in me,
we could have had something.
I could... I could never...
Why?
Am I that repulsive?
You're... my... my father...
Of course I am.
Thank you, Jason.
So this is it.
This is really it?
No second thoughts, no turning back?
Jason, you can come with me.
You can go home, too.
No, it's too much.
It's too late.
I've been here too long.
No, this is my home now.
I still have some work to do.
Ok.
If you manage to make it back to 2077,
give this to my father.
There are some things
I needed to say to him,
to you, that I never had
the chance to before I left.
I will.
Alright, it's time.
Let's hope Kellogg holds
up his end of the bargain.
Goodbye, Jason.
Bye.
You alright?
Where is he?
He's close.
How's our arrangement looking?
She'll show, I know it.
My demands.
Let's go.
This better be you, Kellogg.
Game on, protector.
Head for the north-east door.
You need to move quickly.
How are we doing on that key?
Getting there.
Every minute costs us lives.
Did Marcellus know?
Did Marcellus know what?
That this was an invasion?
What are you talking about?
Oh, come on.
Just tell me.
I want to know if he lied to me
or if you kept him in the dark, too.
Alright.
I suppose it doesn't make a difference now.
Yeah, Marcellus knew.
It was his idea to convince you otherwise.
He knew the first minute
we arrived you went soft.
I betrayed people thinking
this was the only way
to save families!
Nothing's changed, Tonkin.
We're still saving families.
Ours.
Kiera?
Yeah?
You saved me.
What are you talking about?
We all go through life thinking
we know how it's gonna turn out.
We imagine our future, we
make moves and decisions
that lead us in that direction.
But you changed that for me.
You gave me knowledge of what would be.
The life that I was supposed to have,
the future that I built that you came from.
A profound regret is what you spared me.
I don't think I'll ever
be able to thank you enough.
Alec.
The simple fact that you want to change
is all the thanks I will ever need.
I won't let you down.
I know.
We don't have much time.
Go.
Zorin says they're close
to opening the portal.
And you should know they brought
through reinforcements.
How many?
Three.
Carlos and the VPD will be
hitting this place any minute.
Your security team needs to do its thing
and draw the soldiers
into a two-front fight.
Zach.
I'll prepare them.
I'm a man of my word.
Not really.
Alec, what do you need?
Access to the machine.
I'll need at least 30 seconds at the panel,
assuming it's straightforward.
You know I've always been
an admirer of yours.
Women like you are rare in any time.
Past, present, or future.
Whatever happens in there,
I'll always know I met my
match in Kiera Cameron.
Well, thank you.
Don't-don't you have anything
nice you wanna say about me?
Not really.
I'm going to go to the portal
room, do some recon.
You stay here.
I'll be back.
Let's get somebody on the north and south,
we'll need eyes on this entrance as well.
Get eyes over here, let me
know if you see any movement.
We arrested him trying to
get through our perimeter,
says he knows you?
Yeah, it's all good, Cuttlemans.
What're you doing here?
Warning you.
I wanted to warn you.
Kiera, Alec...
Those two of ours are inside.
I'll brief the squad.
But there's something else.
The machine in there
is essentially an anti-matter fusion bomb.
Once those guns start firing,
you could set off a chain
reaction explosion.
What kind of damage are we talking about?
Worst case scenario... half the city.
Ironic.
What's that?
This is near where you killed
Lucas in cold blood.
That was different.
I don't see how.
You made your choice, now you live with it.
It's not always black and white, Kiera.
You of all people should know that.
Oh, that's right.
You're either fighting for
an idea that's bigger than you,
or you're fighting for yourself.
Which is it?
I'm not sure.
I am.
You're conflicted, Brad.
You want clarity,
and clarity is a luxury in this business.
Time travel screws with our notions
about what's supposed to happen.
It gives us a false sense of control,
but really, we're all just pawns.
And all this?
This is to keep the darkness at bay.
And you of all people
should understand that.
Marcellus lied to me.
He told me we were building a portal
to rescue our brothers and sisters
from an oncoming massacre,
but it's a full-scale invasion.
They want to bring the war
to this time and win it
before it even starts.
Audacious.
This whole thing is insane.
So what do you want to do about it?
I want to prevent more suffering.
Brad's right.
Mission priority:
destroy the machine and the portal.
What?
What about you?
If it's my time, we'll find
out one way or another.
But either way,
change of plans.
Carlos?
What are we looking at?
Piron security's gonna let us in.
The north west door.
My guys will go through the machine room
and hit them from the other side.
Copy, north west door.
Hey, Kiera,
do we trust Kellogg?
I'm not sure.
Good luck, Carlos.
Well, that's my cue.
I like to leave before the shooting starts,
as you know.
Goodbye, Kiera.
It's been...
well... never mind.
Sir...
I'm here to offer my services,
limited as they are.
Bradley, let me see your firearm please.
We can use every cop we can get.
Gentlemen.
So how long have you known about Kiera?
Long enough.
Probably should have told you sooner.
The old me would have screwed it up.
I wasn't ready to listen.
Where the hell have you been?
Vasquez is dead.
What?
And Kellogg?
I don't know.
He's not where he should be.
If something happens to him,
this was all for nothing.
Yeah, I know.
Grimes, get your people ready.
Somebody find Kellogg.
I'm on it.
We can't open the portal
without all of them.
I know.
We need to buy ourselves some time.
You know what to do.
What are they up to?
I don't know,
but I don't like the looks of it.
Ok, there's Carlos.
Remember, do not hit the machine.
Where are your men?
There.
Alright.
Here we go.
We have contact!
Oh, shit.
This is VPD!
Put your weapons down and lay face down
with your hands on the floor!
Now!
Weaver?
Oh, no.
What the...?
NOW!!!!!
Take cover!
The Piron guards aren't shooting.
I know!
I don't get it.
Why aren't your men firing?
Orders, sir.
Who's orders?
Mr. Kellogg's orders.
We need to bring in the others.
Tether's holding.
But even if I can fix the key,
we need that power canister.
No!
Kellogg!
You were right.
Predictable to a fault.
I got eyes on Kellogg!
How do I get to his position?
Not on the blueprints that I have!
There's a utility corridor
that runs underneath
the south wall.
Follow me.
Bradley, hold this position
as long as you can.
Let's go!
Back up, back up!
We gotta go, now!
Back up, Kellogg.
What are you doing?
What do you think you're doing, Cameron?
I think you don't want anything to happen
to your supreme leader that
might ripple into the future.
Get out of my way, Curtis.
Someone's gotta put a stop to this.
You've never wavered, Jasmine.
Never stopped fighting for the cause.
You're so focused you haven't noticed
that you're already victorious.
That might be so,
but I'm not going to let you
or anyone else risk the lives
of everyone in this timeline
so that Kellogg can screw us all over.
Kellogg has his own path that he must take.
Neither you nor I can change that.
I don't remember being your
hostage as part of our deal.
And I don't recall you mentioning
your plan to time travel using the portal.
What?
Now why would he do that?
Because he knows he's screwed.
In this time, and in
the one that you come from.
He's got nowhere to go but backwards.
You have been playing
both sides since the beginning.
That's right.
So why should I trust you?
Because I think you want
what's best for the protector
as much as I do.
She left 2077 against her own will
and she's done more to change
the future than Liber8
could have ever done.
At the end of the day
she is our best weapon.
Backwards?
What are you talking about?
You wait under that bridge for
all of us to arrive from 2077
and then you kill everyone.
You're insane.
No.
Because then you
start out with a clean slate
and influence a young man in a barn.
Well, now we can get down to business.
You, fix the key.
Now.
I'll kill him, right now.
Will you?
'Cause I don't think you will.
I think you need that portal
open just as much as I do.
I think you could have raided
this place days ago,
but you didn't.
You needed us to fix that machine.
You sabotaged that key to stall us.
Why?
So you could use the portal for yourself.
Get down, get down!
Give him the key.
Take it.
Fix it.
Weaver?
Move to the lower level.
Let's move!
Fix it.
I'm trying.
Faster.
I'm trying!
The clock's ticking.
What is he doing?
He's bringing his army.
Done.
Thank you.
We have to stop them!
Weaver, take the kid.
This invasion starts now.
Carlos!
Gun!
Kill everyone!
Weaver!
Dillon!
I choose me!
Kellogg, no!
No!
Kiera, the portal is collapsing.
Kellogg destroyed that future
when he went through.
You're gonna be ok, we're
gonna get you out of here, Jack.
It's now or never.
Listen to the kid.
Kiera?
Kiera, please!
No.
You don't have to say anything.
I know.
I'll build you a better future.
I'll do it for you, Kiera Cameron.
Thank you.
We gotta clear out of here.
Everyone, fall back!
Fall back!
It's a shame to lose Dillon
and all those officers.
For what?
Is Kiera dead?
Alec?
She might not be.
The machine was tethered to my future.
The future that was destroyed
the moment Kellogg went through,
allowing the traveller to
return to his own time.
What the hell happened to Kiera?
There's no way to know.
It might be another 60 years
before we figure it out.
Look, what we do with this is up to us.
All of us.
We have a chance to build something better.
For her.
No, except we're screwed.
Kellogg stepped through.
Kiera had the notion
that Kellogg would try something like this.
We used Piron's equipment
to program Kiera's time ball.
By allowing us to
have access to his system,
Kellogg thought he could learn
how to program his time ball,
but instead it just allowed us
to feed him the wrong information
regarding how to select dates,
which apparently he assumed was genuine.
He might have thought he was
going back to the day that
Kiera and Liber8 arrived.
But he didn't.
No.
So where... when did he go?
Oh my god.
Oh, that little shit.
No.
No!
What does this mean?
I'm not sure what you're talking about.
Liber8 won.
What's Liber8?
No, wait.
I remember the stories now.
Uncle Julian used to
tell me about his younger days
protesting the old corporations.
A barbaric and
uncivilized age by all accounts.
But you would know that, wouldn't you?
You would have known him then.
Kiera?
I missed it!
I didn't want to miss it!
I warned you, Alec.
I warned you, but as usual
you don't listen.
It worked.
I've been waiting for you, Kiera.
For 60 years I didn't know
if you died that day
in the portal.
That's right, it's me.
The same one you left just a second ago,
from your perspective.
Alec?
Oh, Alec!
I know, you were just with me!
This is so strange.
Imagine what it's like for me.
You did it.
Sam?
Is he here?
I'll take you to him.
Emily lobbied City Hall
for that before she passed.
You were together?
Every day until the end.
Police?
Not CPS?
CPS never formed.
There was no collapse,
no uprising, no revolution.
No corporate congress.
And no corporate congress.
Julian and Edward and I saw to that.
Amazing.
It's because of you, Kiera.
And Sam?
Over there.
Sam.
I set the time coordinates
as close as I could
to the year you left.
I knew you'd have some adjustments to make.
You're not angry?
No, how could I be?
You've given me the greatest gift.
I have to see him.
You made a better world, Kiera.
What?
We thought you died that day.
Carlos, Julian and I dedicated ourselves
to building a better future.
And we steered civilization
inspired by your sacrifice.
But Sam?
This is the price for making
the world a better place.
This Sam will grow up in
a world free of violence,
free of revolution, free of corruption.
His future is bright.
And it's because of you, Kiera.
That's the price of love.
Real love.
You'll understand in time.
Studyphim.vn