You want a confession from
me because I'm a villain.
I'm a bad man.
But that's not all I am, is it?
I'm a special kind of bad man.
A freak.
When people find out about me,
they find out about all the
other freaks, as well.
Nobody will believe him if he
says he comes from the future.
Yeah, but he has no past.
It doesn't matter if they
don't believe him.
We're associated and suddenly I'm suspect.
You want to tell the
truth about your background?
Go ahead.
All that's gonna get you is a life sentence
in the psych ward.
So if that's really where
you want to end up...
You still enjoy the
semblance of a free press.
Some enterprising reporter will dig around
and find out she's as
intriguing and mysterious as I am.
Alright Inspector, this
is a mess and you know it.
The use of these
restraints is a human rights violation
and my client has been
held for days without charges.
Carlos can delay this.
We just need a few more days.
He's stuck.
He has to lay charges soon or
this is unlawful detention.
It'll compromise the case against Travis.
We have to go.
Kellogg's expecting us.
Lay the charge!
Release the restraints!
We still have plenty of
time to press charges.
I'm not breaking any
federal laws with those restraints.
Except you are a municipal police force.
Not a security arm
with the federal government.
Care enough to deal with me now, Inspector?
You want to kill your lawyer?
Go ahead, I'll sell tickets.
Is that all you got?
You're gonna wish you had let me out
when you had the chance.
If you really cared about
protecting Cameron.
Hmm.
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Sending you forward in time
isn't the most impossible aspect of this.
What are you talking about?
You have two free radicals who
are essentials to this plan.
And free radicals tend to
do whatever the hell they want.
Kellogg is motivated.
He needs us to take down those soldiers
before they take him down.
We trust Kellogg to act according to plan?
And Brad makes
Kellogg look like a boy scout.
You're gonna have to find a
way to get him on board somehow.
And these guys don't want anything.
Is that all you got?
You're gonna wish you let
me out when you had the chance.
Not very cooperative, is he?
Well, he's never
going to admit to anything.
We both know I can't hold him
any longer without charges.
Piron doesn't want him in front of a judge.
Piron doesn't have jurisdiction.
Did you see the medical report
after they initially brought him in?
Unusual physiology
and evidence of experimental
self-healiing nanotechnology.
That sounds like science fiction.
Sounds like Piron.
They've requested...
No. They've demanded we
hand Travis over to them.
If this whole Liber8 thing turns out to be
some kind of Piron project gone awry,
some kind of cover up,
there'll be hell to pay.
Some enterprising reporter will dig around
and find out she's as
intriguing and mysterious as I am.
No more delays.
I don't care who she is and
I don't care what she's done,
I want Liber8 put away
and I want to know what
Piron wants with Travis.
You hear me?
So I'm interested in the
military technology
first and foremost.
I'm sure that's a relief to you, Kiera.
Alec assures me that there's
very little chance
I'll be able to travel
forward in time, so...
That's unfortunate.
But if anybody could do it...
We have a way to enter their stronghold
with no casualties and no gunfire.
We don't want anyone to get hurt.
Care to share how?
After you let us use your lab at Piron.
I need to make some
adjustments to the time ball.
We need it in order to jam their defenses.
Yeah, once I let you in,
what assurance do I have
you're gonna deliver on your promise?
You'll just have to trust us.
And leave us alone while we're working.
Yeah, I can do that.
Joining me in the dragon's den?
Just visiting.
Like you.
I'm not visiting.
I'm a resident.
There's work here I believe in.
You took a hit.
You took it to heart.
You have other choices.
We all do.
In the fairytales I've read,
the hero enters the
cave to slay the dragon.
Not to join him.
It's good to see you.
You got family coming through?
My kid sister and her boyfriend.
If they're still alive.
What about your mom?
She's afraid she'll be blown apart.
That the technology doesn't work.
It's like dying.
You never get a report
back from the other side.
The beacon proved otherwise.
Oh, also
need-to-know?
It's a mission, Tonkin.
You know how it is.
When I left, my sister was dead
and now Zorin says she's on the manifest.
Zorin didn't make the manifest.
Marcellus?
Marcellus took care of you.
If they're on that
manifest it means they're alive.
Here we are.
I can set you up with
some lab assistants...
Don't need 'em.
Kiera will help.
Hmm.
She's driving this mission.
But it's flawed, isn't it?
She wants to go home even
though home probably isn't there.
Does she understand that?
There's a chance.
A chance?
Kid, this isn't Vegas.
Are you really gonna roll
the dice with her life?
How is this gonna work, Kellogg?
That's an excellent question.
Ok, so the soldiers asked
me to provide Piron security
after your unscheduled visit.
Those men are loyal to me,
and they'll turn on Zorin
and his team on my command.
Ok. Sounds feasible.
So, with my help, you and
Alec get inside the building
and, along with my
security, you neutralize the soldiers.
Alec does his magic and abracadabra,
Kiera disappears.
Once you've left us, I destroy the machine
and stop the invasion before it begins.
Then what?
What do you mean?
What happens with you?
I don't think that's any of
your concern anymore, Kiera.
You made your choice.
You chose you.
You think I'm being selfish?
You're calling Brad, aren't you?
I think it's time we
invite him to the party.
I think I trust him less than Kellogg.
Well, we need them both.
I know.
I'll be back.
I believe you.
And I want your help.
What did you have in mind?
Alec says that, with your technology,
he has the ability to send me home.
And if he can do it for
me, he can do it for you, too.
We found something together
because we both lost so much.
But now there's a chance to get it back.
The ability to see our families again.
Even if I could, what if I was too late?
I can't do that.
I can't...
I can't lose them again.
I know.
But there's not much
time, and if you don't want to,
I understand.
But I really hope you want to help.
We need access to the machine, just once.
It doesn't have to be
dangerous for anybody.
If I did choose to go back,
I wouldn't compromise this mission.
I understand.
So I'm going to give you
back the key you requested
as a sign of my good faith.
Alec really thinks he can do this?
He says "impossible" to me as
often as he says "probable".
But you're willing?
For a chance to see my son?
It's possible he may not even be there.
You're really killing the moment.
I just want you to find
what you're looking for.
Then help me.
So we're pressing charges tomorrow,
but I have a feeling Piron
will try to intercept.
So if there's anything you
might want to say to help your case,
now would be the time to do it.
Your system will say what it wants.
It doesn't matter to me.
I'll take us both down.
It doesn't matter to Kiera, either.
She's going home.
Forward in time?
Mmmhmm.
She just woke up and now she
wants to go back to sleep?
You should take me to court now, Inspector.
I'll make sure she stays.
Well, I don't blame her for
wanting to see her kid.
She's still walking out on you.
It's not like that.
I'm not gonna hide who I am, Fonnegra.
Neither would you.
The truth of me reveals the truth of her.
That's a hell of a view, huh?
I always liked it.
What can I do for you, sir?
I'm here to take Travis back
to Piron for processing.
Don't be so surprised.
You and I both know that
our friend in lockup
pushes the limits of biology
in a way that begs investigation.
Kellogg knows more than
he's willing to tell me.
I can live with that,
but I wanted to give
you a chance to tell me
what you know and how
this connects to Kiera.
Kiera, Kellogg and Liber8,
they were sent back in time
from the future to change history.
Ok, that's a good one.
You understand why I had to ask?
Are you ok?
I was looking for a way to be relevant.
After I realized my body was
going to be a liability,
my pride did not allow
me to deal with the truth.
Until now.
It's a recording I found
that's going to help you lay charges
in the Escher murder.
We're in this together.
Sure, you get me to kill Escher for you,
but we're in this together.
You do this, and you're free of me.
Escher used to say that, too.
Once you pull the trigger,
it'll finally be true.
You can get Kellogg on conspiracy
to commit murder.
All you have to do is offer Emily a deal
to testify against him.
Let's bury this son of a bitch!
Are you sure about this?
You tell your partner I'm
walking out of the cave.
With all her mysteries and missteps,
she's always trying to do the right thing.
It's time I did the same.
So I will be back to
deal with this Travis thing.
I hope I can count on you.
I'm reprogramming it.
The way the time ball uses
the soldier's power source is new,
but the brakes and the
steering wheel are all the same.
Except not really.
Well, you only get to use the brakes once.
In the future, my
future, if I ever get back,
there are no guarantees.
Sam might not be there.
He might not even be.
I thought you were
optimistic about Brad helping us.
He asked me the questions I'm
afraid to ask of myself.
Well, you can always stay here.
Thanks.
Don't stop now.
Where's my key, Tonkin?
She has agreed to return it.
In exchange for what?
Doesn't matter.
What she wants, no one can give her.
Mmmhmm.
Why does Kellogg want to come here?
To this time?
He said it was a turning point.
A time when choices could
still be made and have an impact.
Hmm.
I don't think there's any right choice.
You'll feel differently
when you see your sister and nephews
come through that portal.
I want to see them, I really do.
But I would give
everything I have to go back to 2035.
Yeah, we all have our dates.
Outcomes we'd like to change.
But this is a one-way flight.
How can you be sure?
Commander spent years
trying to build forward travel.
He could see the writing on the wall.
He knew that time travel would be a weapon
that leveled everything.
Never cracked it.
He told you this?
I have my date, too.
2032.
Two children, a wife.
That's it.
Finished.
I think I deserve a drink.
If that's true, we all do.
Come on, Tonkin.
Join us.
Will it work?
That's the question I'm
afraid to ask myself.
How's it all going?
Come on, I thought we
were all on the same team.
You didn't think that for an instant.
People change all the time,
and there's no time like the present.
Unless my timing is all wrong.
We're done.
I need to take the device somewhere safe.
I've done my part.
How do we proceed?
I'll tell you when you need to know.
You know, there was a
time when that attitude
would have thrilled me.
But I got too much at stake now.
This?
Some thing you stole?
You know how improbable this has been?
Our survival.
What makes you think my life is any
less precious to me than yours is to you?
Uh, Kiera?
What? Oh, shit.
- I take it this isn't part of the plan.
- No.
Matthew Kellogg, you're under arrest...
Carlos?
For conspiracy in the murder of Escher...
Carlos.
A.K.A. Mark Sadler.
You have the right to retain
and instruct council without delay.
This is a big misunderstanding.
Carlos, what are you doing?
If you do not have a
lawyer, we can refer one to you.
Was this you?
No, it was not.
Anything you say can be
used as evidence in court.
Carlos, this can wait.
I need him now!
No.
This is murder.
This is happening right here and now.
But the thing is we sorta need his help.
Do you understand?
Do you wish to speak to a lawyer?
Call Jacqueline right away.
I'll take care of it.
You're going to regret this, Carlos.
I can promise you that.
I've been waiting a long time to do that.
If you would just listen to me...
Save it, Kiera.
I serve the public, not private concerns.
You should know that by now.
Oh good, you're still here.
I probably got half an
hour or so down here.
Um, you... you could try to recruit me
to that organization of yours.
Um...
Liber8?
I'll call you back.
What evidence?
An audio recording of
Kellogg ordering the hit on Escher.
Did Dillon bring it to you?
So it's selfish if I want to wait,
but it's not selfish if
you're trying to save Dillon.
That's not what this is about.
Then I guess it has nothing to
do with me leaving, either.
Carlos, I know you see
this as a suicide mission.
I do.
But that is my choice to make.
Great. I'm not stopping you.
That's exactly what you're doing.
No.
Kiera, we're partners.
We're supposed to have each other's back.
I didn't even know you wanted to leave
until circumstances forced you to tell me.
Until I could be sure.
Also, my choice.
Yeah, well, your choices?
They have an impact on
the people in your life.
You need to take responsibility,
not just for yourself.
I have honoured my responsibility
to others.
This department, this city.
Dillon, you, Alec.
I have done right by all of you.
Yes, yes, you have done that.
But you've also done
whatever the hell you wanted to
when it suits you.
This is different.
You hear yourself, right?
You want me to release Kellogg.
You know what he's done, you
know what he's capable of,
and yet you still want him free.
Listen, I'm...
I'm sorry about Sonya, by the way.
And Lucas.
Is Garza still alive?
It's hard to believe you're
almost one of us.
What are you talking about?
I'm the embodiment of what
Liber8 was fighting for.
Choice.
Self-determination.
Freedom.
Who better represents
those virtues than me?
It's what you do with those virtues.
Sonya.
Lucas.
Jowarski.
Kagame.
They built a legacy.
Tens of thousands more
who won't suffer and die
because we changed that future.
What about you?
What will they say
about Travis Verta at the end?
He killed like no other.
He terrorized with the best of them.
He'll be out on bail in 24 hours
and all of this will be for nothing.
Oh, I wouldn't bet on it.
Is Kellogg the only one you're arresting?
Right on cue.
Special interest number two.
Are you going to arrest Emily?
If I knew where she was.
Now, I could compel
you to give me her location
or you could just be a good citizen.
Carlos, he doesn't know.
I don't.
And you can't trust
Kellogg to tell the truth
about her involvement.
I have evidence.
Kellogg blackmailed her.
My father did, too.
Well, we'll have to find that out.
Oh yeah, justice.
That always gets to the truth.
Justice, even if that's only a concept,
that's all that I've got.
It works great for those
who can afford to buy it.
Isn't that what you're trying to do?
Huh?
You know, I've tried to
protect you and Kiera along the way,
but Kellogg had your father murdered.
Ok? I don't get to look the other way.
Not for Kiera, and not for
Kellogg, and not for Travis.
What about Travis?
They'll say "Travis Verta, he was the key.
The key to unlocking the
secrets of a genuine superman.
"The future warrior.
"The super-soldier."
I'll be the one keeping your legacy alive
as I patent and replicate every
nano-particle from 2077
inside that bioengineered
hulk you call a body.
Piron doctors want to cut
him open like a guinea pig,
see what makes him so special.
She can't go home now, you realize that.
Yeah, well, I'm sorry.
Ok? I don't get to make exceptions.
That's how the system falls apart.
We can still try to.
We can't get in without
Kellogg and you know it.
It's Brad.
Brad, where are you?
Ok, I'll be right there.
Maybe he can help.
I gotta go.
You're just another CEO
in a long line of
delusional corporate emperors.
And if it's one thing
history has taught us, it's this:
Empires eventually crumble.
Oh, don't worry.
In my future that won't happen.
Kiera?
I'm here.
Brad's here.
No, he's meeting me at the park.
No, he's right here.
They're coming for Kellogg.
Alec, listen to me.
Tell Carlos and get the hell out of there.
Brad's here.
I don't think it's a friendly visit.
Check the cameras.
He's blacked them out.
Some device.
Get out of here.
You just missed Kiera.
Yeah.
What I'd really like
is to bail out Kellogg.
Yeah, I've been getting
that offer a lot lately.
Remember that scene
downtown a couple of weeks ago,
torn up buildings, strange fires.
Yeah.
I also remember the people that got hurt.
So neither of us want that again.
Is that a threat?
Drop it.
Put your hands up.
That'll be my rescue team.
Henderson, is that you?
Brad's here.
Carlos has a gun on him.
I'm gonna check it out and see what...
Oh my God.
Alec, I have three dead cops down here.
They're after Kellogg.
What the hell is Brad doing?
Carlos just arrested him.
I think he'd be
downstairs if that's all he wanted.
I think he's here for the key.
We didn't come here to kill anyone, Carlos.
But if we're attacked...
Shots fired!
Release Kellogg, please.
Put it down.
Right now!
Now! Now!
Hurry up, go! Go!
Kier... Kiera?
Alec?
Shit.
What did you do?
Cuff him.
Chris, Kevin, Randy.
Come with me.
Shit!
Alec?
Clear.
Move.
Don't move!
Identify yourself!
Do it slowly.
Get back up in here!
Let's go, let's go!
He's out!
You really think you're worth it?
Somebody does.
Go!
Grenade!
Move!
Oh, finally.
Thank you.
Come on, protector.
Yeah, come on, protector.
He's close.
First hallway on the right.
Watch my back.
I'll get Kellogg.
Make sure he doesn't take any fire
or Zorin will have our heads.
You don't need to remind me.
Damn.
Vasquez, it's empty.
Almost.
Nolan!
Target is no longer tracked.
I repeat, we are blind.
Fall back.
We can't get to them this way.
Alright.
Go back up.
Alec, give me the key and we'll go away.
Kiera can take her shot, Alec.
But our mission has to come first.
Where is it!
Where's what?
Where is it, Alec?
I don't know!
I'm sorry, kid.
Come on, Alec!
Where is it?!
Don't make me break your arm, Alec!
It's nothing personal,
but I've got a deadline.
I'm glad to see
you're making better choices.
You don't know how much I
hate doing your dirty work.
You get me out of this, I swear to you...
Save your words, Kellogg.
I will do whatever I can to get you...
Cameron!
Move.
Let him go!
Don't let me go.
You have no idea how important he is.
Go!
Thank you, protector.
We need to hold this area.
Any word on reinforcements?
We're completely cut off.
All radio and cell
comms are down in the area.
Where's Alec?
Where are we holding Brad?
Brad escaped.
We haven't found Alec.
What?
I got a bad feeling about this.
Let him go, Brad.
Give me Kellogg.
It serves you, too.
It turns out I'm more
of a cop than I realized.
What the hell is that?!
The fail-safe.
Move.
Fire! Fire!
Get him out of there!
Fall back! Fall back!
Give me Kellogg and all this stops.
You could have killed me.
You could have killed Alec,
and yet you keep choosing not to.
It's not what I want, Kiera.
It never has been.
Then why?
That machine is a portal to my future.
I have family there.
They're alive.
You know how that feels.
Grenade!
Fall back!
Just give him Kellogg.
There's too many dead, now.
And give everyone his future?
Your friends are dying down there, Kiera.
You can stop this.
Make the right choice.
I can call them off.
Ok, deal!
Kellogg for Alec!
Stand down, Vasquez!
Kiera, please don't.
I'm just a walking kidney transplant
for my future self.
I have no choice.
You know that.
You just keep playing along.
I'll come for you.
You'll let me into that building,
the plan moves ahead.
I promise.
Rollins, you've got 20
seconds to get to the roof
or I leave without you!
I got one more thing to deal with.
You can still go home.
After the invasion.
It won't matter.
You won't be here.
All this time,
and you still have no idea who I am.
Travis... wh... what are you doing?
Get out of here.
Vasquez!
Go!
Go, go, go!
Everyone, get out!
Time's up.
This place is a write-off.
Like my dream of going home.
You can't give up now.
We don't have Brad.
Well, apparently we never did.
We have a new man on the inside.
Kellogg.
Yeah, the one and only.
For now.
Are you trying to get rid of me?
I definitely am.
Did we lose Travis?
Yeah.
Yeah, he helped save a lot
of lives, including mine.
He had a chance to walk, but he didn't.
You know, Nora's going to
have a lot of questions.
I'm not sure we have the answers for her.
I'll take the heat.
Alec, give us a sec, would you?
Yeah, sure thing.
What the hell happened to Kellogg?
I had to let him go.
Goddammit, Kiera.
I had no choice.
Brad was holding Alec at gunpoint.
You wanted Kellogg in the wind.
At least that was the play earlier today.
What I said, about wanting to see Sam,
nothing has ever been truer for me.
But every one of us getting what we want
when we want it?
I know it doesn't work that way.
I don't want to lose you.
And sometimes I don't want to go, either.
Well, with the way things are playing out
we may be stuck with each other for good.
Kiera, can't you just
give up this fantasy, ok?
Come back to reality,
as hard as that may be?
Whatever your plan was,
Brad blew it apart when
he blew this place up.
Ok?
I'm going to destroy the asshole
that did this to me and my people,
so you tell me where he is right now.