Previously on "Timeless"...
I know what you're
really meant to be, Lucy.
Just ask them why they really
chose you for this mission.
- Car trouble?
- You're with Rittenhouse.
If you keep playing your part,
it helps us protect everyone.
You, your family.
You and Anthony Bruhl were
the first ones they ever sent
to travel through time.
Rittenhouse happened.
You faked your own death
and hid in the past.
I know things that Anthony doesn't know.
You remember how to pilot it?
It's like riding a bike, right?
But if the Mothership falls
into Rittenhouse's hands,
t's too dangerous.
Flynn?
Most likely discovered
he was trying to...
Do the right thing.
[exhales]
I want you to help me steal
the time machine to save Jess.
He... he brought it back,
okay? No harm, right?
- Tell me about Jessica.
- Jessica's still dead.
She's alive, guys, please!
That's my father.
I'm glad you know about Rittenhouse.
What you are a part of is inhuman.
Well, I've got news for you, my dear,
you're a part of it too.
If it's any consolation,
you're taking this
much better than I did.
I was 17...
when my father told
me about Rittenhouse.
And how do you handle a
responsibility like that?
Took me a long, long time
to come to grips with it.
My father... your grandfather...
Ethan Cahill, he's still alive.
You'll meet him soon.
He ran away when he was told.
It's all right.
You'll come around like we all did,
because it's who you are, Lucy.
It's your legacy.
[chuckles] You know, not a day goes by
that I don't think of you.
Would you please stop pretending
that you actually care about me?
My entire life, not one phone call,
and all of a sudden
you're Dad of the Year?
I get it. Your life is...
is crazy and getting crazier.
You're engaged to some
doctor you don't know.
You don't even have
your sister to talk to,
and now I come along.
I am so...
so sorry about Amy.
You do not get to say her name.
I know what you are.
What do you know about Rittenhouse
besides what Flynn has told you?
I went to 1780 and I met
David Rittenhouse myself!
He had these dark theories that...
You don't think we've
evolved since then?
We don't use leeches anymore either.
When you're inside,
you'll see the good we do.
I will stop you.
I will never be a part
of this, do you hear me?
I said the same thing.
So did my father.
Rittenhouse...
Rittenhouse isn't a choice.
It's blood.
Yours, mine,
and your kids someday.
When you're ready to come home,
i'll be here, Lucy...
with open arms.
[door slams shut]
Two lefts from headquarters,
30 minutes on the freeway,
and four gravel roundabouts.
That should put us somewhere in the...
National Park.
Smart place for a black site.
You stole a time machine, Wyatt.
We can't exactly throw
you in county jail.
Hey.
You think you could, uh,
slip me a snorkel before
the waterboarding starts?
I am seriously pissed at you,
but I put in a call to Sam Dwyer.
He's a JAG defense lawyer, a good one.
I don't want a defense.
I deserve this.
[dramatic music]
Good luck.
♪ ♪
[door closes]
He said something to
upset you, didn't he?
This is why I didn't
want you to see him.
It's not anything like that. I just...
I just want to know more about him.
He was opinionated, and he was stubborn,
and I see a lot of him in you, actually.
[sighs]
What about his family?
I met his parents once... from D. C.
His father was an aide
in the White House,
i remember that.
Hmm.
All right, you want to know
the best thing about Benjamin Cahill?
He gave me you.
♪ ♪
Whoa.
Scary Rittenhouse dude is your father?
You shouldn't have talked to him.
I had to see him with my own eyes.
You put yourself in serious danger.
The guy who's been terrorizing
me, that's your dad?
- My biological father.
- How about you do me a favor,
and the next time you and
your dad are at a barbecue,
you tell him it'd be super great
if he didn't kill my family!
Okay, his name's Benjamin Cahill.
Squeaky clean record.
He's a pediatric surgeon
at UCSF, for God's sake.
Okay, that is so creepy.
Lucy, I'm...
sorry, I can't imagine.
How are you doing?
How do you think I'm doing?
Look, we'll figure
this all out... somehow.
Okay, I'm afraid we don't have time.
Flynn jumped. May 21, 1927.
- Paris.
- What's Paris?
That's the day that Charles
Lindbergh landed in Paris...
the first transatlantic solo flight...
but I cannot do this, not now.
Okay, where's Wyatt?
I mean, we're not
doing this without him.
After his little stunt,
there's zero chance
he's going on this trip.
My hands are tied.
You can either jump
into that "Lifeboat,"
or you can sit back and
watch Flynn torch history.
Maybe we let Flynn torch history.
- Lucy...
- No, I'm serious.
Okay, we know that
Rittenhouse is terrible.
We know that... that they want
to take the Mothership back
and destroy everything.
So what if we let Flynn take them out?
I mean, that's a good thing, right?
Lucy, I'm gonna go.
What? Why?
I mean, after everything
that Rittenhouse said
they're gonna do to your family?
Yes, they wildly and extravagantly suck,
and I want them gone, but
Flynn is going to hurt people.
He is going to kill
people, change history.
You know that.
And if we don't stop him...
that's on us.
[soft music]
I'll go alone if I have to.
♪ ♪
I'm in.
Okay.
Well, actually, you two
won't be going alone.
[dramatic music]
Lucy Preston, Rufus Carlin,
this is Master Sergeant
David Baumgardner.
Bam - Bam.
Uh, Wyatt mentioned you before.
"Dave's" fine.
We've had him on standby
since the Alamo mission.
I thought Agent Christopher
was yanking my chain
when she said "time travel," but...
holy crap.
I know how you feel.
He's been thoroughly briefed,
but show him the ropes.
You're the varsity squad now.
That is not comforting.
Look, I get how you must
feel. Wyatt's one of the best.
Just do me a favor and
no cowboy stuff, okay?
Unless there's cowboys or something.
Then, uh, do cowboy stuff.
[energetic music]
Ma'am?
"Lucy's" fine.
Well, you're in charge, Lucy.
♪ ♪
That's right.
It's a common misconception,
but it's not true.
Well, why do they say short
people have a Napoleon complex?
Well, that's just the
thing, Napoleon wasn't short.
He was 5'7".
That's above average for his era.
He just... he surrounded
himself with tall men,
and it just made him look short.
It's all relative.
- How do you know that?
- Because I met him.
What, you think the Wild
West was my first trip?
[scoffs]
Okay, seriously, what's the
deal with this little diary?
Not worth getting into
right now, believe me.
You ready yet?
[airplane approaching]
Do you hear that?
Yep.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
Are you sure you're not gonna
kill him with that thing?
Oh, he's flying in slow and low.
This thing can cripple a
rudder from twice this distance.
He'll be fine, just needs
to land early, that's all.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[man screams]
[groaning]
[groans]
Thought you said he was gonna be fine.
Ah, It's all relative.
Congratulations, Lieutenant Lindbergh,
and welcome to Paris.
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www. Addic7ed. Com
Thought you said the
ride would be bumpy.
Nothing? You're not nauseous at all?
Not even Tea Cup ride at
Disneyland type queasy?
Lindbergh is set to
touch down any minute.
There's about 100,000 people
waiting for him to
land just west of here.
Flying what, 3,500 miles
in a crappy single - Seater?
Guy's like Indiana Jones.
He was. Just a nice boy from St. Louis
who becomes the most
famous man in the world.
About a decade from now he
becomes a Nazi sympathizer,
paranoid, and anti - Semitic.
Hitler awards him a medal.
Boy, that story took a dark turn.
[people speaking French]
_
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
See there?
Tire marks. This thing didn't crash.
It landed.
That plane took a direct
hit to the back rudder.
- So Lindbergh's alive?
- I don't know.
But he didn't burn up in
the crash, that's for sure.
Flynn kidnapped him maybe.
Where do you think
Flynn shot him down from?
Best guess?
Tripod mounted MILAN at 400 yards,
and judging by the debris over there,
not too far.
[energetic music]
Yeah, they were right here.
You really think there's a
chance Lindbergh is still alive?
I'm a reporter for the "Toronto Star."
Name's Hemingway.
[exciting music]
Ernest Hemingway?
- You read my book.
- Oh, my God.
I've... i've read all of them.
I mean, all of the
words in your one book,
but maybe you will write more.
I doubt it, but still,
tell me you love whiskey,
and I'll marry you.
- Hey.
- I...
Found this.
Think one of our guys was smoking it.
[sniffs]
It's Havana tobacco.
Only one district in Paris
sells a cigarette like that.
God knows I smoke enough of 'em.
Give me the scoop, and I'll take you.
- Hmm?
- [uncorks flask]
['20s music playing]
♪ Honey, I've been blue ♪
♪ Sad and lonely too ♪
♪ I can't help pleading all the time ♪
♪ What else can I do? ♪
- Cheers.
Bad news is, this is the
only place that's open.
The good news?
It's the only place that matters.
♪ ♪
♪ Cryin' to the moon ♪
♪ For I want some loving ♪
If there's anyone who can help us find
the folks you're looking for, Josie can.
♪ You make me weep and cry ♪
♪ Yes, wish that I... ♪
Josephine Baker?
♪ And hear the reason why ♪
My mom had a record cover of her that...
got me through some lonely nights.
♪ ♪
That's some antique porn, my friend.
I prefer the term "vintage."
♪ What a fool am I ♪
Who's Josephine Baker?
Seriously? Uh, well,
she's the biggest entertainer
in the country at the moment.
I mean, think Beyoncé 1927.
She basically owns Paris.
And she became an undercover spy
for the Allies in World War II.
I mean, she's just...
she's... remarkable.
♪ Lonesome lovesick blues ♪
[cheers and applause]
Come on. I'll introduce you.
Okay.
[overlapping chatter]
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
Who the hell are all these people?
I thought you'd tell me.
They say they're in charge now.
Who said that?
Matter is, they've been checked
and double - Checked and triple - Checked.
- Now, all of these people...
- Who authorized all these people?
I did.
Everything's under
control, Agent Christopher.
Is it? And you are?
I'll leave you two to get acquainted.
More later, obviously.
Jake Neville, NSA.
Here's my badge.
And my Homeland Security clearance,
and a letter from
Deputy Secretary Ledgett.
This project's command was taken over
by the National Security
Agency at 0900 hours.
My team and I are just
getting up to speed.
So NSA is taking point, and
no one bothered to tell me?
After Logan went on his joyride,
a decision was made to get
fresh eyes on the project.
And the buck stops with me, so it seems.
Look, between you and me?
Wasn't your fault.
You're getting a raw deal.
Still, I think Homeland Security
is waiting to reassign you.
Sorry. Escort's just NSA protocol.
Thank you for your service.
Best of luck, Agent Neville.
Oh, I forgot.
Denise, set your badge to
the facility on the table.
Nope, never seen them.
Lindy and me, we're both from St. Louis,
so if there's any chance
he survived, I want to help.
- Thank you.
- [chuckles]
I'm from the Midwest as well, Chicago.
Just saying. Practically neighbors.
Mm, Windy City.
So tell me, Chicago,
how hard do you blow?
Uh, su... super, uh, hard... hard.
Well, see? I told you Josie would help.
If I had a nickel for every
time I hit on this woman,
- I'd have...
- $1.05.
Sounds about right.
I'll take these photos.
We'll ask our friends if
they've seen them. Hmm?
Um, do me a favor and
don't tell Jiya about...
any of this.
Mm - Hmm.
[sighs]
[ominous music]
His shoulder's dislocated.
I need him focused. We need
to find something for his pain.
I don't think Vicodin's
been invented yet.
Well, people are getting
drunk someplace. Improvise.
Get me some absinthe.
Where are you going?
The Dingo Bar.
That place is gonna be
crawling with famous people.
You think I'm gonna miss
a chance to meet Picasso?
Sorry. Nothing yet.
What are you goggling at?
Picasso, sitting there with
Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald.
Don't be too awestruck.
Picasso's all hands.
- Really?
- You know, Ernest calls them
the Lost Generation,
but I think he stole that from Gertrude.
Lost Generation.
I get it.
Oh? How so?
All seen too much violence.
Aimless, confused,
don't know what's right
or wrong, good or bad.
Sounds like you're not
just talking about them.
[chuckles]
I'm, uh...
I... i was a teacher.
- Hmm.
- Um, a good one.
I loved the research, the facts.
I love facts, they're solid.
You can trust them.
Your personal life might be a mess,
but you always have the facts.
It's like... standing on concrete.
But then you realize that
you're standing on quicksand,
and nothing's true.
You know, you're wrong about one thing.
What's that?
When Ernest calls them
the Lost Generation,
he doesn't mean aimless.
He means battered...
broke down...
but getting ready to stand back up.
There's a difference.
I like that.
♪ ♪
I like you.
[laughs]
Thank you.
I never meant for you to
get pulled off your detail.
- I'm sorry.
- The hours sucked.
Yeah, but...
changing horses midstream, that's risky.
Wait, so this Neville guy just
shows up with how many people?
A dozen, maybe more.
On a top secret project like this?
How do you get that much
clearance for that many people?
Overnight?
[dramatic music]
In Delta, we once ran a two - Month
op in the Ghazni province
where the village chiefs
were itching for a fight.
Well, we showed up as an
international peacekeeping force.
Painted the schools, built
the wells, all that stuff.
By the time the Afghans realized
that we controlled their village,
there was nothing
they could do about it.
Takeovers don't have to be hostile.
Nah.
No, I don't think you got canned
'cause of my little joyride.
This thing feels organized.
It feels coordinated.
They had to have been
planning this thing for weeks.
This is a coup.
♪ ♪
[crowd chattering]
['20s music playing]
What the hell are you doing?
Sit down. Have a drink.
You're supposed to be
helping us find Lindbergh.
I'm devising a plan.
Step one, lubrication.
So my friend Claudette was working
the corner of Rue Emile and
Avenue du Nord earlier today
when she saw the man you're looking for
walk into a shabby old château.
Ah.
See?
You're welcome.
Hi.
At the bar.
Emma.
I saw them.
[dramatic music]
Get down!
- Get down! Now!
- Oh, my God!
What's that?
It's a 1927 Colt.38.
But where's your modern gun...
like whatever Wyatt uses?
I was told not to bring
anything back from 2017.
- Those are the rules.
- You're supposed to ignore that rule.
Now you tell me.
[gunshots]
[groans]
Go! Run!
[gun clicks]
[groans]
I think you got one!
Dave?
Rufus, do something.
No.
[French music playing]
We can't just... leave him there.
We can't go back.
He's right.
Best case, you spend all
night in a police station,
answering questions.
Worst case, they try and pin it
on the two American strangers.
How's that gonna find Lindbergh?
It's my fault.
It's not your fault.
It's Flynn's.
How are we gonna find Lindbergh now?
[laughing] You know, this is the part
where Wyatt would say
something annoying,
but he'd be right...
and... pull it all together.
Yeah, well, we don't have a Wyatt,
we don't have a Dave, and
we don't have a soldier.
[toilet flushing]
You need a... uh, you
need a soldier, you say?
- [uncorks flask]
- Hm...
You've come to the right place.
He is the bravest man I know.
- And the drunkest.
- No. Absolutely not.
- No.
- You may not know this,
but I fought in the Great War.
- You were an ambulance driver.
- I took shrapnel.
You have had too much to drink.
No, absolutely not.
I'm gonna make this easy on you.
I'm not taking no for an answer.
We have an address.
What are we waiting for?
I smell adventure.
[song ends]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
You sure this is the right place?
See any other old châteaus anywhere?
- Maybe Josephine's friend was wrong.
- Yeah.
Josie's friend is a
prostitute, a good one,
and if I know anything
about prostitutes...
and believe me, I do...
they never forget a face.
She says they were here, they were here.
Hmm. I didn't know that.
What is it?
I'm going to be ill.
Perhaps somebody could lead me outside.
- Rufus would like to do that.
- Did you want to do it?
- No, I think you can take this one.
- You're a big literary fan.
- [clears throat]
- No, Rufus...
Rufus is gonna take
this one... okay, okay.
[boards creaking]
So the machine lands right there.
It's remarkable.
Must say, It's rather
jarring seeing you here...
so openly.
And Lucy's in Paris now.
- Well, 90 years ago, but yes.
- Hmm.
Would you tell me now,
why the fixation on Lucy Preston?
She's my daughter.
[unsettling music]
♪ ♪
Lucy?
Lucy!
♪ ♪
Oh, let go! Tell him to let me go!
Let her go. She's not a prisoner.
His name is David
Baumgardner, by the way.
I'm sorry, I don't know
who you're talking about.
The soldier that he killed, my guy.
I thought your guy was Wyatt.
You knew, didn't you?
That's why, at the
"Hindenburg," you told me
to ask them about Rittenhouse
and ask them why they chose me.
If you knew who my real
father was all along,
why didn't you just tell me?
You needed to see with
your own eyes who they are
and why you're gonna fight them.
That's right, because everybody
knows my future except me.
Where's Lindbergh?
He's right in there.
You know, according to your journal,
he's Rittenhouse.
In a decade he becomes a monumental ass,
spews his hate across America.
The way you feel about Rittenhouse now?
Can't tell me it wouldn't be at least
a little bit satisfying taking him out.
You can't just kill Charles Lindbergh.
It's not right.
Look, I will go in
there, I will talk to him,
and I will convince
him to leave Rittenhouse
and not become the monster
he's supposed to become.
And you think he's gonna just, what,
give up all that fame,
the power, the legacy?
- Yes.
- [scoffs]
I would.
Okay. I'll take that bet.
It'll be entertaining if nothing else.
You convince him there's a better way,
and I'll spare him.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
What does that lunatic want with us?
He knows that you're
part of Rittenhouse.
- Ritten... what?
- It's okay.
I'm Rittenhouse too.
Part of the... the Cahill family.
Pure blood family.
Very well - Respected.
Apparently, It goes back generations.
My father, he just
told me. He said that...
That it's your legacy? [groans]
- Here, let me help you.
- [grunts]
Let's see what... let's
see what this will do, okay?
My father is a, uh...
a congressman.
When he told me what we really are,
it's...
it's hard to take in, you know?
Yeah. I know.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
He says that I am supposed to be...
their golden flyboy.
And then...
they want me to say terrible things
about all sorts of people.
- Why?
- Dad says it's a distraction.
He says that when you
create a scapegoat,
no one can know who's really in control.
You don't have to do that, you know.
What am I supposed to do?
A couple years ago, I...
I got offered this professor
job at a small college in Ohio.
It was...
my dream job.
When I told my mother
about it, she said...
"You can't leave Stanford.
"You can't leave me."
[chuckles]
But my sister, Amy, she
told me to go for it.
She was always...
encouraging me to stand up to my mother.
So what did you do?
My mother would have been devastated
if I wasn't following in her footsteps.
When I got off the phone,
after I turned down the job,
i looked and...
there was Amy.
[chuckles]
My little sister, disappointed in me.
God. [chuckles]
She was really the only person
I could talk to about this stuff.
I know... exactly what she would
say to both of us right now.
What's that?
Nobody gets to decide
our futures except us.
Nothing in the whole house.
Little medicine, friend?
Are you kidding me?
Your drinking is what
got us into this mess.
Oh, stop sounding like a woman.
Do you have any idea
what I've been through?
In the last two days,
i've had to ID a mentor,
see a friend of mine hauled off to jail,
watch a new teammate
get killed in an alley.
All the while, Lucy has disappeared.
Probably kidnapped.
I'm all alone...
and I have no idea what to do.
[uncorks flask]
[grunts, sniffs]
You ever been in war, Rufus?
I've lost more friends in war
than you'll make your entire life.
It almost broke me, you
want to know the truth.
Right now...
there are millions of people
buried in the catacombs below us.
Death is everywhere.
Please.
- [uncorks flask]
- So what are my choices?
Give up?
Curl into a ball and die?
Or live...
and drink...
and fight and screw
on behalf of those who can't.
So you can either stand
there like a corpse,
or you can be a man!
And fight!
First of all,
you are a world class jerk, Hemingway.
Second, I fought the Germans,
the Shawnee,
french, British, cowboys, killers,
people you couldn't even imagine.
And no, I may not have
fought in the Great War,
which, by the way, sounds
like the most pointless war
in the history of
wars, but I have fought!
[laughs] Ah!
That's the spirit. Yes.
[glass shatters]
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
That is a disappointment.
The catacombs.
You... you said there
were catacombs below us.
Yeah, so?
So... so what if Flynn's
not in one of the buildings?
What if he's underneath them?
Yeah, It's nice to think about,
but family's family.
Blood is blood.
I can't even imagine
what my father would say.
Does your father care about
what you want, Charles?
I know mine doesn't.
What do you want?
- To get married.
- Mm - Hmm.
Buy a small farm, a few
kids, just... a simple life.
Do it.
The whole world thinks
that you died in that crash,
including your parents.
Maybe, or...
maybe there are people out
there right now looking for me.
What do you mean?
My dad said once I landed...
that I was supposed to call Mr. Charvet,
and Rittenhouse would handle the rest.
- Who's Charvet?
- Julian Charvet,
owner of one of the largest
car companies in Europe.
And apparently a big
player in Rittenhouse.
Smart, using her.
Sneaky as hell, but smart.
Keep listening.
Maybe you'll hear something else.
I'll be back.
You don't have to make
that call, Charles.
You can decide your future.
You can choose the life that you want.
This doesn't have to be
either of our futures.
So you've seen this limo at
Mason Industries, so what?
Because I realized I've seen it before,
and the Rittenhouse guy who owns it,
he's the one Mason's
been meeting in secret.
This is the creep that's
been threatening Rufus?
- Yeah.
- That means Rittenhouse
is in control of Mason Industries...
and the Lifeboat.
- And Lucy and Rufus.
- And there's something else.
That guy...
is Lucy's biological father.
What? Does she know?
She just found out. Wyatt,
these sons of bitches
are getting more and more brazen.
We have to do something.
Well, there's nothing I
can do about it in here.
This is the confession they
want me to get you to sign.
You could sign it and vanish
down some black hole
for a couple of years,
- Or you could fight this.
- [groans]
Just think about what Lucy
and Rufus are coming back to
before you make your decision.
Think about what? I let them down.
- I let Jessica down.
- I know you feel...
No, you don't.
Because either Flynn was lying
to me about who killed my wife,
or he wasn't, and fate
wanted her dead anyway.
Wrap your head around that for a minute,
that the universe...
or God...
wanted the one person that
I love most in this world...
to be dead.
Maybe the universe is saying
there's something else
you have to do first.
Maybe you're not meant to be here.
Maybe you're meant to
be helping your friends.
How do I do that now?
[door opening]
I don't know.
I will let them know you won't
be signing the confession.
[dramatic music]
[knocking]
_
[ominous music]
I have so many questions.
We have a lot to talk about.
♪ ♪
- Do you know where we're going?
- Oh, God, no.
People get lost and die
down here all the time.
Encouraging.
Yeah, well, It's one way to pass the...
[bones rattling]
Okay, this will be a lot easier
if they don't hear us coming.
[clears throat] Sorry.
[whispering] It's dark.
[distant voice] Lucy? Can you hear me?
♪ ♪
Are you down here?
Lucy!
♪ ♪
Lucy?
Lucy? Lucy?
Surprise, you son of a bitch.
- [exciting music]
- [groans]
[sighs]
Hemingway hook.
[groans]
Told you it'd work. Come on.
Just...
[sighs]
- Lucy.
- Oh, my God. Rufus!
How did you find me?
Where... where's Flynn?
Who knows? Uh, not here.
- This is Charles Lindbergh.
- Charles.
Let's get out of here
before Flynn gets back.
Emma.
Been a long time. Good to see you again.
You too, Rufus.
[dramatic music]
Either you're coming with us,
or you're letting us pass.
♪ ♪
Be careful.
Flynn's not too good at
taking care of his pilots.
[rhythmic music]
♪ ♪
Here goes nothing.
[electricity sparking]
Charles?
Josephine here is gonna help
you find the life that you want.
I suppose I know some people.
Someplace in Bordeaux sounds nice.
You realize you don't
get your story after all.
Gotta keep the whole thing a secret.
Ah. What the hell.
- Did it for the fun of it anyway.
- [chuckles]
We should get started, then.
Rufus, remember,
you're not dead yet, so...
Dink and fight and screw
for everyone who can't.
- [laughs]
- Got it.
Um, can you do me a favor
and not mention this
to Jiya either, please?
Uh - Huh.
[alarm blaring]
Hello?
[grunting]
[exciting music]
♪ ♪
I'm sorry in advance for the
headache you're gonna have.
♪ ♪
[ominous music]
- Oh, no.
- What happened?
We changed history too much.
Where's Agent Christopher?
Well, Agent Christopher's
been reassigned.
Lucy, Rufus, I'm Agent
Neville, her replacement.
Been studying up on you two.
Welcome back.
Where's Baumgardner?
Were there any other casualties?
No.
- I don't think so.
- I don't think so, or no?
No.
[keys clacking]
Approximately how many people
did you interact with in 1927?
I would say about 15...
[stammering] To 17.
- [whispering] Right?
- I'm asking you.
- Not him.
- Mm - Hmm.
Uh, that's my answer.
You're free to go.
Were we not free to go
before you said that?
We'll call you when there
are more developments.
♪ ♪
[whispering] Did nothing change?
- Hey.
- Oh, hey, Mom.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to wake you, I...
just had to borrow a book or ten.
I see.
What's got you reading
about Charles Lindbergh?
He still became a world class a - Hole.
Isolationist, anti - Semitic,
the whole nine.
You saw that like it's news.
I just don't get it.
I mean, he gets injured
in a crash landing,
and then disappears for a few weeks,
only to reemerge to claim credit
for the first transatlantic flight.
- Why?
- He was an ambitious man.
I mean, his father was a congressman.
Maybe the love of the
spotlight got passed down.
I mean, he had money, adoration, power.
How do you walk away
from a family like that?
I just thought he'd
make a different choice.
[phone buzzes]
I'm sorry, Mom, I... i have to go. I...
Lucy. Hold on.
I know meeting your
father has thrown you,
and I get it that you don't
want to talk to me about it,
but what do we do in our family
when we go through tough times?
When we need to collect our thoughts?
We write them down.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
It's a journal.
[door opening]
Hey.
You're okay.
[soft music]
Boy, we really could've used you.
- We tried...
- You didn't have a choice.
I knew you'd make it out of there.
Don't worry, I swept for bugs.
The place is clean for now.
♪ ♪
Lucy, I heard about your father.
I'm so sorry.
But you know that dick's got
nothing to do with you, right?
Okay, guys, I'm afraid it gets worse.
The agents in control
of Mason Industries,
- They're Rittenhouse.
- What?
- Jiya's there right now!
- No.
Maybe that's a good thing,
somebody working with us on the inside.
A good thing? This is
Rittenhouse we're talking about.
- They could kill her!
- Guys, It's okay.
So what, Rufus and I,
we're just supposed to
go to work like nothing's happening?
Yes.
Yeah, It's gonna be okay.
How can you be so calm right now?
Because I've been through a
lot in the last couple days,
and I fought it for a long time.
You can call it fate,
or God, or the Force,
but I am meant to do something.
I am meant to protect the both of you.
I see that now,
and I will.
You realize you sound
like a crazy person, right?
Mm - Hmm.
I sound like you.
Exactly.
But seriously,
what are we gonna do about Rittenhouse?
- We fight.
- Mm - Hmm.
How?
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www. Addic7ed. Com